Hey.
Hey. Hey.
Heat.
Hello, good evening and good day
everybody and welcome back to the Ask a
Minute Show. This is episode 342
and today we go back to our discussion
about the ongoing war. It is the
USIsrael versus Iran war, the American
and Israeli war against Iran. We're
going to discuss that. A lot is
happening in real time. Trump is making
magnificent threats right now on Iran.
So yeah, looks like escalation is on the
cards. Looks like escalation is on the
menu. We're going to discuss all of
that. I will take as many questions as
possible from you all today. Uh but
before we do that let me see who is
there on the live stream. Rashi Kudin
Bjour U Dashan Patel Saksham Jasia
Sakamia Akshit Sharma Nirvana Shanks
Aarian Arian Gol from Indor good to see
you. Omnak from Odisha. Hello only gems.
Tesh Pande Ashwani Sharma Disha Saksham
Jasia once again. Uh Vishal Ram
Pmanik Rohan Biri Harum meet Raj Singh
Judas Marik good morning ma'am Aayush
Singh Praam Sarji uh Ziggy Stardust
Nirvana Shanks good to see you Nirvana
Nirvana Shanks uh Ziggar Stardust I I'm
sure I've heard it at some point in time
but I don't remember quite quite
remember what was in the package so um
Anoop Ajay Rana Mkeshv Ready. Always
ready. Uh Shashir Upadhya
Sam Winston Sam Winston says, "Please do
an analysis of the conflict before
jumping into the questions." How about I
do How about I do that? Sure. Pratt.
Namaste. Um Monish Monish Han Sharma
Jotesh Pande injured soccer player from
Richmond Hill, Ontario in Canada. Good
good morning Swami. Good evening Swami.
Nabi Tadas. Namaste. General Subatai,
hello. Uh, Manka, Bona, hyphen, Ajana,
Pradesh, once again, Vinit Kapper. Uh,
who else do we have? Suknil Saka, Ajana
Prana, Mahita Busetti, hello. Vishwendra
Singh, Vishuendra Singha. Yes. Hello.
Swami is here from Jaipur. Abhishek
Shukla live is a viewer from a train is
in a train right now. Well, I enjoy I
hope you enjoy your train journey.
Pratit
um who else who else do we have? Rit
Ashish Tabra Ram Ram Sarji Kal 673 Kumar
of Yas from Dublin. Panam, good to see
you after a long time. Good to have you
back. Uh Svesh Padwal, hello. Malik say
good to see you sir. Hyderabad. Yes.
Okay. General Subai says Americans are
not Mongols. I agree they're not
Mongols. Kahan is here from Delhi. Uh
Manisha Kardoshu. Namaste ma'am. Good to
see you. Priyan Chupoli, hello. Somi
Ajana once again. Uh, who else? Boiled
potato. Okay. Cintillating kids. Mochi
XO gaming. Nitin. Uh, Nithin Shivanas.
Shinasan from Dubai. I hope you're okay
in Dubai. I hope you're okay. I hope
you're doing well. Hang in there. It'll
hopefully be fine soon. Uh, Viru is here
from Germany. Deand and everyone else. U
Sakam is here. Sak Shik Sakim is from
Jammu. Josef Shikh is here from Kashmir.
Good to have you. The rational reporter
is here from Rayur. Hey from Mumbai and
everyone else. Okay. Okay. Uh okay. I
will now end that part of the thing.
Let's get into Okay. So before we get
into the questions, uh let's see what's
all has happened thus far, shall we? And
let's let me do a quick recap. I've I've
uh you know these days uh Twitter is
pretty useful for kind of understanding
what's happening. Obviously there is a
lot of censorship on Twitter. A lot of
real time analysis is now missing from
Twitter. A lot of real-time reporting is
now missing from Twitter. But and yet we
get good information um as it kind of
happens from Twitter. So let's see. I
I've collected a bunch of tweets etc.
that kind of give us an indication of
what's happening in the world right now.
So let's go through these uh quickly.
So Mario Nava Nafal says, "Iran just
proved its missiles can reach far beyond
the Middle East. Iran fired two IRBMs at
Diego Garcia, a joint US UK military
base sitting 4,000 km away in the middle
of the Indian Ocean. Okay, so Diego
Garcia, it's south of the Maldives. It's
in India's so-called strategic backyard.
Okay. And the Iranians filed fired two
missiles apparently.
Apparently these were intercepted or
whatever. Iran says we did not do it.
Iran says it's Israel that did it. Okay.
So as always we don't know what quite
happened but allegedly two missiles were
fired. So Pierce Morgan, the fantastic
guy from England, says, "So not only has
Iran brazantly lied, brazantly lied
about its ballistic missile range
capacity, but this means it probably can
hit the UK with them, and we have zero
defense against these missiles." Very
worrying. So Pierce Morgan expects that
Iran should disclose its its military
offensive and defensive capabilities to
him or to the UK. Really?
That's that's really like funny, isn't
it? Here's Derek Grossman. Derek
Grossman says the war is right in
India's backyard. Derek Grossman is a
guy who works for Rand Corporation.
Rand Corporation guy. Derek Grossman. He
says so he's referring to this alleged
Iranian ballistic missile attempted
strike on Diego. And he says that the
war is right in India's backyard. Iran's
failed intermediate rate range ballistic
missile attack on the Garcia
illustrated. So my question to Derek
Grossman is this.
You say that the war is right in India's
backyard, right? My question to you is
why is there an American military base
right in India's backyard?
that to
an American base built on stolen land
from the people of the Chagos
archipelago.
Why don't you remove your illegal
military base and keep your war to
yourself? Yes, Derek Grossman, that's
what I would recommend you do. So, these
people, they are dragging the war into
India's backyard and then they expect
India to do something about it. Why
don't you keep keep your war to
yourself?
Right. So, he's trying to somehow
instigate India and try to trying to
drag India India into this matter. What
else do we have happening? Uh, what is
this? Yeah, it's it's a response to
Pierce Morgan. So, instead of being mad
at the US and Israel for kicking the
Hornets's nest, you're complaining about
how well then Hornets can hornets can
defend yourselves. It's a response to
Pierce Morgan. That's a good response.
Yes. Uh, Doc, sorry, Mr. Modi India's
Prime Minister tweeted this yesterday
evening spoke with President Dr. Masud
Pizashan and conveyed Eid and Navu's
greetings. We expressed hope that this
festive season brings peace, stability
and prosperity to West Asia. Condemned
the attacks on critical infrastructure
in the region which threatened regional
stability and disrupt global supply
chains. reiterated the importance of
safeguarding freedom of navigation in
ensuring that shipping lanes remain open
and secure appreciated Iran's continued
support for the safety and security of
Indian nationals in Iran and it is
addressed to Dr. Masud Peshkan.
So the Indian prime minister condemned
attacks on critical infrastructure in
the region. So this can be interpreted
as a condemnation of Israeli and
American activities, Israeli and
American strikes on Iran because
obviously when Mr. Modi speaks with Dr.
Pzashkan, he's not one who condemn Dr.
Pzashkan. Right. Right. So yeah, India
is is doing the balancing act. India has
good relations with Iran. India also
seeks to have good relations with the
aggressors, the Americans and the
Israelis. So Mr. Modi is obviously doing
his best to ensure that he navigates
India's ship through the treacherous
waters that have been created by the
Americans and the Israelis right because
the war who started it is the Israelis
and the Americans who started it not the
Iranians okay so India is is trying to
navigate this uh turbulent period of
time
what else do we have Dr. J Shankar. So
India's foreign minister spoke with
foreign minister of Iran say Abbas Araji
and yeah same kind of thing so that
that's a few hours after Mr. Modi spoke
with Dr. Bzesh Kyan. Now this is a tweet
from the white house
from March 21. Today is March 22 right
March 21.
The white house that is Trump tweeted
this. We are getting very close to
achieving to meeting our objectives as
we consider winding down our great
military efforts in the Middle East with
respect to the allegedly terrorist
regime of Iran completely degrading
Iranian missile missile capability
launchers everything else pertaining to
them destroying Iran's defense
industrial base eliminating their navy
and air force including anti-aircraft
weaponry so how come they were able to
shoot down F-35 at least one yeah never
allowing Iran to get even close to
nuclear capability and always being in a
position where the USA can quickly and
powerfully react to any situation to
such a situation should it take place.
Protecting at the highest level our
Middle Eastern allies. You failed at
that Donald Trump. You failed miserably.
Protecting our Middle Eastern allies
including Israel, Saudi Arabia, Qatar,
UAE, Bahrain, Kuwait and others. The
hormones state will have to be guarded
and policed as necessary and so on so
forth so on so forth.
the so the hormones trade will have to
be guarded and policed as necessary by
the other nations who use it and the US
does not. So the US has led has created
the situation where the hormonal strait
is selectively closed and now the US
says that those who use it must guard it
and police it and the US is no longer
responsible for this washing his hands
of the mess he has created. H if asked
we will help these countries in the
hormones efforts but it shouldn't be
necessary once Iran's threat is
eradicated but you're claiming it's
eradicated right? Importantly it will be
an easy military operation for them
right? So why is if it's so easy why
isn't the US walking in and finishing
the job and claiming all the glory?
So this is from March 21
days a one day ago. This is from
yesterday. Now this is the tweet from
today.
If Iran doesn't fully open without
threat the straight of Hermuz within 48
hours from this exact point in time the
US the United States of America will hit
and obliterate their various power
plants starting with the biggest one
first President Donald J. Trump H. So
now he's panicking.
Didn't he say that the it's it's the
nations that use the hormones trade that
need to open it? So why is he now
suddenly panicking about the hormones
trade? Isn't he claiming here that we
are getting very close to winding down
this war and meeting our objectives and
winding down our great military efforts?
So then why was this necessary? And does
Donald Trump understand
what it means to to target power plants
of a nation?
You're targeting civilian
infrastructure, which is a war crime.
When the Russians allegedly hit power
plants in Ukraine, you were complaining
about this. You were calling it a war
crime. Now you are threatening a war
crime,
right? I mean look at this. Okay. What
is the definition of international
terrorism as per 18 USC 23311?
Okay. It in it means activities that
involve violent acts or acts dangerous
to human life that are a violation of
the criminal laws of the US or any state
or that would be a criminal violation if
committed within within the jurisdiction
of the US, United States or any state uh
appear to be intended to intimidate or
coersse a civilian population to
influence the policy of a government by
intimidation or coion or to affect the
conduct of a government by mass
destruction, assassination or kidnapping
and so on. This is a war crime. This is
this is international terrorism that
Donald Trump is threatening here,
right? So yeah, and do you do does
Donald Trump really expect that Iran
will now suddenly, you know, give up and
open up the straight of Hormuz? Iran has
made it very clear that if if you hit
our power plants, we're going to hit all
the power plants in the entire region.
And if you then try to hit our
desalination plants, we Iran will hit
all the desalination plants in the
region. Now when it comes to Iran's
power plants, the largest power plant
that Iran has, it produces about 4%
roughly of Iran's energy needs,
electricity, electricity needs. So Iran
has got a distributed power plant system
network. No one power plant if you
destroy it will the nation.
you're going to have to destroy dozens.
But when it comes to Israel, their
largest power plant produces about 20 or
25% of the nation's electricity. If Iran
takes it out, it's disaster for Israel.
Does Trump understand what he is talking
about here? So Trump is now talking
about massively escalating this
conflict.
Massively escalating this conflict.
Right? This is going from bad to worse
now. Okay. So now what else do we have?
Uh this is the this is a message from
the from Iran.
Okay. They are saying that to the
honorable and great nation of the US,
this man is not mentally fit for office.
He's dishonoring dishonoring a
courageous and diligent nation's
reputation by abusing their tax.
Uh your money was meant to build your
nation, not bomb our schools.
Yeah, it's it's they're referring to
this these threats by Trump. Okay, what
else do we have? Okay, so now that's
about Iran. Now let let's take a look at
this. Okay,
shocking revelations from a former
executive at Loheed Martin, the company
that manufactures F-35 fighter jets.
Nalan Yazgan, a Turkish engineer who
previously worked as an executive
director on an F-35 project at Loheed
Martin, made notable statements
regarding the F-35 aircraft. If Turkey
had obtained F-35 jets, we wouldn't have
been even able to take off with them due
to the software. In fact, we shouldn't
have taken off with them at all. The
F-35 transmits information about all
military assets within a certain radius
instantly and in real time to the United
States in Israel. It's also mentioned
that some Turkish engineers involved in
the project say that if Washington
decides to cut off connectivity or
updates to a country, the aircraft would
literally turn into a piece of metal
unable to carry out combat missions or
even routine maintenance. In other
words, my dear friends, the F-35,
it is riddled
with kill switches and back doors.
It is riddled with kill switches and
back doors. I have been warning about
this for years and a lot of geniuses
have been laughing at me about that when
I talk about kill switches and back
doors. Who's laughing now?
You know when I say something it it may
take a few years for it for the truth to
come out but it does come out and it's
not just the Turks who are talking about
this. It's a nations you know people
from the Nording nations also have made
these revelations. So do you really
believe my friends that India should buy
this F-35? Yeah. Which will transmit all
information instantaneously and re and
in real time about all military assets
in a certain radius in real time to the
US and Israel. Do we want everything
about our nation to be known in real
time
to nations that may not be the best of
friends of ours? I'm especially talking
about the US, not Israel.
Do we need that? And you can't take off
if the Americans decide you can't carry
out a certain mission. And before you
carry before you carry out a mission,
you have to send the entire
mission plan and flight data, flight
path, etc. to the Americans for
approval. Only after they approve it
will you get an OTP to to start the
aircraft. That's the kind of junk
they're trying to sell to us. We should
stay away from this overpriced flying
trash can. Okay. Now, what else do we
have? What is this? Oh yes. The prime
minister of Japan. Okay. Madame Sai
Takichi. He has gone and paid tribute to
the pilot who dropped the atomic bomb on
Japan.
So if you are a vasal of the United
States, you are required to periodically
humiliate yourselves
in order to please
the overlord.
Okay, that's so I get this question from
time to time. Isn't it a is it really a
bad idea for India to become an American
vasal? We will have prosperity. We will
have protection blah blah blah blah
blah.
So if you if you are an American vasal,
you have to first of all buy their third
rate products which compromise you even
further and then you have to
periodically humiliate yourselves. The
prime minister of Japan had was made to
go and pay tribute to the person the
pilot who dropped the atomic bomb on
Japan. Nice. That that is what you get
when you become a vasal and your nation
is wiped out through various means
economic means and your TFR is
destroyed. Okay. What else do we have?
Okay. This is about Manipur, right?
Russia reacts to India detaining
Ukrainian nationals, US citizens. Terror
charges have been slapped on them.
comment by foreign ministry spokesperson
spokeswoman Maria Zakarova on India's
national NIA detaining Ukrainian and
American citizens on charges of being
implemented implicated in terrorist
activities.
So long statement
um okay let's read it the Indian media
reports that report that six Ukrainian
citizens and one US citizen were
detained and taken into custody at
international airports in New Delhi,
Lucknau and Kolkata by India's NIA on
March 13. These allegedly these
individuals have crossed illegally cross
the border from the Indian state of
Misaram into Myanmar and established
contacts with the local armed ethnic
terrorist groups with the aim of
supplying them with EU manufactured
drones and training them in drone
assembly and repair in conducting
electronic warfare. The publications
quoted the NIA as saying that these
armed group maintains these armed groups
maintain ties with terrorists in
northeastern India. The reaction of the
Ukrainian embassy in New Delhi was quite
revealing as it reportedly sought to
conceal the incident and keep its qu
citizens questionable activities which
are clearly designed to destabilize the
situation in the region under wraps. The
Ukrainian foreign ministry chose to
remain silent on its citizens violation
of India's counterterrorism legislation
and wasted no time baselessly accusing
certain Indian and Russian news agencies
of deliberately falsifying the facts.
The incident clearly shows that
Zalinski's neo-Nazi regime has a core
exporter of instability worldwide.
Russia has repeatedly issued warnings
about the risks associated with the
large-scale militarization of Ukraine by
NATO and the EU. Weapons supplied to it
are inadequately accounted for and may
surface anywhere. Today, Kiev is a major
supplier of weaponry and military
technologies in the to the global black
market, including military supplies to
Latin American drug cartels and training
terrorists in Africa. As we can see, the
western created Ukrainian tentacle
network is reaching as far as regional
contacts in the Middle East, South Asia,
and Southeast Asia. Just days ago,
Zalinsky brazenly boasted that several
hundred Ukrainian fighters had been
deployed to the Persian Gulf area to
take part in the ongoing war against
Iran as instructors and specialized
experts in using unmanned aan aerial
vehicles. Sure enough, enforcing
international oversight over Ukraine's
military technology exports is out of
the question. All of that is the result
of lack policies pursued by Western
sponsors of Zalinsk's regime. Today's
Ukraine is undermining regional and
global security and stability and is an
extremely destructive factor in
international politics. Once again, we
urge the world majority to take a good
look at destabilizing activities of the
agonizing cave regime which western
countries use as leverage against Russia
and other countries around the world
including India. So that's kind of
what's happening in the world right now.
Okay, that's kind of a recap and a
roundup of what's happening in the world
right now. So clearly once we focus back
on Iran, Trump is extremely frustrated.
He seems to be running out of patience.
He seems to be panicking. The the uh
straight of hormones remains closed. He
says it's it should be very easy to open
it. The war is almost over. We have
almost finished the operation. Iran is
almost destroyed and the EU and other
nations should come and open up the
state of Hermuz. But now he's saying you
have 48 hours to open it otherwise I'll
blow up your power plants
which obviously is an act of terrorism
because it's civilian infrastructure
that he is talking about targeting and
Iran is not going to you know just sit
and let this happen.
Iran thus far has been responding to
aggressions,
right? When the Americans destroyed a
desalination plant on Kashm Island,
then Iran went and destroyed a
dissolination plant in Fujira or
wherever it was, UAE or was it Oman
Katar? Wherever it was when the
Americans and Israelis destroyed oil
storage facilities in Thran and other
places, Iran went and did that in Saudi
Arabia and wherever else.
When the US attacked the Paris gas
field, the Iranians went ahead the went
ahead and attacked the Qatari gas field
which is an extension of the Paris gas
field. Right? And now if if Trump goes
and attacks power plants, Iran is going
to obliterate power plants in the
region, which will leave the Gulf
nations, the unfortunate
Gulf nations without power. If the
Americans then go and attack more
desalination plants, the whole Gulf
region will be without water very soon.
If Iran responds by attacking their
desination plants,
clearly this is extremely frustrating
for Trump. He has not achieved any of
his objectives despite his tall claims
and boasts
and we are now entering more dangerous
times.
We are entering a more dangerous phase
of the war.
And Trump, I promise you, every day when
he wakes up or goes to sleep, he's
thinking of extreme options.
And he's the kind of person who if he
makes the Japanese prime minister go and
pay tributes to the guy who dropped an
atomic bomb on Hiroshima Nagasaki he'll
be thinking of atomic bombs right now
right so yeah a very dangerous phase of
the war that's what we are entering
ideally put not putin Trump should just
declare victory I've won and he should
walk out but his ego won't allow him to
do that and why because even if he
declares victory and walks out the whole
world will laugh at him because everyone
knows that he has failed
and Trump's ego won't allow this to
happen. So he is trying to now escalate.
There is even talk about the US sending
Marines to to Kajar Island or wherever
it is. That is going to be suicidal if
they try that suicidal.
So the US doesn't seem to have good
options right now. They have they're
running out of extremely critical
supplies. They're running out of Tom
tomahawk missiles. They're running out
of interceptors. Their THAD systems and
those radars have been destroyed. They
they are operating blind.
Their infrastructure in the region has
been either severely degraded or
entirely destroyed. The fifth fleet
headquarters in Bahrain, what happened
to it? It's gone.
If the war ends like this, the US will
no longer have any power projection
capabilities in the whole of West Asia.
The US talks about its awesome
aircraft carriers. Where are those
aircraft carriers?
They have scuttled their aircraft
carriers away hundreds of kilometers
away from the u Persian state of Forbos
and Persian Gulf region. Why? Because
the Iranians will obliterate those
aircraft carriers are now sitting ducks.
They may have the Aegis system for
defending the aircraft carriers. Let's
say the protective bubble around the
aircraft carrier which is multiple
warships. Let's say they have 200
interceptors ages aegis interceptors.
What if Iran fires 500 drones at Shahed
drones? What happens? It's a
mathematical certainty. The aircraft
carrier will be blown to bits.
That's why the Americans have moved
their aircraft carriers far far away.
This is the situation right now. Iran
has done its homework well and they are
actually you could say despite the
immense
despite the immense damage they are
taking every single day they are still
winning you know understand this is
something you should learn from Maetung
Maung's Mauist
u formulation see Mao Maetung he
understood some things very well
one of the things he understood very
well is that you can separate
political victory from military victory
and political defeat from military
defeat.
And if you are a nation and a people
that are resilient enough,
you can keep taking military defeat and
you can still convert that into
political victory.
And that's what's happening right now.
I'm not saying Iran is being military
defeated militarily defeated. They are
being pounded every day. They are taking
damage and some of some analysts can
interpret that as an ongoing military
defeat.
But they are winning the political war.
Whatever long-term objectives they've
had, they are achieving those
objectives. Their population is now
rallying around the flag.
People who are against the regime in
Thran, they are now volunteering for
serving the nation in whatever way they
can. So the US may be winning tactically
day after day by imposing more pain and
destruction on Iran but Iran is winning
the strategic war. Do you understand
what's happening? That is where we are.
That is the situation in the war right
now.
And Israel is taking tremendous damage.
If Iran is taking tremendous damage,
Israel is not taking any less damage.
Israel is also being significantly
damaged. It's taking ballistic missile
strikes every single day. Dimona was hit
yesterday or today. What is Dimona?
Dimona is the city is the town
close to the negative nuclear uh
facility
right
so
that that is alarm bells and the
Americans are trying to target what
fordo natans whatever which is Iranian
nuclear facilities so if they actually
do something like that Iran will go
after the
so you can see the escalation threshold
being crossed It's it's going higher and
higher and higher. Very very bad times
right now.
And obviously nations who are not
involved in the war at all are going to
suffer.
India depends on u LPG.
A lot of our LPG comes from Hormuz the
the Hormos region. So now we're going to
have to source our LPG from God knows
where from Russia probably. There are
many countries that can that can sell us
LPG for sure. But uh yeah, we're going
to it'll take some time before it
reaches us. So yeah, this is a bad time
right now. The war is escalating. And
Trump is essentially threatening
Armageddon. He's threatening the
destruction of Iran's uh uh power
generation plants and Iran is not going
to take that take that sitting down.
Okay, enough of my explanation and the
overview and summary of what's
happening. Let's take some questions.
Okay, Tanmadesh Pandi says uh number one
is Ulfa attack in Assam connected to the
Van Djk arrest. Secondly, will the US
force Pakistan Iraq to attack Iran for
its ground invasions? What's my take on
this news? It looks like see Ulfa has
not been in the news for years if not
decades.
It's been a long time since you heard
about Ulfa. Ulfa is some terrorist
organization that seeks to liberate
Assam or something from India.
Separatist organization, right? and they
they are almost defunct. Suddenly
there's a well-coordinated attack by
Ulfa
on Assam police commandos or something.
Um I don't know for sure but looks like
it is clearly something that comes in
the wake of the arrest of this terrorist
this uh regime change specialist Van Djk
and the Ukrainian terrorists he who are
with him. Looks there are no
coincidences in these matters. Looks
like it is it is connected to this Van
Djke arrest, right? So the guy was
training terrorists in drone warfare and
god knows what other things across the
border in Burma and Ulfa.
Ulfa has a presence across the border in
Burma. Ulfa also has a presence in
China, Yuna and whatnot. The Chinese
have sheltered some Ulfa top ranking top
ranking leaders terrorists.
So I think it's highly likely that this
Ulfa attack is connected to the Van Dyke
arrest. Will the US force Pakistan Iraq
to attack Iran for its ground invasions?
Uh Iraq I don't see how Iraq can be
forced Iraq doesn't even have a standing
army today. Iraq is under US occupation.
De facto occupation not dur occupation.
I'm not sure what the Iraqi armed forces
capabilities are. And about 50% of
Iraq's population is Shia and they are
aligned with Iran. So it's very hard for
the US to somehow make Iran get involved
Iraq get involved in this battle or the
US wanted Kuresh militias to fight
against Iran.
Now the Kurds will say you betray you
betrayed us multiple times you Americans
in Syria and god knows where else right.
Why should we once again be canon fer
for your geopolitical games? What do we
get in exchange for that? What do we get
in return for fighting for you?
We are fighting for Kuristan.
So if you want us to fight against Iran,
first declare
the nation of Kurustan. The United
States must declare it, then we'll fight
for you. But that doesn't work because
the majority of Kurustan is in Turkish
occupied territory. Doesn't work. So
yeah, about Pakistan, yeah, the US may
at some point activate Pakistan. We'll
see about that.
Vishal Ro says project Kusha M1 trials
got completed 150 km range. So let's
find out what is this project Kusha. Um
project Kusha. What is that? Let's see.
Project Kusha.
Okay. It's an extended range air defense
system.
Extend extended range surfaceto-air
missile 150 km range. Excellent.
Excellent news. I'm glad to hear this.
Outstanding.
Only gems says some experts say that the
rupee has been kept artificially low.
They predict that by the end of 2029 or
so rupees 3 will become dollar one might
be the result of China dumping bonds.
What I'm your thoughts on this sir? I am
not a fortune teller. I am not somebody
who sees the future. Um I don't I don't
know if India has the ability to keep
the rupee artificially low and
manipulate the the exchange rates and
all that. I don't think I'm not sure if
India has that ability. I don't think
India's India's RBI can actually make
such things happen. Right? So, uh my
what's my view on my thoughts on this? I
my thoughts is that I'm skeptical about
this and overall yeah I'm skeptical
about this. Okay. Rupees 3 will become
dollar one by 2029. We'll see. We'll
see.
As an aspiring aerospace engineer, will
I risk death if I advance Indian
military industrial complex internal
enemies? Maybe I'm overthinking
thoughts.
You're an aspiring aerospace engineer.
Will you risk death if you advance
India's military-industrial complex? You
can't advance India's
military-industrial complex without
becoming part of India's
military-industrial complex. Which means
joining DRDO or joining something else,
H or whatever or starting your own big
company, a one-man team. There's no such
thing as a oneman team in the mil
military industrial complex. So you
either join an existing organization
like DRDO, HOL or some private company
or you start your own company with a
bunch of people and u
will you risk death? I don't see any
DRDO scientists H engineers or whatever
risking death. So I don't think so.
MK says Bahrain is equal to major Shia.
Does India does Iran capitalize on this?
We'll see. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, wherever
you have a majority Shia population, uh
there is a pro-Iran sentiment for sure.
Yeah. And in Bahrain, you can say that,
you know, it's very likely that the
common people of Bahin who are who are
Shia are not very fond of the Sunni uh
leadership of Bahrain. So Iran can
definitely capitalize on this and that
that if if Iran is able to do that it
will be a significant setback for the
United States.
Crazy Gmers Crazy Gamer says salute to
you sir. I wish we had people like you
in the government. Uh thank you very
much sir. Thank you.
Prattana says Iran war has exposed that
India isn't prepared for war.
Um India isn't prepared for war.
I'm not sure. Uh look, one thing is sure
that we are certainly well equipped to
to defeat Pakistan. Operation Shindu
Sindur showed that we have a very high
quality multi-layered air defense
system. The Pakistanis could couldn't
hit any target in India. When it comes
to our offensive capabilities, we had
rules of engagement etc. instead of
having rules that said destroy them all.
So if the political will is clear then I
think we can certainly defeat Pakistan
and and achieve whatever objectives we
have visav Pakistan. When it comes to
China I'm not I don't know how well
prepared we may or may not be. We
obviously have issues like Navi is no
longer fully operational. The Indian
satellite positioning system etc. We we
obviously have significant room for
improvement. Uh so I would not say that
India is entirely unprepared for war. I
would say that we have areas of
significant improvement where a
significant improvement is possible. We
need a much more augmented navy. We need
better distributed lethality. Uh we need
more submarines. Uh we need to have
stockpiles of maybe hundreds of
thousands maybe millions of drones and
tens of thousands of missiles of various
kinds. All those things are needed. I'm
not sure what how large our stock piles
are. Um but there are certain things
that are going quite well. Certain
things where there is room for
improvement. So uh
and we haven't been preparing for a war
the way Iran has been preparing for a
war. Iran has been preparing for this
war for the past 45 years, 45, 46 years,
right? Uh we haven't been doing that
because we've had, you know, times where
the political leadership kept changing
every 3 months, every two years or
whatever, right? And when you have that
situation, you there's no long-term
planning. But now we have a government
that's been in power for about 12 years,
whatever. So hopefully there's been
progress on that front. That's what I
shall say here.
Hanish Sharma says, "I I have a CAP
interview on the 25th. Apparently they
are asking for a lot of current affairs.
What should I go through before going
except Iran war?"
One out of two. One out of two. Is there
a follow-up to that?
A followup to that. Should I talk about
this theory of six sovereign countries?
Definitely can't say we need educational
reforms or orientation theory is false
because they might just kick me out of
there. What else? Plus and it tips my
August sire. Um
they're asking a lot of current affairs.
What should I go through? Well, you
can't go through you have this interview
on the 25th 3 days to go. I have never
been a big believer in in you know last
minute cramming and crash courses in 2
days 3 days. If you are already
interested in current affairs and you've
been following current affairs then you
are reasonably well informed. Uh what
can you memorize or cram in two three
days? I'm not really sure. Um
so I would say
look I don't know I don't I don't even
know what cap is of course
um
the theory of six sovereign countries.
This is not a mainstream theory right
it's something I speak about. Of course,
if you are able to explain this
properly, why you believe there's only
six sovereign countries, why the rest
are not sovereign, if you can convincing
convincingly argue and explain this,
then it will it will definitely be
helpful for you because it shows that
you have come up with ideas that are
reasonably well thought out and possibly
original, right? U yeah, you can't talk
about educational reforms because they
will not agree with that. You can't say
aid is false because they will you know
they will be upset with that. Um yeah if
you if you are already keeping track of
current affairs and international
relations that should be good enough.
Apart from that I don't really know what
tips to give you because I don't even
know what cap is. So anyway I would say
that I know that you have been you know
uh participating in these live streams
and you've been uh I mean been you know
following what I talk about. In that
case you are already reasonably well
informed. So that hopefully should help
you out. All right. So yeah, all the
best sir. Do well.
Okay. What next? Ritik Paw says, "Was
Kame holding Iran back? Now Iran is
showing its power." No, Kame was not
holding Iran back. Kame was the old was
a member of the old guard. They were not
holding Iran back. They were hopeful
that there there will be a peaceful
settlement to the issues. So Kame was in
favor. Kamei and the old guard of Iran
who are all dead now. They were in favor
of finding some kind of compromise with
the US you know and that's why they went
and signed the JCPOA the joint
comprehensive path plan of action with
the US the Iran nuclear deal. They
signed it was all all was well and then
Trump says no I don't I'll walk out of
it unilaterally. So the US walked out of
this deal that they had signed
unilaterally
and Kame was also against a nuclear
weapons and so on and uh they were not
holding Iran back. They were hopeful.
They they they tried one approach. So
Kami and the old guard they represented
one approach to international relations
and dealing with the US. But the US
obviously has shown that it it doesn't
care about negotiations, compromises,
whatever. It just wants to destroy Iran.
So um they were not holding Iran back.
They they tried their best to to have a
peaceful approach and that did not work.
That's why Khal Kame clearly volunteered
to die and the old guard has been taken
out and the US probably has done a favor
to Iran by unleashing new blood among
the Iranian leadership because now it's
going to be all hardliners.
Vined Kapper says Munir had a meeting
with Pakistan top Shia clerics. He asked
them to go to Iran rudely. All clerics
made a video on how they were they have
been treated posturing to join war
against Iran by Munir on Saudi behalf.
Will Saudi Park join war?
Look so okay before I go into this
matter Saudi Arabia Saudi Arabia is
already involved in the war, right? Uh
they have been hit multiple times.
You've had at least three American large
large massive um uh refueling aircraft
that were destroyed.
on the ground in a Saudi air base. Uh
Saudi
refinery at least one or two have been
hit, right? Saudi Arabia has already
been hit in this war and they are
already in some shape or form involved
in the war. But they are making very
sure the Saudis that they don't respond
retaliate otherwise it's going to be a
full-scale war and the Iranians can
obliterate Saudi Arabia with just with
ballistic missiles and drones. The
Saudis don't have a response to that,
right? They have bought in the past
hundreds of billions of dollars worth of
American hardware, military hardware,
but that is not going to be enough to to
fight Iran off. So Saudi Arabia wants to
stay out of the war. They don't want to
start attempting to hit Iran in response
to whatever is happening. Uh but if the
war escalates, if Trump carries out his
threat and destroys power plants in
Iran, then Iran will go after power
plants in the whole region including
Saudi power plants. So at some point in
time, Saudi at some point in time Saudi
Arabia may have to make a decision
that now we are taking too much damage
and now maybe we should get involved
directly in this war. In that case,
Saudi Arabia may u invoke its agreement
with Pakistan.
Right. Um, in that case, Pakistan will
have to take approval from the United
States
because Pakistan's boss is the US, not
Saudi Arabia. Pakistan has a deal, an
agreement, mutual self-defense agreement
with Saudi Arabia. But the big boss of
Pakistan is the United States. So if
Saudi Arabia tells Pakistan that we have
this agreement, you need to fight now
with me. When Pakistan, we'll have to
take the green light from the US. If the
US is don't fight now, the Pakistanis
will have to say no to Saudi Arabia and
breach the agreement. So it all depends
on the US what the US wants from
Pakistan.
The US is right now most likely holding
Pakistan in reserve
that we will not activate Pakistan's
involvement in this war
until certain lines are crossed then we
will have Pakistan enter into enter the
war. So right now Pakistan is being kept
in reserve. It's like a substitute
player in in a football match. Only when
you know certain things happen, that's
when you activate the substitute
substitute play player. So that is the
deal right now. Uh I don't know about
the Shia clerics and all if he was rude
to them. Well, I don't know. I I've not
seen this news but uh would not surprise
me.
Black Panther says NATO military
alliance future over. What we expect
from future NATO EU future Putin
invasion will start.
Uh NATO is NATO over? NATO is not over.
NATO is not over by a long shot. See,
Trump has asked the European nations to
get involved in the war and send their
warships to the Strait of Hormuz and
forcibly uh open the state of Hormos by
sending their warships. And the European
nation said, "No, thank you. We're not
doing it." And that's why Trump is
furious and he has accused them of being
cowardly. He's called them cowards.
But understand this,
NATO is not relevant in the West Asia
theater, military theater. NATO is
relevant in Western Europe. The
objective of NATO is to protect
Western Europe from hypothetical future
Russian aggression. That's why NATO
exists. That is the of NATO. That is the
reason for existence of NATO.
So if Trump says you come and fight here
and fight there, Trump should go to
hell. That's what DAT will tell Trump.
That's what the European nations will
tell Trump. This is not our war. You
started this, you end it. You deal with
it. Why are you trying to drag us into
it? That's why they've said no. And
that's why Trump is upset.
But there's nothing Trump can do about
this. So NATO is not over. NATO is still
very relevant in Western Europe. What to
expect from future NATO? It's going to
continue existing and uh they're going
to be focusing on Russia, right? EU
future, EU will also continue for the
for the for the foreseeable future. EU
NATO will both continue. Putin invasion
will start. No, Putin invasion will
start. Putin is not crazy. Nobody is
crazy. Do you think Iran is crazy? Iran
is a very sane, grounded, stable nation
with a stable leadership.
They killed off Kame etc. But Iran's
leadership is fine.
Iran's leadership is the distributed
IRGC leadership and that is that is not
a bunch of mad people. They are very
sane people.
So Iran isn't a bunch of crazy people
and neither is Putin. Putin is a very
sane leader. Okay.
AK edits says US under Dems was more
cunning than Republicans in policy.
What's an INF policy? US and Democrats
was more cunning than Republicans in
policy. Okay. Yuraj Gupta is a new
member. Well, thank you very much.
Welcome to the membership of the
channel. Thank you. Vined Kapper says,
"The Muna has been massively hit
yesterday. Iran really hitting where it
hurts. War going to dangerous level.
Should India allow innocent Iranian
migrants?" Okay, first of all, let's
talk about Dimona before I talk about
any migrants. Where is map? We put the
map on the screen and we're going to
take a look at Dimuna. So Dimuna is not
a nuclear power plant. Dimuna is a town.
Okay. So let's go to uh Israel. Dimona
is in the Ngev desert in the south of
Israel.
So let's zoom zoom zoom zoom zoom.
A
beer shiva.
Okay. Dimona. This is Dimona. But Dimona
is a town. Let's uh
put up the satellite imagery. You see,
if you look here, it's in the southern
part of Israel. Dima is a town. It is
not a nuclear power plant. This is a
town of Dimuna. There's a community
center and there's whatnot. And there's
a mall here. There's a small airfield
here. There's a park
uh and pizza and so on. That is Duna.
But near Dimona
you have this
not this. Hang on where is it?
Oh yeah here we have it. The negative
nuclear research center. So as you can
see it's not in Dona it's near the if
you measure the distance it's about 11
12 km from Dimona right the negative
nuclear research center. And if you see
here, you can see that they have a
nuclear reactor. You can see the dome of
the thing and so on and so forth. This
is the negative thing. So Dimona was hit
yesterday. Dimona the hits came here
here not in the negative nuclear
research center. Okay. So clearly if the
Iranians hit Dimona
it obviously is a warning that if we can
hit demona we can hit negative, right?
So, it's a warning to the US and and
more more than the US, it's a warning to
Israel that if you try and hit our
nuclear facilities, we're going to take
out your nuclear facilities. That's what
the Iranians are messaging and signaling
to Israel and to the United States.
Okay? So, clearly it's a it's it's a
warning. So, there escalation once
again. So, what is the next step in that
escalation?
You first hit the Mona as a warning. If
Israel doesn't get the message then you
hit negative. If the Israel is hit an
Iranian nuclear nuclear facility. Uh so
yeah the war is escalating to dangerous
levels. Absolutely. Could India allow
innocent Iranian migrants? I don't think
any Iranian migrants are trying to come
to India. So the question doesn't arise.
John Amber says, "If AI is being used in
modern warfare and a strike hits still
hits a school full of children, who is
actually responsible? The commander, the
programmer, or the algorithm? Was this
AI or them blaming AI?"
So, a school was a school full of uh
little children was hit by the Americans
in the early initial days of the war
against Iran. We know that, right? 300
400 school children died in that. And
it's very clear if you see the footage,
it's a American Tomahawk missile that is
hitting the school, right? The footage
came out in the public domain. So then I
think AI has been blamed that some AI
system was used by the Americans which
automatically selected targets and then
did it also launch the strikes or was a
human being required to be in the loop
who would then review the targets
selected by AI and approve some and
reject some and then give the green
light for the for the strikes or was the
the whole process taken over by AI and
uh the strikes also launched by the AI.
So we don't know quite exactly how it's
happening right we don't know what the
procedure is what the process is whether
there is a human being in the loop or
not so in that case since we are not
aware of who is responsible see first of
all if you are giving if you are
allowing AI to select targets and then
launch strikes then you being extremely
irresponsible
because there has to be
a human being in the loop
Right? AI makes mistakes sometimes. We
know that every casual user of AI knows
that AI makes mistakes sometimes. So you
need to have a human in the loop unless
you have absolutely no regard for human
lives. But we don't know if the
Americans have a human in the loop. So
then the question is who do you actually
blame? Who's actually responsible? I
would say in that case if we are not
aware of who's responsible, the
responsibility lies with the
commander-in-chief of the United States,
Donald J. Trump, the president of the
US. That's what I would say.
Prataradana says big UAE may buy Indian
weapons, US won't like it. We'll see. We
will see about that. Uh right now it is
UAE may buy. It's not like we signed a
contract and we have exchanged money and
we've sent the weapons. Uh we have not
signed any any contract as far as as far
as I know. There is there are
indications that the UAE is considering
buying Indian weapons and the UAE may
buy Indian weapons. Well, we'll see how
it goes. If they buy Indian weapons, the
US, I agree with you, will not like it.
But maybe neither will Iran. And we want
to have a good relationship with with
Iran also. So we will see about this.
We'll see. Of course, the UAE doesn't
threaten Iran. The UAE seeks to only
have a peaceful existence and uh
self-defense. So even if we sell weapons
to the UAE, I don't think it it really
threatens Iran's uh uh interests. So we
will see about this. When it happens, we
can rejoice. Right now, it's a maybe.
Okay. Hakashi says MLE sent gold to the
UK, unjoined bricks, converted to
Judaism, gave up forklins, speaks
English to appease Trump, took IMF lawn
and US bailout, wants to join NATO.
Well, that's a heck of a lot of
coincidences there, isn't there? Has he
has he converted to Judaism or was he
already Jewish uh by by parentage? I'm
not sure. Um, is Javier Mille Jewish?
Not that Mille. M I L L. Okay. Is Kavir
Mle Jewish or Catholic? He was raised
Catholic but has deeply embraced
Judaism. Oh, fascinating.
Oh, very interesting.
Okay. I have no idea what his religion
and so on. He has mentioned that his
grandfather was Jewish. That doesn't
make you Jewish. Your mother has to be
Jewish in order for you to be born
Jewish.
So he is regarded as a Catholic who is
highly devoted to Judaism.
Very interesting. Now he says he was
Jewish from matrinal descent. You really
what?
Let's see. He discovered he was Jewish
from matrineal descent.
his grandfather. Which grandfather?
Patrineal or matrineal grandfather? Uh,
no idea. Okay. So, that's okay. He seems
to be very devoted to Judaism despite
officially being Catholic. Has he given
up the Faulland silence? Let's check
that again.
Has Argentina relinquished the Faulland
Islands to the UK?
No, it's not relinquished its
sovereignty claim. So yeah, I was not
aware of that and clearly it's not
happened. U he speaks English to appease
Trump. Yeah, sure. Uh took IMF loan in
US bailout, I'm sure. Wants to join
NATO. I don't know about that, but okay.
Did he send gold to the UK? Here's
Argentina.
Sent gold to the UK.
Yes, they have done that. Here's
Argentina. Walked out of brakes. Let's
see.
walked out of bricks.
Has Argentina Yes, they formally
withdrawn from bricks. Has Argentina
taken IMF loans?
Taken an IMF loan?
Taken. Taken.
And
yes, I'm sure it has. Yes. Yes.
Okay. Does
does Argentina seek to join NATO?
Yes, it's seeking to become a NATO
global partner. So, a lot of these
patterns are indeed correct. A lot of
the things that you've said are indeed
correct and some of these may possibly
be correct, but maybe Google's AI
doesn't want us to know. Who knows?
We'll see about that. So, an interesting
set of converging coincidences and there
are no coincidences in geopolitics.
Okay.
Pratana says we need numbers. Quantity
eventually trumps quality. I could not
agree more with you. I completely agree
with you. That's what I mean. I agree
with you. You need numbers. Quantity.
Quantity trumps quality. Quantity has a
quality of its own. And once you have
enough numbers, it trumps all the
quality. Yeah. So the Americans have the
Aegis system. The Aegis system is an is
a system. It's a ship defense system.
It's designed to to destroy incoming
threats like cruise missiles, ballistic
missiles, drones and so on. Now the
Americans have this massive floating
targets
called aircraft carriers. So how do they
protect the aircraft carriers? They
create a bubble
around the aircraft carrier. The bubble
is made up of multiple warships like 7,
8, 10 destroyers, a couple of submarines
and so on. And each destroyer has an
Aegis system which is an uh which is a
ship defense system. So let's say the
the aircraft carriers defensive bubble
let's say it has 200 200 interceptors
missiles.
Let's say it has 300 interceptors.
Let's find out
how many interceptors does an Aegis
system have.
Let's see.
Uh,
Aegis ships typically carry varying
loads of SM3, SM6 with over 500. Okay,
there's a total of 500 SM3s.
Does an
aircraft carrier strike group have?
How many interceptor
missiles does an does a carrier okay 300
to 400 VLS cells hundreds of interceptor
missiles okay 122 so let's say they have
a thousand interceptor missiles okay
so let's say this entire aircraft
carrier strike group has a thousand
interceptor missiles
these missiles each cost about2 to3
million each. So if thousand it's about2
to3 billion dollar worth of
interceptors.
Now let's say I have a shahed class
drones. I launched 2,000 of those. Each
of these costs $20,000.
20,000
20,000 four zeros and you have three
more zeros or seven zeros. So 20 $40
million,000.
Yeah. $40 million. With $40 million
worth of drones, I can destroy the
entire aircraft carrier group just like
that because of quantity.
So that's the deal. It's it's a
mathematical certainty that if I have
more drones than their interceptors
done. Of course, they will have the
point defense guns and so on. But how
many how many? Let's say you launch
2,000 drones and and 50 ballistic
missiles. That's it. End of story.
Guaranteed destruction.
So quantity eventually trumps quality.
It does. So I agree with you. We need
numbers. Mastik Da says, "Hi from
Kolkata." Hello. What if the US says we
have achieved our objectives and leaves
Iran and the world media suppresses the
facts and by the time the US takes over
Greenland over for Trump's image damage
control? Well, the US can do it. The US
can do it, right? So let's say the Trump
says we have won. We have defeated Iran.
we have achieved our objectives then we
are we are out of here and they leave so
then what happens is that the US leaves
and loses its entire power projection
ability in West Asia because all their
bases are destroyed there are let's see
let's see okay
US bases in Middle East
let's see let's see the the graphic I'm
sure there's a graphic somewhere so
these are the American bases in the
Middle East okay what are the green
boots for okay outposts, air bases,
naval facilities. I assure you Iran has
severely degraded all of these if not
destroyed most of these especially the
ones in the Gulf nations along the
Persian Gulf and so on. These are
destroyed, finished, wiped out. If the
Americans say that we have achieved our
objectives and they walk out of of this
place, then they'll lose their power
projection capabilities in this region
at least significant.
they lose significant power projection
capabilities in the region. If they had
let's say a 100% score of power
projection in the region, now they'll be
left with 30 or 20% power production
capabilities in the region, which is a
big setback for them. Now, if the media,
world media suppresses the facts,
that's the western media that will try
to suppress the facts. But the
non-western media will let the world
know what's really happened and the
world will laugh at Trump that you
actually lost this war, right? But
anyhow, let's say Trump still leaves and
all that and let's say he doesn't care
about what the world is saying and then
takes over Greenland. Well, he can do
it. He can take Greenland tomorrow
morning. What can Denmark
Denmark, right? Greenland belongs to
whom? Denmark, Norway.
Does Greenland belong to Denmark or
Norway?
Uh, okay. Denmark, of course. Yeah. So,
what can Denmark do about this? What can
NATO do about this?
Nothing much. So, yeah, Trump certainly
can do something like that. And
Greenland makes sense for the US to
take. Like I've said so many times, I
think by the time Trump is done, he's
going to take Greenland.
Aluk Patel says your view on India's
plan to join sixth generation European
Union jet program. I think it's a stupid
idea. India should stay out of these
things. India should develop its own
fifth and sixth generation fighter
planes. And more than fighter planes, we
need to focus on unmanned systems
like missiles and drones. We need to
focus on very large quantities of
missiles and even larger quantities of
drones.
Autonomous unmanned systems is the
future.
And when it comes to fighter planes, we
should develop our own fighter planes.
That is my view.
Somia Paul says why can't so-called
non-western countries like Russia,
China, Iran, Myanmar, Belarus, Cambodia,
Vietnam, Central Asia and Sahil nations
form a united block against the West?
See Myanmar, okay, let's take these
nations one by one. Russia and China are
kind of working together. Russia, you
could say, has kind of become like a
junior partner of China right now. The
way things are going. When it comes to
Iran, Iran is already cooperating with
Russia and China. In this war, the
Chinese and Russians are providing Iran
with intelligence, ISI, intelligence,
surveillance, reconnaissance data. The
Chinese and Russians are providing uh
Iran with satellite positioning uh
systems, BEu and Lunas. So the the
Russians, Chinese and Iranians are
already cooperating. Myanmar the
government is in the whole nation is in
chaos because of the civil war that's
going on which is being fueled by the
Americans and maybe the Chinese also but
definitely the Americans. So Myanmar
Myanmar is struggling to control its own
country. How will it think about
cooperating with other countries right
now and playing larger geopolitical
games? It can't. Belarus is working with
Russia, right? Cambodia.
See if Cambodia tries to cooperate with
Russia and China, the Americans can
create significant trouble for Cambodia.
So Cambodia wants to stay out of this
geopolitical games. So does Vietnam.
Vietnam already has good relations with
the US and even better relations with
India and they are worried about China.
So each nation depending on where it is
located. It faces various threats and
obviously it is it is afraid of the US
and that's why most nations try to hedge
their bets and remain as neutral as
possible instead of instead of openly
visibly picking one side which is a non-
US side which is going to make the US
very angry most nations are worried and
afraid of the US worried about the US
worried about what the Americans can do
to destroy those nations or destroy
their economies and hurt them and that's
why they're trying to stay out of it
okay that's
Kakashi says Arachi indirectly condemned
Pakistan aggression to Afghanistan on X.
Okay, I haven't seen that. Um
let us uh try and find out.
Uh okay, let's let's not do it because
it will take time to dig out this
specific tweet. There'll be so many
tweets but okay, thank you for notifying
me about this.
Okay, minimalist Maverick says,
"Scenario if the US drops poison on
Iran's food and water." Let's not
discuss such such horrible things. We
don't discuss want to discuss such
things. We don't want to contemplate
such horrible actions and it's not
happened. So, let's not talk about it.
Kakashi says Arachi is cool and Iranian
politicians have great CVs.
The Iranian politicians do have great
CVs, don't they? They're all highly
educated. Many of them have master's
degrees and PhDs. uh Mr. Ari Ali
Larijani had a PhD in philosophy or
something. He was a scholar on canthian
philosophy.
Many of the Iranian politicians have
extensive education educations. They
they are they there are they've either
published books or published research
papers and so much more and they are
very well educated very well read. Yes.
Yeah. So that is indeed true. Yeah.
Compare that with Phil with politicians
from the US.
Compare that with politicians from India
for example. So you can see the
difference right? Iran the politicians
from Iran are a different quality of
politicians.
Yeah. Kauashi says Saudi PM admitted US
Saudi Arabia created Salafism and
Wahhabism.
See Saudi Arabia had its own specific
form of Islam that did not require women
to cover up and all that 150 years ago.
Then the Anglos took over the region.
They installed the house of Sud
as the ruling family of Saudi Arabia.
They gave them military protection and
so on. And that's how Arabia became
Saudi Arabia. And then when you had uh
the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan in
the 19 in late 1979, early 1980, uh
that's when the Americans wanted to have
this jihad against Saudi Arabia against
against uh the Soviet Union. And that's
why the Americans had the Saudis uh
promote this more extreme various
extreme versions of Islam very whether
it is Salafism, Wahhabism, all those
things. I don't know exactly what these
things are but apparently extreme
extremist versions of Islam or whatever.
And so the Saudis did what the Americans
told them because the Americans are the
overlords. And that's how we have the
situation that we have in certain parts
of the world today. So yeah, that is
indeed true.
Nitesh Jooshi says, "You think the US
would have gone for this war no matter
Republicans or Democrats?" Most likely
uh the Democrats
I think the US I think that Israel
enjoys bipartisan support in the US. It
doesn't matter who's in power, whether
it's the Republicans or the Democrats.
If Israel is in trouble, the US always
comes to Israel's aid.
If Israel has to go to war, the
Americans always assist in the in that
war. So, I think the US would have gone
to war for Israel. Even if it was the
Democrats who were in power, I don't
think it would have made any difference.
Kakashi says, "You say Islamism/Islamic
terroris terror is not a thing. Why? I
don't speak about these things. I have
never said that this is not a thing.
That is not a thing. I don't comment
about Islamism or Islamic terrorism. I
don't comment about that ever. I have
never said it is a thing or it is not a
thing. I don't I don't comment about
these matters. Okay? I don't know where
you have heard me say that Islamism or
Islamic whatever is not a thing. I have
never such a thing.
I don't comment about this as a matter
of policy. As a matter of policy from
day one that I've been on this channel,
I don't talk about these things. So I
don't know what you've heard, but I have
never said that. Swapil Saka says,
"Namaste. Namaste. What evidence
suggests Israel influences US political
decisions and could abstain files be a
factor in the US entering this war? What
evidence suggests that influ Israel
influences US political decisions?
Well, on day two or day three of this
war, okay, the US Secretary of State,
which is their foreign minister, Shri
Marco Rubio was having an interaction
with the American media.
And in that interaction, Shri Maru Rubio
Gi said that we knew that Israel was
going to attack Iran and we knew that if
Israel attacked Iran, Iran would attack
us and therefore
because Israel was going to attack Iran,
we also decided to attack Iran.
So essentially he admitted indirectly
that Israel dragged America into this
war against Iran.
And there was no credible evidence that
Iran was planning to attack Israel or
planning to attack any Gulf nation or
planning to attack the US. So if there
is zero credible evidence, zero
intelligence that Iran is planning an
attack on Israel, the Gulf nations or or
the US, then why was there a need for
the US to attack Iran?
There was no need. But Rubia said we
attacked Iran because Israel was we knew
that Israel was going to attack Iran.
That's why we also attacked it on. So,
so doesn't that tell you and I'm I'm
sure I have I may not be using the exact
same words as Rubio, but you can look up
that that interaction that Rubio gave
that he had with the journalists and he
clearly said
essentially that Israel dragged us into
this war. We went into this war because
of Israel. And then the next next day he
says, "No, I didn't say anything like
that. But then if you replay the those
original words, you'll say that you'll
say that he's lying. He's contradicting
contradicting himself. So Rubio's
statements alone
demonstrate
that Israel dragged America into the
war. And America knew that if Israel
fights alone, it will it will not be
good for Israel. That's why the
Americans enter the war. So the
Americans are willing to go to war to
start a war to enter a war because
Israel is involved
against a larger nation. So it's clear
it's it's unambiguous evidence
that Israel
clearly influences very major
top level political decisions by the
United States at the level of the US
president at the level of the US
military
and the way things have gone thus far
it's almost like the US is serving
Israel I mean it could not be any more
obvious anymore in the past people would
say you are talking you are you are
peddling ling conspiracy theories now.
Nobody can ped can say that you are
peddling conspiracy theories when you
said that the Americans are fighting on
behalf of Israel.
It's almost like Netanyahu is the
president of the US.
That's so obvious now. This is no longer
a conspiracy theory. Right? So that's
that's just one blatantly obvious piece
of evidence. You can be you can do your
own research and find more. Could the
Epstein files be a factor in the US
entering the war? Well, I would not rule
it out entirely.
Okay. One wonders what else is there in
the Epstein fires and obviously that can
be held as a held
as as as leverage against
um US politicians. Let's say US
politicians. Okay. So, Satyjit says is
this US West split start of US decline?
I don't see a US west slip uh split
right now. But this is unambiguously
the
the visible beginning of American
decline.
Absolutely visible beginning of American
decline. This is not America's S canal
moment. The S crisis moment. 1956 so
crisis was the official end the official
deaths of the UK as a first rate world
power after 1956 and the S debacle the
UK became a third rate world power at
least a second rate world power today
it's a third rate world power it's not
even a world power no one takes it
seriously now it's the it's the 51st or
52nd state of the US that's what the UK
is today so 56 was the death of the
British Empire. It was the final final
nail in the coffin. 2026 Iran is the
beginning is the visible beginning of
the decline of the US. It's not the end
of the US. But you can now clearly see
that the US is in decline. US power
projection capabilities are in decline.
US prestige is in decline. US
credibility is in decline.
The US military is in decline.
It's it's very very visible. Now,
Chir Chinat says, "Uh, slightly
different question. How do you view
France's position in this conflict and
can it be traced back to Sha the Gaul's
postc world war push for strategic
autonomy, especially after the S crisis
and tensions with the US?"
Okay, France. Shall the Goul. So shall
the ghoul was this great resistance
fighter of the of the French during the
second world war and for a decade after
the second world war. Not immediately
after but later on there was a he he was
the the president of France for roughly
a decade not immediately after the
second world war but a few years later
um 60s around the 60s time right that
period of time and shall the Gul was was
fiercely
he he was fiercely in favor of of of
French sovereignty and independence and
strategic autonomy and France for some
time even withdrew from NATO's core core
working group
Um
so and because of Rashald the goal's
policies and the direction he took for
France and the course that he charted
for France that's that's why France
today is the most strategically
autonomous nation within the EU and NATO
nations. It is a quasi sovereign nation.
It has a quasi independent foreign
policy. not entirely sovereign, not
entirely independent, but the most
independent and most sovereign among all
of the NATO and u uh EU nations, right?
Because the French have their own uh
aircraft carriers. Uh they have their
own jet engines. They have their they
produce their own uh fighter jets, the
Gafas, the MiGis and so on. Uh the
French have their own nuclear weapons,
they have their own missiles, ballistic
missiles. So they independently have
their own deterrence.
In the case of the UK, they have
aircraft carriers, but those can't be
defended against uh supersonic
hypersonic missiles. Even the French
shall the gold aircraft carrier can't be
defended against that. But uh apart from
that, the UK's nuclear deterrent,
their nuclear warheads are mated to
American Trident missiles.
Okay, which means that the big red
button is not in London, it's in
Washington. So the UK's nuclear
deterrent is actually an American
nuclear deterrent. In the case of
France, the big red button is it sits on
Mu Macron's desk, right? So that way
France France is way more strategically
autonomous than any EU or NATO nation.
Uh France,
I don't I don't believe the French have
any US bases on their territory. They
don't host American uh military
personnel and the French intelligence
agencies do not see the US as a friendly
nation
right they see the US as an adversary.
So all of this a lot of this is because
of the course that shall the goal
plotted for France uh in the 20th
century right and the sewers crisis was
a slap in the face for France as well
not just for the UK.
So for the UK it was the final
humiliation. It was the final nail in
the coffin of the British Empire. But
the French also were involved in this
crisis. In 1956 the British, the French
and the Israelis tried to
attack, invade, occupy and control
Egypt.
They made landings in Sis in Port S and
so on. And they did succeed initially
before the Americans told them to get
the hell out. And they had to get get
the hell out.
So the French were also involved and
they also had to
uh ignously
slither away from suis just like the
British. It was kind of humiliating for
the French as well as the British. Um so
with all that in mind, what is France's
position in this conflict? France is not
directly involved in this conflict in
any way whatsoever. Where is the shall
the goal aircraft carrier? Let's find
out. I don't think it's anywhere nearby.
It must be in the Mediterranean right
now.
Where is the French aircraft carrier Sha
the Gaul currently?
Where is it right now? It is in the
eastern Mediterranean Sea. Okay.
Specifically, like I said, it's clearly
in the eastern Mediterranean Sea. It's
uh located northwest of Cyprus,
100 kilometers roughly off the coast of
Turkey.
So 100 kilometers sorry where uh
northwest of Cypress let's take a look
at that.
So Cypress is in the Mediterranean
eastern Mediterranean. Okay. So here we
have Cypress.
It is approximately
100 kilometers of the coast of the
Turkey. North northwest of Cypress. So
somewhere in this region is where the
Shala goal is. It is not exactly near
Israel or something. So yeah, it's in a
kind of forward position but kind of
neutral position as well
and I don't see I don't think there's
any French warship in the vicinity of
the of the Persian Gulf. So France is
kind of staying out of the conflict
especially from military perspective.
Diplomatically they must be obviously
saying that you know please stop the war
and blah blah blah but yeah the French
uh have stayed out of it. Trump will
definitely want the French get involved
with their warships, but France is not
stupid. They won't do it. So, I think
the French are are doing the right thing
by staying out of it militarily.
Mr. Henll says, "If only the US had a
strong man on Iran's border who also
hated Iran. Too bad they took him out
first."
Also, thoughts on India's Indians
vacationing east best. If only the US
had a strong man on Iran's border who
also hated Iran. Well, they had one,
right? But they hanged him. His name was
Saddam Hussein alakriti.
Saddam Hussein aliti.
They hanged him.
Saddam did not exactly hate Iran, but he
did not he don't mind more territory,
right? So, they had Saddam fight Iran,
didn't they?
In what 1980 or something, Saddam
invaded Iran with American uh blessings
with American funds and and weaponry and
all that and his army intruded into Iran
went about 50 60 km into Iran and then
got bogged down for a decade and Saddam
Hussein for five six years for five or
six years he was begging for a ceasefire
and the Iranians said no we don't want a
ceasefire you you started this we got to
end
So even then when the the regime was new
the Iranians said we don't want to stop
the we we don't want to end the war
we'll fight you started this now you
going to pay the price
yeah so uh today there's no Saddam
Hussein the Americans hanged him and
yeah
uh thoughts on Indians vacationing east
best go east go to there are many
fantastic countries in the east right
there's the beautiful nation of Thailand
with such beautiful culture. I have been
to Thailand. I've been to Bangkok in
2023 in autumn. Beautiful place. There
are Vishnu temples on every street
corner almost. Right. I I went there for
the World Hindu Congress which happened
that year. Thailand is beautiful.
Cambodia is beautiful. Uh Vietnam is a
fantastic place. I don't you know you
can even go down south Sri Lanka. You
can even visit Maishes.
There's plenty of nice places within
India itself.
You could go to Korea. You could go to
South Korea. You could go to Japan.
There's plenty of wonderful countries in
the east. You can even visit Russia's
far east if you like. Wonderful place.
Kamchchatka, Sakalin, Ladivostto and so
on. So it's up to you essentially. But I
I would say Indians should also explore
the eastern nations not just keep going
westwards. Okay.
Tiger Okando says, "I have qualified for
IPHD TI for exam physics and have
interview at TI for Bangalore at 24. I
am extremely nervous. Please provide me
with some guidance."
Well, you see being nervous is it's not
unusual. No matter how well prepared you
are, when you're going into an
unfamiliar situation, a high stakes
situation, it's natural to be nervous.
So, it's okay. Um but clearly you are
prepared for what you're doing. You have
qualified for the um
IPDT for exam.
Have you passed the exam or have you
qualified for the exam? I'm not sure
what is qualified for exam and you have
an interview. Well, I would say look on
the 24th you have the interview, right?
Today is 22nd day after tomorrow. Well,
I would say you know what uh
trust in your abilities
trust in your abilities. If you've
qualified for the exam and for the
interview and all it means that you
already well prepared, right? So do
whatever revision you can do in the next
uh 24 hours. Don't overdo it. Okay? Do
the revisions. Look at the concerns. I'm
not sure what they ask in PhD qualifying
exams. They will ask you fundamentals
essentially. Uh they may ask you to
derive things from the on the
whiteboard, blackboard, you know, they
will try and understand how rigorously
you understand the fundamentals of of
theoretical or whatever physics whatever
yeah of of physics. They may ask you to
derive certain things um from from from
first principles. So you need to be well
prepared with the basics with the
fundamentals. You don't need to solve
complicated things or whatever. They
will test your fundamentals, your
basics. They will try and see if you can
solve problems on on the go, that sort
of thing. I suppose I mean if I was an
examiner, that's what I would do. I
would not ask you
complex questions. I'll ask you
fundamental basic questions to see if
you really have the basics down. So
prepare for that. And obviously 24 hours
is not enough to learn something new.
Just revise all that you know. revise
the the fundamentals the basics the core
concepts that underly all of physics
and uh yeah all the best all the best
the being nervous is is natural such
tender played I don't know how many 200
test matches even on the last when he
played the last test match the night
before he could he was never able to
sleep well the night before a test match
right so that is normal no matter how
well prepared you are so that doesn't
mean that you aren't well prepared it
just means that it's it's a it's it's a
high stakes situation and it's an
unfamiliar situation for you. That's how
that's normal. Don't worry about it.
Okay? Trust your abilities. Trust uh
everything you've learned. Prepare as
much as you can over the next 24 hours
without overdoing it and try and sleep
well before the interview. Try and sleep
8 hours and then leave the rest to the
gods. All right. All the best. Do well,
sir. Do well. Let me know. Let me know
in the next live stream how it went.
Okay. All the best. Do well.
Hyphen says, "History shows empires fall
when they grow too large. Is the US
making the same mistake? Is expanding
beyond control as seen in struggles in
West Asia?
You know, the US has expanded across the
world. Yeah. And the mistake they are
making is not that they've expanded too
far and overstretched themselves. That's
not the mistake they are making. The
mistake they have made in the current
war is they have underestimated their
enemy or the nation that they want to
destroy. They have underestimated Iran.
They have not done a proper even basic
cloutin analysis of Iran. What's
Clausvichin analysis? Klon Claus
Clausowitz.
Let me give you let me tell you who Carl
Fon Clausovitz was. He was a great uh
German Prussian uh general and war
analyst Carl Fon Clausvich
C okay this guy okay
and he obviously uh wrote the great book
from on war and he came up with the
concept of punct
right uh center of gravity so center of
gravity is not something that you make
fun of it's an actual military concept
So even if you examine if you even if
you do a a clausitian analysis of of
Iran and the center of gravity and the
critical u critical strengths critical
critical weaknesses and critical
requirements of of Iran requirements of
Iran then you will see that the US has
failed to do it properly. They have come
into the war with the wrong assumptions
and without doing the right kind of
homework.
They
assumed that Iran's critical
vulnerability is its nuclear program and
its and and the personhood of its
leader. They thought this was the center
of gravity of Iran, the nuclear program
and the ayatah the supreme leader. They
thought if we strike on Iran's nuclear
program, nuclear facilities and if we
kill the leader, Iran will come begging
for a surrender.
That was a huge mistake. That is not
Iran's center of gravity. Iran's
leadership is dispersed. It's like a
fault tolerant network. You take out
multiple nodes, the network still
survives. It is fault tolerant.
So that's what Iran is. Its center of
gravity is not the personhood of the of
the supreme supreme leader. They kill
the supreme leader, the RC will put out
a new supreme leader without losing any
functionality.
So the Americans underestimated the
Iranians and secondly they were not
prepared for the quantity versus quality
battle. They did not anticipate that
Iran will have so many drones and
missiles
and the economics of their war is just
wrong. And they went in without knowing
what they wanted to achieve. They
assumed that it will work out in 24 to
48 hours if we kill the there was no
essentially no plan B.
So now the situation is that the
military
actions will perhaps dictate political
outcomes or whatever which is which it
should be the other way around.
So they have made a category error. It
should be that war is a continuation of
politics by other means. But you here
you have politics becoming a
continuation of war by other means. So
the Americans have made massive
mistakes, multiple mistakes in this war.
They have underestimated Iran. They have
miscatategorized uh Iran's center of
gravity. Uh they have not been prepared
for what Iran would throw at them. They
have not done their homework. They have
been full of hubris and uh arrogance.
And now they are panicking.
They have involved all the Gulf nations
in the war. They're trying to escalate
now. Right? So they have the military
might but they have approached the war
in all the wrong ways
and they don't have the means to produce
the kind of the number of weapons you
need to take on Iran. They are running
critically low on tomahawk missiles
stockpiles on interceptor missiles on so
many things and even if they try to ramp
up production it'll take a couple of
years for their military industrial
complex to start producing churning out
weapons in those quantities and those
weapons are going to be incredibly
expensive so they have made mistake
after mistake after mistake
and they are in a situation I don't know
how they will extricate themselves out
of
right uh but it's not yet the fall of
the empire
But it could be the beginning of the
decline and soon perhaps fall. If the
Chinese learn the lessons of the war and
then they go after Taiwan, Korea and
Japan, good god, what will happen? If
that goes in China's favor, it's it's
end of days for the US.
ICMBBS says, "Your take on India wanting
to join FCAS or GCAP?"
FCAS is is is one of those
fighter jet programs, right? European
thing or whatever. Let's see.
FCAS
um future combat air system European
combat system of systems under
development by Daso Aviation Airbus and
Indra Systems. What is Indra systems?
Really? Indra systems
Spanish company. Okay. What is GCAP?
GCAP.
GAP. What is GAP?
GCAP. Global combat air program. British
a merger of British Tempest and Japanese
FX programs partnered with Italy.
So these are programs to
produce sixth generation air fighter
jets. Should India join these programs?
I don't think it's a good idea. India
should develop its own programs. I am
categorically I am fundamentally against
u the joining foreign programs. Right.
Right now India should focus on
producing on mass producing highquality
but cheap drones in in lacks and also
producing tens of thousands of missiles
of various kinds.
India should have the quantity that will
preclude that will ensure it defeats any
quality from any any country. We need
probably millions of drones and tens of
thousands of missiles maybe hundreds of
thousands of missiles. when you have
that you don't even need jet jet
fighters
right and when it comes to fifth sixth
generation fighter planes India should
develop its own that's what I believe
push sa says what will is gain if
allegedly
if the allegations of their involvement
in India's northeast is true what will
they gain by creating instability in
India if they know that India always
stood with them in their difficult time
listen nobody gives a damn you stood
with them in their difficult time and so
on. Nobody gives a damn. In geopolitics,
doesn't matter. In the Second World War,
the Russians and the the Soviets and the
Japanese had a non-aggression treaty,
neutrality treaty. The Japanese did not
ever do a thing against the Soviets.
But three days, two days after the
Americans dropped the Hiroshima bomb,
the Soviets attacked Japan and took
Sakalin and the Kurill Islands from
Japan.
And more than the nuclear tests, it was
the Soviet betrayal that made Japan
surrender. That's how it goes. Nobody
cares that you always stood by them.
Nobody gives a damn. Okay? Let's not be
all emotional. In geopolitics, no one
cares. Okay? Oh, you always stood with
us, we will always be true to you.
Nonsense. No such thing. Understand
that. First of all, we need to remove
our emotions out of all considerations
in geopolitics.
Otherwise, there you will always be
played for a fool. If you are an
emotional person, you think, "Oh, you
know what? I always stood by you and I
expect you will also stand by me."
Nobody will stand by you.
Unless you have something to offer or
unless they have something to gain from
you. Now,
um what does Israel stand to gain? Let's
say involvement India India's northeast.
Look, what do what are the facts that we
know of? Let's forget about what the
allegations are blah blah blah. What
facts do we have?
Here's one set of facts that everyone
knows to be true. There's a bunch of
individuals called cookies who currently
squat on Indian territory in Manipur.
Okay, cookies. They are not Indians.
They're not even Burmese. We know that.
Now, the cookies claim that they are one
of Israel's lost tribes. They claim that
we are Jewish. Actually, our ancestors
were one of the Israeli lost tribes.
There's no genetic evidence. Genetic
evidences that they're not Jewish at
all. But Israel says, "Okay, fine. We
happy with that. So what the Israelis do
is they baptize and convert these people
to Jew Judaism and then they bring them
to Israel, give them citizenship and
settle them. These cookies are settled
in conflict zones in Israel. Territories
taken from the Palestinians and so on.
That's where the cookies are are settled
and they are made to join the armed
forces and fight against the
Palestinians and whoever else. So that
is what the Israelis are using the
cookies for.
So that is one thing we know for sure is
happening. There's a bunch of cookies,
certain number of cookies who are
Israeli citizens. And when this entire
cookie terrorism in Manipur started,
there was a lot of support for the
cookie terrorists in Manipur from the
Israeli cookies
that also we know there were Israeli
cookies u you know posing with automatic
weapons
and threatening the the mates the
manipures
on social media on social media. So that
is a known fact.
A couple of years ago, there was a bunch
of Indian journalists and one Indian
politician who went on a trip to Israel
and the government of Israel brought a
cookie rabbi to meet these Indian this
Indian group and to explain Israel's
position on Manipur.
Now this is clear interference in the
internal affairs of India.
So that also is a fact. It is well known
that this thing happened. This cookie
rabbi was brought to meet with the
Indian delegation and explain Israel's
position on the Manipur thing. What
business does Israel have to do have
have to interfere in India's internal
internal matters? This guy may be a
cookie but he's an Israeli citizen. So
stay so so stay out of Indian matters.
Right?
So these are facts that we are aware of.
Now what does Israel stand to gain in
because of their involvement in this
region and the conflict and so on if
there is any involvement well I think
that question should be asked to Israel
I can only speculate and I don't know
what actually they stand to gain right
but these these facts that I've listed
out you can fact check that right go and
do a Google search go and search on
social media don't ask me to spoon feed
you where's the evidence find it that's
what I would say Okay.
The scrummer says, "Back in our school
days, teachers used to slap one kid so
the other kids making noise would stop
and set an example. Shouldn't we as a
country do the same? First of all, if a
teacher slaps a kid, the teacher needs
to have their bones broken." Actually,
teachers have no business slapping
somebody's kids. First of all, that
that's one thing. Okay. Now, secondly,
in geopolitics, it's a great thing to
do.
Teachers have no right to hit kids. If a
teacher hits somebody's kid, that kid's
parents should come and break the bones
of the teacher actually because hitting
someone's child is a crime. So teachers
have no business doing that. But when
you transpose this scenario into
geopolitics, it's a fantastic idea.
Yeah.
The Chinese have this proverb, right?
Kill the chicken to frighten the monkey.
It's a good idea in geopolitics. Kill
the chicken to frighten the monkey.
Yeah. Prataradana says, "Gatak and cats
warrior drones in numbers are more
important than any fighter jet program
for India. Cost of these will be much
cheaper than any jets." I completely
agree with you.
You know what's the objective? What does
a fighter jet do? The from in the Indian
context fighter jets are either
interceptors who will take out incoming
hostile aerial assets
or they will be used for for for
destroying enemy assets on enemy
territory which means the fighter jet
needs to either you know hit the enemy
assets from standoff ranges from within
Indian airspace or cross over into
hostile airspace and then attack targets
on the ground. These are very
high-risisk missions. You have a fighter
jet that costs millions of dollars and
you have a human being inside the
fighter jet and you've trained that
person over a period of many years and
you've spent god knows how many millions
of dollars in that. That human being is
a very valuable asset and the fighter
jet is very valuable. Now you can do the
you can achieve the same objectives
using unmanned drones, cheap drones that
are a fraction of the cost of a fighter
jet
especially when it comes to a nation
like Pakistan. You can use drones to
achieve all your objectives. So why do
we need to waste so much money on
fighter jets? Jets. We do need fighter
jets. I'm not saying we should not have
fighter jets.
But we can have drones do everything a
fighter jet does. So we should have
fighter jets, but those should be
high-tech, highquality fighter jets that
should be used for only very specific
missions, especially and those missions
should be take should be undertaken only
after drones have sanitized the enemy
airspace and enemy defenses. That's what
fighter jets should be used for. Not
dog fighting is is a 20th century thing.
There's no dog fighting today. But the
Indian Air Force is still still
practicing dog fighting.
So I completely agree with you. We the
Gatak is an unmanned unmanned combat
aerial vehicle, right?
It's a stealthy unmanned aerial combat
vehicle. We need to produce these assets
in large numbers and we need to have
even smaller drones. You know the the
Gartak is supposed to go and be used as
a fighter plane and as a bomber and then
it's supposed to return back to base. So
Gartak is still going to be a reasonably
expensive platform. But I would say use
cheap expendable drones that are
essentially flying bombs that are on a
oneman mission, suicide mission. Use
those drones like the Harop drone, like
the Shahed drone and so on. Produce
these in very large numbers so that you
can launch saturation strikes on the
enemy that the enemy simply can't will
be just overwhelmed by the by the
numbers of drones.
And that's how you just wipe out the
enemy's defenses and their assets. So
then why do you need fighter jets? Once
that is done, you can have fighter jets
go in and maybe land on the enemy
enemy's airports and and take over
physically.
after suppressing the enemy air defenses
and the enemy personnel.
So fighter jets are now increasingly
becoming redundant. Even the American
F-35s and other fighter planes are being
shot down by the Iranians. They are
supposedly the best in the world, right?
The F-15s and F-35s and all. Do you see
how dangerous it is to have fighter jets
and to operate fighter jets in contested
airspace now?
So I completely agree with you that
these assets you know flying munitions
uh suicide drones and gatak like like
platforms these are the future of aerial
combat and that's what India needs to
invest in. Fighter jets are increasingly
uh a relic of the 20th century. We
should still have some we should still
have our own high quality jet engines
and all that
but but we should not put them in harm's
way. We should instead send use drones
for putting them and put drones in
harm's way where where anyway doesn't
matter if a drone is destroyed or not.
Polomial says the only option the
Americans have is to back out of the
conflict but this may not be politically
feasible. Does this thing does it mean a
war might start somewhere else which
gives them an exit strategy?
Interesting. So the Americans their best
option is to back out of the conflict. I
completely agree with you. But this is
not politically feasible because if you
back out now, even if you claim victory,
the world will laugh at you and even the
American voters will laugh at Trump and
they will say that you have led our
nation to its biggest humiliation since
Vietnam
and that will be the end of Trump's
political career.
He's going to be humiliated and
whitewashed in the midterms in November.
That seems to be more and more likely
now. So what can Trump do about this? He
has to somehow win. But there is no way
he wins against Iran. Even if he nukes
Iran with 10 nuclear bombs, it's not
going to work. Why do I say this?
Because Iran is so mountainous that even
a nuclear weapon if it is detonated
somewhere will produce local
destruction.
But the nuclear fallout radiation will
not spread horizontally. It will first
go vertically up because of the
mountains and only after it it reaches a
certain altitude will it start spreading
horizontally and then it will spread
over the entire region West Asia
including Israel. It will even come to
Pakistan, India.
And it doesn't kill people immediately.
The effects are long-term effects. If
you're exposed to radiation, you may
have cancer in 5 10 years, but you won't
die immediately. So you'll keep
fighting.
So even if you detonate 10 nuclear
weapons, tactical nuclear weapons, it's
not going to prevent Iran from stop fire
from from fighting. They will keep on
fighting another 10 years. So even if
Trump employs nukes, he's not winning
this war. So what does he do now? Does
he start a war somewhere else? Well, he
can invade Greenland. Sure, that will be
a big victory for the Americans. They'll
gain a big chunk of territory.
But will that be enough to offset the
humiliation they are going to suffer in
Iran? they that they may be that they
may suffer in Iran. I'm not sure. Where
else can he start a war? Who else does
he attack? Does he attack China?
Oh man, that is maybe the Chinese are
waiting for that. What What does he do?
Does he attack Russia? That is suicidal.
Attacking Russia is if you can't deal
with Iran, do you think you can deal
with Russia?
I don't know where he starts a new war
which gives the gives them exact
strategy
right now in a few months the Chinese
may be tempted to start a war with
Taiwan about Taiwan to launch an
invasion of Taiwan because America's
resources are getting depleted very
rapidly their interceptors they're
they're very short on interceptors
they're very short on to Tomahawk
missiles they're short on THAD TH a
terminal high altitude area defense
systems they're short on everything
the EU is short on munitions. NATO is
short on munitions because all the
munitions have been eaten up by Ukraine.
It's actually a fantastic opportunity
for China to wait a few more months for
the war to go on so that the US reserves
are further depleted and then launch an
invasion on Taiwan.
I don't see Trump having an exit
strategy anywhere. Even if he uses
nukes, it's not going to
have America win the war. Trump has dug
himself into a very deep well. I'm not
sure how he exits this well,
but it's going to get worse.
He has given a 48 hour deadline
ultimatum to the Iranians and the
Iranians are are seeing nothing doing.
So I I am seeing more escalation coming
now. Trump is if if we are not careful
Trump is going to turn this into World
War II. Yeah.
Ankita Kachab says, "Good evening,
ma'am. What about Israel? What did it
achieve in terms of peace and stability
in the region in the long run?"
That's a good question. What were
Israel's objectives in in all of this?
Um, Netanyahu probably see Nathan who
probably wanted regime change in Iran.
Uh,
Israel is is right to be worried about
Iran. Iran has consistently since 1979
said that Iran that Israel does not have
the right to exist. So from Israel's
perspective, it is correct for them to
worry about Iran and want a regime
change. Um Iran Israel says says that
Iran should not have nuclear weapons.
Well, that's a hypocritical stance
because Israel has its own nuclear
weapons. So if they can have nuclear
weapons, why can't Iran have nuclear
weapons? But they say, you know, it's
not allowed. Um so Israel's objectives
were first of all the destruction of
Iran's military capabilities, secondly
the destruction of Iran's nuclear
capabilities and nuclear program and
thirdly regime change and fourth ideally
bulcanization of Iran. Now these are
these are the objectives that is Israel
had. How many of these objectives have
they achieved? None. They have not
destroyed Iran's military capabilities.
They have not destroyed Iran's drone and
nuclear and and and missile
capabilities. They have not destroyed
Iran's nuclear program or nuclear
capabilities. They have not done they
have not successfully achieved a regime
change in in Iran. And they are years
away from ever balkcanizing Iran. They
have achieved none of these objectives.
But they have taken a tremendous amount
of damage
in Israel on Israeli territory. Tel aiv
has been hit over and over and over
again. Hi has taken tremendous damage.
Other parts of Israel have taken damage.
Isbaha has been activated. They are
launching missiles at at Israel. Dimona
has been hit by ballistic missiles.
So Israel is taking almost as much
damage as as Iran is taking. And
Israel's number one ally, America, the
United States, its bases have been
essentially destroyed in the region.
So if Israel thought that it will
achieve a easy victory and achieve peace
and stability in the region, they have
achieved the exact opposite of that. And
their people have are in the process of
suffering. They are being hit every day
by Iranian missile strikes. And these
missiles are are the many of these
missiles are launching cluster
munitions. So one missile launches 50 or
60 submunitions that all hit
independently. and each is a separate
explosion. So clearly Israel has not
achieved any of the objectives it sought
to achieve. Has Israel gained any
territory? It's trying to grab some
territory from from Lebanon if it can
defeat uh Hezbollah and take some
territory from them. That could be one
gain that they may achieve if they are
able to succeed. I'm not sure if they'll
be able to succeed in that also because
we'll see about how it goes. So long run
I don't see peace and stability being
achieved in the region. Long run there
is destabilization that's been achieved
in the region. So yeah it's it's not
gone the way they wanted at all.
Anabilar says 10 Ukrainian drone
operators soldiers beat two battalion
NATO forces
in 2025. NATO can't beat Russia.
10 Ukrainian drone operators,
soldiers beat two battalion NATO forces
in 2025. NATO can't beat Russia.
Okay, I'm not aware of this incident,
but okay. Uh NATO can't beat Russia.
Well, we'll see.
See, if you want to defeat Russia, you
need to have better capabilities in
Russia. And you also need strategic
depth. Russia has tremendous strategic
strategic depth because of Siberia
enormous territory. Even if they take
tremendous damage in a war, they can
simply move their factories further
eastwards, further eastwards, further
eastwards and they have all the
resources there just like operation
Barbar Roa 1940s.
And Russia
over the past four years has learned how
to fight a 21st century war, right? they
have chosen to take the long approach,
frozen conflict,
um you know that sort of thing, long war
scenario. Uh but they know how to fight
a 21st century conflict with drones,
with missiles and so on. And they have
ramped up their production of drones,
missiles, munitions, weapons, all of
those systems. And their air force is
more or less intact. And Russia has done
a very very wise thing by keeping their
air force out of harm's way. Most of
their air force, some of their aircraft
would have been destroyed and so on. We
know operation spiderweb that was on the
ground, but they have not pressed large
quantities of fighter planes into
service into operations over hostile
territory. So Russia has actually done
the right things. They've been very wise
and their military industrial complex is
now churning out weapons, munitions,
everything in very large numbers. If
there is a war between Russia and NATO,
I don't see NATO prevailing at all.
Yeah.
Mishan says, "Are Sunnis on Israel's
radar after Shia are done?" I have no
idea. I don't know. No idea. Sorry.
Can't speculate. You seem
says my earlier question stemmed from
the fact that any scientist who tried
something revolutionary has been hurt in
some ways. Nambi Om Baba scares me. What
was your earlier question about you
getting into military-industrial complex
will that harm you? Uh well
yeah I I I know what you mean. Homie
Baba we know that he was killed off in a
plane crash which was very suspicious
and they did not Yeah. that um Nambi
Narayan all those false allegations were
made against him and so on. So look when
you are in national security and defense
and all there's always some potential
danger that could be there. So you have
to be cognizant of that right if if if
it is something that is if a certain
degree of potential danger is something
that's something that you don't want
then you should go into a different
sector I would say. Yeah.
Clavian says two questions. First, why
was Hitler so obsessed with Nordic
people in his aran Arian ideology?
Secondly, if a nation is peaceful for 60
or 70 years, do they become soft? Uh why
was Hitler so obsessed with Nordic
people in his Arian ideology? I don't
know. I have not tried to do a
psychoanalysis of Adolf Hitler.
So, and and he himself was did not have
that much of a so-called Arian
appearance. So according to his
worldview, Arian means north European
people with blue eyes and blonde hair
and those Nordic features. That was what
that was Arian according to him. And
today because of that uh Nazi worldview
the entire world believes including lots
of Indians that Arian means blue-eyed,
blondhaired and white-kinned. And even
Indians believe this despite Indians and
Iranians being the actual Arians, not
the white people. So the actual Arians
are brown people. The Arya people are
Indians and Iranians. Our Vic ancestors
not the whites. But Hitler reconfigured
the meaning of Aryan. Right. Uh so I
have no idea why he was obsess obsessed
with these people. I don't know. I have
not really bothered to study the roots
of his obsession. I have not read mine.
Maybe there is some answer to your
question in mine camp but I haven't read
it. So I don't know. But it it is what
happened and the world is still dealing
with the consequences of the nonsense.
Secondly, if a nation is peaceful for 60
or 70 years, do they become soft? Short
answer, yes.
War is horrible. War is brutal. War is
cruel.
But war prevents a nation from going
soft.
War
despite all the cruelty, all the
inhumity, all the all the tragedy,
it has the effect of rejuvenating
nations. It cuts off all the fat and the
flab from a nation.
It solves the problem of elite or
production. It solves the problem of
mediocrity.
The overproduced elites are taken care
of by wars. And the mediocre people who
may be in battle are taken care of by
war.
And in warfare, if it's a protract
protracted war, there's going to be
field promotions on the battlefield.
What's a field promotion on a
battlefield? You're fighting a battle.
You're a platoon or company or whatever,
80 soldiers led by a commander.
And let's say during the course of
battle your commander loses his life.
Tragic. Now what do you do? You need
someone to lead you. Now how are you
going to decide who becomes the
commander because your commander is
dead. Are you going to see oh who is the
senior most person here? No. You're
going to promote the most capable person
to the post of commander. That's called
a field promotion. It happens when your
commander is killed in battle. So when
you have field promotions,
the most capable people rise to the top.
If a war goes on for long, you're going
to have field promotions all across the
board. And then at the end of the war,
you have the most capable people leading
the armed forces and potentially the
political uh class of the country.
So wars harden nations.
Wars make nations in a way much better.
But obviously wars cause immense
suffering to the most innocent of the
people which is the civilians. So you
see that's the trade-off. Without wars a
nation becomes soft and obsessed with
all the wrong ideas. But if you have
wars there's going to be suffering but
it makes the nation far better and it
weeds out the
people who can't survive tough times.
So war is like winter in the northern
areas.
Yeah, right.
Fast snail says, "What can China do to
stop Japan's nuclear program? Can they?
They can't do a thing." Japan doesn't
have a nuclear program. They have a
civilian nuclear program. They have
reactors, some of the best reactors in
the world. But Japan is not in the
process of developing nuclear weapons.
If they want to develop nuclear weapons,
they can have them next week. That's how
advanced their nuclear technology is.
What can China do to stop it? Nothing.
Of course, Japan, if they acquire
nuclear weapons, they will have to test
them. The Chinese can protest and do
diplom diplomatic protests and so on so
forth. But again, that makes no big
difference. But my view is that if Japan
does acquire nuclear weapons in the
future, it's going to be American
nuclear weapons most likely,
which means that the Americans will park
their nuclear weapons on Japanese
territory and point them at China.
Just like the situation in Pakistan, I
don't believe for one second that the
nuclear weapons in Pakistan are
Pakistani made.
99.9% my opinion is that these are
American nuclear weapons in Pakistan
in on Pakistani territory. So Pakistan
is the custodian of these weapons but
the weapons are actually in the custody
of American technicians on Pakistani
territory and they are aimed at India.
So that is most likely what the
Americans will do with a vijapan aimed
at China.
Sachadev Sati says how dangerous are
dirty bombs? Will Iran use one? So
before I answer how dangerous they are,
the question is will Iran use one? Iran
is not a stupid nation. Iran won't use
one unless they are targeted by with
nuclear weapons. If Israel or the US
detonates nuclear weapons on Iran's
territory,
then Iran will not hesitate from using
conventional or dirty nuclear weapons.
If they have conventional warheads by
now, they will use those. If they don't
have conventional warheads, they
definitely can manufacture con dirty
bombs because they have file material,
hundreds of kilograms of moderately 60%
enriched uranium. So what's a dirty
bomb? A dirty bomb is a normal chemical
weapon. Chemical bomb. So what is a
chemical bomb? A hand grenade is a
chemical bomb. A tank shell is a
chemical bomb. A ballistic missile
conventional warhead is a chemical bomb.
Bomb, right? Plastic explosive which you
see in movies, these are chemical bombs.
So a dirty bomb is a standard chemical
bomb
which also has uranium or plutonium
along with it. So when the chemical
explosive explodes, it's going to either
fragment or vaporize the uranium or the
plutonium or whatever u radioactive
material is there in the package and
that will be dispersed over a very wide
area causing massive radioactive fallout
and contamination of the area.
So it won't kill people immediately but
people will gradually start falling
sick. People who are exposed to massive
doses of radiation, they will have
radiation sickness in a couple of days.
Some of them may die in a week or two,
maybe a month. Other people, you may
have cancer after 5 years, after 10
years. You have you may have children
born with defects. So that is a
long-term disaster,
but immediately it's just an explosion
of a of a chemical bomb. So that's a
dirty bomb. It doesn't kill people in
large numbers like a nuclear weapon like
like a like like a proper nuclear uh
detonation, but it irradiates a large
area. Depending on the size of the
chemical explosion
that the the the the magnitude of the
chemical explosion will determine the
size of the irradiated area in a certain
radius around the the place where the
explosion happened. And if the explosion
happens in midair, then the fallout will
be larger. It depends. Okay.
Abising says, "On a leader
scale from Kaiser Villhan to Jail Neu,
where will you rank Trump?" Good God,
what a question and what a pertinent
question.
Where do I rank Trump? Well, I don't
know if you can compare Trump with Mr.
Nu. Mr. Nero was magnificent. Trump is
behaving like an like a demented madman
right now.
Where would I rank Trump? Maybe
He he shows some characteristics of
Ilulch Benolini.
Yeah.
I don't know. We'll see. Let let let let
us be done with the Trump presidency.
Then then we will be able to better rank
him in the hierarchy with with the
benefit of hindsight. Right now the
person who he reminds me the most of is
Ben Mussolini. I'm not saying Trump is
fascist but personalitywise
vision says is the there is a sudden
influx of cookie militancy videos on my
Twitter for you feed any propaganda
there is a sudden influx of cookie
militancy videos on my Twitter for you
feed is that propaganda I have no idea
so there are two tabs on Twitter one is
the bunch of people you follow the
accounts you
And the other one is for you which is
determined by the Twitter algorithm. I
don't know on what basis they decide
what you should see but there's a for
you feed. Yes. And you saying that
there's a big influx of cookie terrorism
militancy videos on your for you feed.
Is it propaganda? Is it not? I have no
idea what it is. I can't say. But those
videos I'm pretty sure they are real
videos.
Yeah.
So yeah, I don't know if it's propaganda
or not, but the the koki terrorist
activities are real. Yes. Okay. Uh Akit
Sharma says, "How relevant is Tulsi
Gabbad's statement on Pakistani nukes?"
I have not seen her statement on
Pakistani nukes. Let me quickly try and
see what it is.
Tulsi Gabbad's statement on Pakistan
nuclear weapons.
What did she say?
Okay. She says that Pakistan missiles
are future threat to the US.
Um,
Pakistan biggest nuclear threat to the
US says Tulsi Gabbad. Syrian news 18.
Pakistan has a history.
Okay. Pakistan's long-range ballistic
missiles could potentially be a problem
for the US. Okay. So, she is trying to
warn the US leadership that Pakistan is
a problem for the US. I well
it certainly is relevant. She is the
director of national intelligence in the
US.
Yeah. She is the boss of the all the
intelligence programs and intelligence
agencies of the US. So obviously if she
says something it's it's going to be
taken very seriously. Right. Uh but what
will be done about this? What action
will the US takes take on this? Not very
sure about that. Her statement is
obviously very relevant. She's a very
important person and she is a very
credible person and she's a very
grounded person. She is not given to
hyperbolic statements. So if she says
something you have to take it seriously.
I hope the US establishment and the
Trump uh regime takes this seriously.
Okay. Kauashi says what is petro dollar
and does it fund terrorism?
So there's dollar in this petro dollar.
What is the petro dollar?
The petrol order system is see
originally the United States dollar was
tied to the price of gold
which basically if the US uh government
had a certain number of US dollars in
global circulation then the US treasury
needed to have that quantity of gold in
their ws.
So that's why the US dollar was the the
paper currency was an actual proxy for
physical gold. Then in 1971 or
thereabouts the Americans delin the US
dollar from from gold. So it became a
free floating currency not linked to
anything of real value. It became a fiat
currency.
Then to make the to to to continue the
dollar's relevance the Americans uh
reached an agreement with the Gulf
nations especially Saudi Arabia that all
all transactions that involve oil buying
or selling of oil will only be done in
US dollars. So that ensured that the US
dollar became
remained globally relevant and it
remained the global reserve currency. So
all petroleum transactions since the
1970s have only been done in US dollars.
So if you are India and you have a bunch
of rupees, you buy US dollars from Saudi
Arabia. You can't give the Saudi
Arabians rupees. You have to acquire
dollars and then buy the oil only for
dollars. You can only give dollars to
Saudi Arabia. That was a deal. And
that's why the US dollar be remained so
relevant until very recently. Now the
Saudis are are selling oil to the
Chinese in yuan. They taking yuan
instead of dollars. So the dollar is is
no longer the petro dollar now. But that
was the petro dollar system. Did it
front terror? I'm sure it did.
Fields strong man says why did Hollywood
always show Japan as the tech superpower
in the distant future? Alien. Yuthani
Corporation Corporation 1989. Blade
Runner 1982. Cyberpunk game 2019 far
ahead of the US not done for other
vasals US you told us 60s7s Japan was
insane tech power truth or paid off
uh okay so Hollywood did show Japan as
this m as this technological superpower
no question about it see until the 1980s
even 1990s even today Japan is
incredibly advanced technologically
Japan is even now
the world's most technologically
advanced society.
Okay.
Until the 1980s, Japan was the world's
second largest economy.
And if you see Hollywood movies from
that time, you will see the Japanese,
you'll say that the Americans were in
awe of the Japanese. So, Alien, Utani
Corporation, Blade 82, it's all Tokyo.
the the the the the cyberpunk thing and
all right the the neon uh cityscape of
Tokyo that was the inspiration for
Bladeunner 82 cyberpunk game I'm not
aware of and so on uh there were more
movies right uh what's that movie uh red
sunrising
there are many movies like that uh the
the the the Kristoff Lombair movies what
was that um I forget the names of the
movies but yeah there was a lot of Japan
and lot of Japan being being shown as
this or inspiring nation,
technologically advanced, very hard
negotiators and so on. And that's why
that's because the Americans were
genuinely in awe of the Japanese at that
time. Okay? And of course, Japan was a
defeated nation. Japan was a vasa. So
there was no harm showing Japan in good
light. They never showed the USSR in
good light even though you even though
the USSR was also aspiring in in
multiple domains. So that's only done
when Hollywood praises
a non-American a foreign nation or shows
a foreign nation in good light. It's
always
it's always going to be the case that
it's a defeated or vasal or vasalized
nation. It's always going to be like
that.
So um they will never show India in a
good light ever. They will show various
cultures in good light. Whether it's the
Greek culture, whether it's the Roman
culture, all cultures of the past, they
will show the Polynesian culture in good
light because Polynia is insignificant
geopolitically and part of the US bunch
of vasals. So they'll show Moana,
Polynesian culture in good light.
They'll show Mexican culture in good
light because Mexico once again is a
American basal whether it is u which
movie was it?
Um I forget the names of the movies.
some some P Pixar movie or whatever
Disney movie the movie with the day of
the dead
I forget forget the name but yeah they
only do this for defeated nations or
vasalized nations
right the rock stars what happens if
unknown men target PFI cookie rohhingas
kangloo
well if that happens then that happens
what happens it means
It means has it happened? Has it
happened?
Right. Um the unknown men typically
target enemies of India outside of
India. If this starts happening within
India, it it could destabilize India.
The solution is not to have unknown men
target enemies of India within India
because these these individuals you're
talking about are infiltrators who are
in India in very very large numbers. The
solution is not to have unknown men
target them. The solution is to legally
deport the these people who are all
illegal infiltrators. That is the
solution.
Funny says, "What do you think of the
role of AI in this war? I know the US is
using it. What about Iran missiles?" uh
trump any defense systems or jets? Why
are we not taking talking about
submarines in this war? Does Iran have
ICBMs or nukes by any chance?
Uh what do I think of the role of AI in
this war? The US is using AI. What about
Iran? I don't know if Iran has any
world-class AI systems. I'm not sure.
Probably they don't, right? Probably
they do not. Missiles trump any defense
systems of jets. I agree. Yes, missiles
can do the job that in the past uh jets
would have done and missiles can take
off your take care of your defense as
well. Yes, missiles and a multi-layered
defense system which includes not just
missiles but also guns, gatling guns and
various kinds of other assets. Uh why
are we not talking about submarines in
this war? Because submarines well we did
speak about submarines when an American
submarine destroyed an Iranian warship
south of Sri Lanka. We did talk about
submarines right at that point in time.
an American submarine torpedoed the
Iranian uh warship which was not an
active combatant. Um apart from that
submarines have not really participated
in the war. Iran has a number of small
submarines and those seem to be
completely intact and undamaged. What
are they doing? Are they also
participating in the blockade of
hormones or the selective blockage of
blockade of hormones? We don't know. The
thing about submarines is that they are
not visible. So you don't know what
they're doing and that's why people
typically don't speak about them unless
they are aware of what's really
happening which people outside of the
inner circles don't know about that is
the thing about submarines they are
invisible they are stealthy and they are
very deadly and very scary
says hi sir Joe Kent director of CT USA
what's CT USA resigned saying the US
president is being controlled by Israel
is it safe to say the US is a vasal
officer of Israel.
Okay. Who who was Joe Kent? I remember
that. I tweeted about that. Joe Kent.
Who was Joe Kent? Okay. The former
director of the United States National
Terrorism Counterterrorism
Counterterrorism Center. So, let's go to
Twitter. Let me find the tweet by Joe
Kent uh that he put out and uh let's
let's take a look at that, shall we?
Give me a second. Let me pull out the
relevant tweet. Um, Joe Kent,
Joe Kent, Joe Kent, Joe Kent, where is
he? Give me a second or two.
Um,
in which he did say very clearly that.
Yeah, here it is. Give me a second.
So, let's see what he actually uh stated
in his tweet.
Let's remove this and let's put the
tweet out.
Joe Kent, let it load.
So, here is the tweet by Jokent. Joe
Kent is the former um the former what?
Former director of the US National
Counterterrorism Center.
President Trump, after much reflection,
I have decided to resign from my
position as director of the National
Counterterrorism Center effective today.
I cannot in good conscience support the
ongoing war in Iran. Iran posed no
imminent threat to the United States and
it is clear that we started this war due
to pressure from Israel and its powerful
American lobby.
Right. and long star and and long
message after that. I pray at the end he
says I pray that you will reflect upon
what we are doing in Iran and who we are
doing it for. The time for bold action
is now and so on. So he says that I have
decided to resign
and it is clear that we started this war
due to pressure from Israel and its
powerful American lobby.
Right?
He is saying that very openly. So
essentially he's saying that the
Americans were the United States was
dragged into this war by Israel and he's
also saying that this war is a war that
is being fought to serve Israel.
Essentially it serves Israel's interests
not America's interests. There was um
there was no imminent threat to the
United States from Iran.
Right.
So is it safe to say that the US is a
vasal of Israel?
But it's a good question. It's a good
question.
Israel clearly is not a vasal of the US.
And the way things have gone in this
war, it looks like we have to ask
ourselves this question quite seriously.
Is the US actually a vasal of the US of
Israel?
Um, I'll I'll think about this. I
maybe it's a little early to say yes,
but it's not early. It's not early to
say maybe.
Right. I I I have said this, right?
After this war is over, I'm going to
revisit the the sovereignty index. Right
now, there are six sovereign nations on
the sovereignty index. My sovereignty
index. That's the US, Russia, China,
India, Israel, and Iran.
The question is, is the US really
sovereign? If they are serving the
interests of Israel, are they really
sovereign? I will revisit this in a in a
month or so.
But it's a good question to ask. And the
answer is
is not no right now. It's maybe. Okay.
Business says through what circumstances
we shall learn and do what?
Through what circumstances we shall
learn and do what? Now I don't know what
the question is. I'm not able to
understand the question. This question
is in reference to what is in Is it in
reference to the war?
The question is pretty unclear.
Through what circumstances we shall
learn and do what? I have no idea what
it means. I'm very sorry. I wish I could
understand what you're trying to ask me.
But it helps if you formulate the
question in a clear unambiguous manner
so that someone with less intelligence
like me will understand it. See my
intelligence has is is not able to I I
clearly don't have the sufficient
intelligence to understand this. See
sorry Praradana says Muslim name favin
may be rigid abartin.
Uh okay I I'm I'm not aware of this. I
can't even begin to to analyze that
right now. Okay. I I'm not sure but
maybe okay maybe you have thought about
this.
Uh so okay okay okay
says please rank leaders of six
sovereign countries 1 to six.
Okay the leaders of the six sovereign
countries. So the so the six sovereign
countries are the US, Russia, China,
India,
Israel and Iran.
So we have
let me just open a note over here.
We have
Trump,
Putin,
Xiinping,
Modi.
Uh, who else do we have? Um, who's the
leader of Iran? The younger Kame Kame
Jr.
and Netanyahu.
Netanyahu.
Okay. So, how I
am a man.
So, we have Trump, we have Putin, we
have Xijin, we have Modi, Kame Jr.,
Nathan. Now, you're putting me in a very
difficult position here because I will
have to rank Mr. Modi somewhere in this.
And no matter where I rank Mr. Mr. Modi,
half of you are going to be very upset.
So
let's let's keep Mr. Modi aside as a
special case and let us see
uh see Kame Jr. is a new leader. I don't
know where to rank him. So let's also
keep him aside.
But who are the experienced leaders
here? Trump clearly
Putin, Fiji Ping and Netanyahu.
I would out of Trump, Putin, Xijin Ping
and Natanyahu. I would put
uh I would say Putin number one,
Xiinping number two. I would say
Netanyahu number three and Trump number
four. So it's Putin, Xiinping,
Netanyahu, Trump.
The younger Mr. Kame, the new supreme
leader, he is untried, untested. So I
can't rank him anywhere. And I will not
rank Mr. Modi anywhere because it will
it will it will displease at least 50%
of my audience no matter where I put
him. So Mr. Modi I'm not ranking him
anywhere. All right. Okay. Please
forgive me.
Okay. Sparoo says X says, "Namaste G.
This is my first super chat ever." Well,
okay. Thank you. Have I have learned so
much from you history, international
relations, etc. You're my online guru.
Thank you for your teachings. Well,
well, thank you so much, sir. Thank you
so much. Um, thank you so much. I really
appreciate your very very kind and warm
message. It's a privilege to be able to
communicate with you all on an ongoing
basis. I've been doing that since 2021
and uh well, it's all thanks to you that
I keep doing this. So, thank you to you
too and to all my viewers and
specifically uh SP Arouch XG. Thank you
so much. Thank you.
It's all about Sashank says what are the
good things Indra Gandhi did as prime
minister? Uh one of the good things uh
Mrs. Gandhi did as prime minister. Well,
one is Pokran 1974. I think it was under
her prime ministership that India um
detonated or tested its first ever
nuclear uh device in Pokran. That's one.
Number two, 1971 the the the vivise
section of Pakistan and the um the the
creation of Bangladesh. Of course the
question is why was Bangladesh not
reincorporated into India because it's
anyway historically Indian territory and
if Bangladesh was not reinccorporated
into India why was Chitagong not taken
into India why was the siliguri corridor
not widened so you see those things
should also have been addressed but okay
she did defeat Pakistan she did give the
army the kabl to go ahead and do
whatever it takes to defeat Pakistan in
71 good job agreement was a bad
we gave back territory in West Pakistan
that we had no business giving back to
them and uh we treated them as as equals
there of a defeated nation. So yeah that
but anyway I would say 1974 and 1971
definitely
excellent u things that Mrs. Gandhi did
as prime minister. I'm sure there's more
but I can think of two right now. Yeah.
WKT says grandpa told that Sri Neu died
due to an STD. What's my opinion?
It's not a matter of an opinion. It's a
matter of whether this is true or not.
Even I have heard
uh this claim being made that he died of
a sexually transmitted disease. Now, is
it true or not? I have no idea. If he
did die of a STD, I'm sure the
government of India would cover it up,
but then some of some people would know
about it and that's why the news will
spread. So, I don't know. I have no
opinion about this. I don't know whether
it's true or not, but a lot of people
seem to be of the opinion that it's
true. That's why we must perhaps take it
seriously this this claim, right? But I
don't know if it's true or not because I
have not seen any evidence that proves
this and I have not seen any evidence
that doesn't that disproves this. So
it's somewhere out there in between.
That's that's how I see it.
Cortana says emperator
salutant
hail emperor those who are about to die
salute you.
Thank you. I love that movie. Yes, love
that movie.
Anoj says, "Do you think countries will
try to denuclearize Pakistan in the
future as now the US has put Pakistan at
as risk for its security? Can India with
the help of Israel convince the USA? So
uh Miss Gabad, Miss Tulsi Gabbad, the
director of national intelligence of the
US, she has said like I just saw that
Pakistan is a threat to the US because
of its uh nuclear weapons and u and the
missiles that it's developing. Okay. So
yeah, that is indeed the case. She has
indeed made the statement and she is a
very uh senior person in the US
government and she has to be taken
seriously. Uh now
uh will countries try to denuclearize
Pakistan in the future? And can India
with the help of Israel convince the US?
Sir, please sir sir, we are begging you.
Please be convinced. See, Israel also
agrees with me. Please do something for
us. Are we a bunch of losers or what?
Why do we have to convince the US?
The Pakistani nuclear weapons, my dear
friends, are actually American nuclear
weapons. These are American nukes on
Pakistani territory. Maybe Madame Tuli
Gabad has not been given this
information.
Okay.
But the most likely the Pakistani
nuclear weapons are actually American
nuclear weapons on Pakistani territory.
That explains a lot of things about
operation Sundur and the way it was
suddenly stopped after the after the
after after the targeting of Kirana
Hills.
So if the Americans have placed American
nuclear weapons on Pakistani territory,
why will they denuclearize Pakistan?
Pakistan is a useful asset for them. And
those weapons are American weapons aimed
at India.
So you can go and beg to the Americans
sir please sir sir please sir sir yes
sir full support sir please please
please dnuclear Pakistan. They will
laugh at you privately. Okay. If India
is is concerned about Pakistani nuclear
weapons, India must find a way to
denuclearize Pakistan on our own instead
of going and begging to other countries.
This this slave mentality has to has to
be expuned from our minds that we need
to go and beg some great sir please help
us out. Please duclearize Pakistan. Yes
sir. Stop this nonsense.
Grow a spine and grow some some some
some dignity and selfrespect. Stop
begging others to help you. India has to
solve this problem on its own. Neither
Israel I mean you think Israel.
Okay. Israel Pakistan
that's also an interesting question.
Okay.
Rarun Rajger. It's always a tongue
twister but good to see you. ships used
to switch off transponders where when
passing through the straight of Hormuz
but Pakistan ship revealed the route
while P while while passing. Why did
Pakistan do it? I have no idea.
I don't know if this has happened and if
it has happened I don't know why they've
done it.
So I I'm not aware of this and I I can't
begin to speculate.
Uh ships do switch off transponders.
Even aircraft switch off transponders.
If if if you have some time on your
hands, go and look at the flight data.
There are various websites where you can
see, you know, realtime flight analysis
and data like flight radar 24 and so on.
You will see that certain fly aircraft
passing flying around conflict zones. If
you if you actually see that the their
route, you will see that they will
switch on and switch off transponders
from time to time and you can't really
see which which which part of the world
they flew over and where they came from.
Sometimes
you will sometimes see drones that
inadvertently leave the transponders on
drones as in military drones and then
they switch them off. You see all this
stuff happening. So even ships do that
of course. But why did a Pakistani ship
do this? Did they actually do it? I have
no idea sir. I can't say. I have not
seen this personally so I can't give you
an answer.
WBKT says many people are discussing the
possibility of Hamas Hbullah and the
company shifting to the UK after Iran
the war ends and establishing
Londonistan as their new headquarters
is very possible. Yes, is very pos
possible. London is already London
Londonistan they have a Pakistani mayor.
Um they have a Pakistani who foreign
minister defense minister something
who's that that new lady I forget her
name. She has got a foreign I mean I
mean Pakistani name right? Uh so
it's very possible Hamasah al-Qaeda ISIS
um whoever else they may shift their
headquarters to the UK. It's very
possible. I would not be surprised if
that happens.
Okay. Dave says Israel destroy Alaka for
the third temple. Possible. I would
rather not speculate about these
matters. I apologize but I my I don't
want to specul speculate about this. I
hope the Israel does know such thing but
who knows. So yeah I I I I can't answer
this question.
Anchul Gupta says USF15 intercepted by
Iranian hormones. Is it a new
development? I am not aware. Let me see
in
let us uh
let's see. F-15, you're saying?
Let's go to Google and see what's going
on in if if there's some news about
this.
F15 Hormuz.
What do we have
5 hours ago? Iran claims it it struck
enemy F-15 fighter jet intercepted near
Hormuz.
Uh F-15 fighter jet shot down near
Hormuz
3 hours ago. It Iran inter it claims it
intercepted struck American F-15 jet
near Hormos. Okay. So look
when Iran claims something these news
websites will say Iran claims when US
claims something they report it as a
fact.
I think you have to take Iranian claims
also seriously if you want to take
American claims seriously and Israeli
claims seriously.
So, it looks like Iran has taken down an
F-15 near Hormuz. They've taken on down
multiple F-15s near Kuwait, at least
three or four of those. They've taken
down at least at least one, if not two
F-35s, which is a major major major set
back to the US. They've destroyed at
least five aerial refueling oil tanker
uh aircraft of the US. Two in Iran,
Iraq, and three in Saudi Arabia.
So the Americans have lost multiple
aerial assets including fighter planes,
including stealth fighters, including
tankers, and this is an ongoing
situation. Looks like there's one more
that we will have to add to the lift
list. Okay.
WBKT says, "Your opinion on theories
about greater Israel and the decline of
the US." The US is now visibly showing
signs of decline because it's losing
it's right now in the process of losing
its power projection capabilities in
West Asia because most of its bases
military bases in the region have either
been severely degraded or entirely
destroyed. A clear decline this is the
beginning of the visible decline of the
US. But it doesn't mean the US is no
longer a superpower. It means it's it's
a somewhat diminished superpower now.
So that's not a theory, it's a fact.
Greater Israel, I have no idea. Some
people claim that there's this uh Israel
Israeli aspiration of creating a greater
Israel which encompasses larger areas of
West Asia. I don't know about that.
Yeah, I I don't know.
There's no evidence that Israel intends
to do do this. But if a theory is so
persistent, maybe there is potentially
some truth to that. But I can't
speculate.
Kakashi says if India becomes a vasal
instant soft power boost like Japan and
Korea. Yes, you may get some soft power
boost or not. See Pakistan is an
American vasal. Do you see any Pakistani
soft power boost? Ask ask yourself this
question.
Pakistan is an American vasal today and
not today. It did not become a vasal
yesterday. It was it's been a vasal
since 2022. And it was an American vasal
from from 1980 all the way to 2012.
Did Pakistan get any soft power boost?
Ask yourself this question.
Bangladesh is an American wasal. They
did a regime change there in 2024.
Did does Bangladesh get any soft power
boost?
There's your answer.
Harshett Parihar says Joe Kent in an
interview also said that Kirk's assassin
was being investigated for foreign
connection and that it was stopped by
the FBI. Kirk was anti-Israel. Okay.
I've not seen this interview so I'm not
aware of this but um Okay.
All right. I I don't know but okay.
Interesting piece of information here.
WBKT says, "Have you returned from the
Jaipur dialogue summit for your opinion
on Ankita?" I don't give opinions. Oh,
first of all, yes, I did participate in
the Jaipur dialogue summit yesterday.
There was an there was one uh panel
discussion that was that I was part of.
It was about uh India's foreign policy
and how successful or not has it been in
this period of turmoil. So that was the
panel discussion I was I was I I
participated in yesterday, right? There
was yesterday my opinion on so somebody
or the other I don't express opinions
about people unless they are globally
relevant.
So I will be happy to give you my
opinion about Donald Trump about Mr.
Xiinping about Mr. Putin about Mr. Modi
about Mr. Elon Musk.
I'll be happy to give you my opinion
about um
um Steve Steve Jobs
uh Sam Alman Sundar Pichai
and so on.
I'll I'll talk about people who are
globally relevant.
If I talk about other people,
what is the difference between me and
some gossip monger?
So, um I shall refrain from, you know,
giving opinions about random people who
are not globally relevant. I'm not
trying to say that this person is a
random person and not important or
whatever. Maybe that person may be very
important for a large number of people.
But I will talk about people who are
globally relevant and who are going to
be remembered in history. Okay, that's
that's my policy. As a matter of policy,
I don't give opinions about other
people.
Nitesh Jooshi says, "Do you think deep
state put Trump on the chair to create
this chaos and the world considering the
conflicts he started with many countries
as he really didn't care about his
legacy cause number one from Dems was
capable of doing this because no one
from the Democrats were capable of doing
this.
I think the deep state which I am pretty
certain exists which is a group of
powerful people who run the who rule
large parts of the world including the
United States. I think the deep state or
the establishment they decided that
Trump is the right person for for this
time. They decided that Trump is the
right person to be the president of the
US at this point in time because he will
be the best person suited to effect the
changes in the world order that we would
like to have happen right now.
So that's why he was engineered into the
position of the 47th president of the
United States. I don't believe for one
second that the US is a free and fair
electoral democracy.
Trump himself claimed and still claims
that the 2020 election was stolen from
him
and
at least in that matter I agree with
him. I I am inclined to believe him that
the 2020 election was stolen from him.
So if this 2020 election was rigged then
maybe the 2024 election was al also
rigged in Trump's favor this time. And
you can see how different this Trump
presidency has presidency has been
compared to the previous Trump
presidency 2016 to 2020. From 2016 to
2020, Trump was able Trump was the
president of the US, but he was able to
achieve nothing that he wanted to
achieve. He had modest ambitions. He
wanted to put a wall between the US and
Mexico. That also he could not achieve.
The US establishment refused to
cooperate with him on anything.
and see the contrast with between that
and today's Trump. Today he's rampaging
across the world and upending the whole
world order, imposing tariffs
as per his whims and fancies and now uh
participating in in an Israeli led war.
So I think yes the deep state put Trump
in the hot seat to create to engineer
the chaos we are seeing in the world
right now. Kokashi says, "I keep saying
seeing Ibraim
reals." Excuse me. Give me a second.
Um, excuse me. Okay. Kakashi says, "I
keep seeing Ibrahimore
reels that he's bringing growth and
development to Burkina Faso and the
Sahel State Alliance. Is this true?"
I don't know. I have not been keeping an
too much of a close watch on what's
happening in the Sahil region. He's a
young man,
a man with military uh with a military
background. He clearly is a patriot. He
clearly wishes to decolonize his
country. He clearly wishes to be um to
to rid his country of the colonial and
neocolonial forces whether it is France,
whether it is the United States. Right?
And for that he has allied himself with
Russia
and he has visited Russia and he's been
greeted very warmly by the Russian
president Mr. Putin all of that and he
clearly wishes to serve his country and
bring prosperity. So that clearly is his
agenda. He seems like a young and honest
person.
Now how far is he succeeding or not? I
don't quite know cuz I a couple of years
ago I did make a few videos about
Burkina Faso and what's happening there.
But after that I have not kept a close
watch on what has happened since then.
So I don't know how far he has been
successful or not. Maybe it's time for
me to revisit that. As of now I don't
know. Yeah I hope he is succeeding in
his efforts and endeavors that that I
can tell you.
R. Rahun Rajger says why is China
not helping
North Korea to improve economically?
So the question is how bad of a state is
North Korea's economy in?
So the entire media that talks about
North Korea says that North Korea is
this extremely poor impoverished nation
where people starve, there's famine,
there's poverty, blah blah blah blah
blah.
How do you know this is not propaganda?
The media is the western media and the
Indian media simply regurgitates Western
propaganda.
You have people who go to North Korea
once in a while. I know personally some
people at least one person who has gone
to North Korea the other Abijah my
friend
um the thing is if you visit North Korea
um you can't go wherever you want you
have a chaperon
you have a a guide or a minder and uh
you don't really get to see the the
entire nation but is it really true that
North Korea is impoverished and so on
maybe it's not that important
impoverished. Maybe the people are in
okay shape
and maybe the leader of North Korea, Mr.
Kim Jong-un does not want any economic
assistance,
right? So if the nation doesn't want it,
if the leadership doesn't want it, then
why will China insist on helping you
out?
There's no need for that.
Goravnis says, "Our authenticity here in
this discussions may not be liked by
all. Do you get offers to amplify
amplify narratives of powerful people or
get pressure to do so?
Do I get offers to amplify narratives of
powerful whatever?
I have never got a direct offer to
amplify any narrative. Okay.
But u
I have been uh you could say contacted
by representatives of certain nations.
You could say just just you know you
could say feelers
not you know direct offer or any such
thing and I am pretty sure that anybody
who
watches me will know that I will not be
available to amplify the narrative or
the agenda of any nation apart from
India. Right. Um
so yeah I mean I have even I once went
to Hong Kong. It was an invitation from
well indirectly from the Chinese
government to participate in a two-day
um discuss discussion session. There
were representatives from India
representatives from the EU and Chinese
representatives. And this was done on
neutral territory in Hong Kong not in
mainland China. And I put forth India's
perspective the best the best I could
and this was held under Cham House rules
which means you can speak about what
happened but you can't name who was
there and I had agreed to that that's
why I have not spoken about it
uh but there was no financial incentive
what or whatever in that and I went
willingly there was no incentive of any
kind and u they did not
even try to hint at wanting me to
amplify any narrative right Uh and China
is not the only nation
but yeah um nobody has I would say dared
to give me a clear offer that yeah
please amplify our narratives because
they know that it's never going to work
with me pressure no pressure no pressure
and uh my discussions the way I discuss
things I'm sure a lot of nations don't
like me so I agree with you I agree with
you yeah but that's fine that's fine I
am not here to to put myself out there
as somebody who seeks employment or
seeks uh incentives. I am here I I don't
need anything from anybody. I'm here to
speak on behalf of my nation the way I
understand it and that's all.
Messi alien says
what if God which we can't even
comprehend really
is but even he is created by someone to
think that he is the God and doesn't
know about anything beyond him. Well,
you are not the first person to ask
yourself this question.
Okay? Our ancestors asked this question
several thousand years ago. Let me show
you.
Nasadia.
Okay. Let's see. Let's take a look at
what Wikipedia has to say about this.
Even though Wikipedia is not a reliable
source of information, but let's see
what it has to say about the Nasad
Sutta. The Nasad Sutta
also known as the hymn of creation is
the 129th hymn of the 10th mundal of the
rigida. It is concerned with cosmology
and the origin of the universe. Okay. So
what's it say?
Okay. Let's read the whole thing. This
is one of the translations into English
by uh Al Basham.
good scholar, very good scholar, a
scholar I respect. So what did it say?
Of course, he was the mentor of Roma
Tapar, which is a different story. But
okay, let's read this.
Um or do we have a different version?
Okay. Okay. Let's reread this one.
Kramer Christian.
Uh
okay. See there was neither
non-existence nor existence then neither
the realm of space nor the sky which is
beyond what stirred where in whose
protection there was neither death nor
immortality then no distinguishing sign
of day or nor of night that one breathed
windless by its own own impulse other
than that there was nothing beyond
darkness there was at First by darkness
hidden without distinctive marks. This
all was water. That which by becoming by
the void was covered. That one by force
of heat came into being. Who really
knows? Who will here proclaim it? Whence
was it produced? Whence is this
creation? The gods came afterwards with
the creation of this universe.
Who then knows from where it has arisen?
Whether God's will created it or whether
he was mute, perhaps it formed itself or
perhaps it did not. The supreme Brahman
of the world, all pervasive and all
knowing, he indeed knows. If not, no one
knows.
So you can see the question it is asking
the the nasa is where did the unifor
universe come from? The gods that we
worship, they came into existence with
the creation of the universe. But who
created them?
Who created them?
Who is the creator?
What is the nature of the creator? Does
the creator know or the does the creator
himself don't know? Does not know? So
essentially, it's a deeply skeptical
worldview. It's a very skeptical
questioning of the existence of the
universe, of the birth of the universe.
It's a deeply philosophical
introspective and skeptical
introspection
of where did the universe come from? Who
created it? Can we ever know? It's
pretty agnostic.
This is the oldest text in in human in
human existence that we know of. This is
the oldest and most sacred text of
Hinduism.
And it it it essentially expresses a
very deeply agnostic and skeptical view
of the of the origin of the universe. It
says we may never know about it. Other
religious books they say this is exactly
how the universe was created.
Right?
Whether it's Islam, Christianity or
whatever, whatever, whatever. But in
Hinduism, it's like we have no idea. We
may never know. Even the gods don't
know.
So you're not the first person to ask
this question. Our ancestors asked this
questions thousands of years ago.
Okay. WBKT says why TFR of Thailand,
South Korea is so low US hand. Look, I
don't know about Thailand what the TFR
is, but South Korea it's very low
because of the nature of the society
about the extremely hardworking nature
of society.
Um,
essentially nobody has has the time to
procreate. Everyone's just too exhausted
from working.
Right? Similarly with with Japan I'm not
sure about Thailand but
see South Korea and Japan are both US
facad so clearly there's a US hand in
all of this at least in South Korea and
Japan. Uh Thailand I don't know I have
not looked into it so I can't say
Sergeant Skylan says can we ever be
energy and minerals independent?
I'll tell you what, India has the
world's largest reserves of rare earth
minerals, rare earth elements, way
bigger than China or anybody else. India
has the largest reserves of the rare
earths. Yet, China controls 95% of the
global output.
Once we operationalize the production,
the extraction, refining, all of that of
the rare earths, we're going to be super
minerals independent, especially in rare
earths. When it comes to other minerals,
I'm sure we pretty much have all the
minerals in our gigantic land mass
and our
offshore continental shelf and all that.
So, we'll definitely be minerals
independent.
Uranium may be not, but thorium. Haha.
We have at least a quarter of the global
thorium resources reserves. When it
comes to energy,
well,
we are currently the government of India
is currently beginning the process of
looking for oil and gas offshore in the
Andaman Sea region, right?
And uh that process is beginning slowly
slowly
it'll go on. I'm sure we will find
something gigantic there too because
that region is known to have huge res
reserves of oil and gas. The question is
why did this process not start in 2014
when the government came to power that's
the only thing that disappoints me. I
think once we find
see the Indian um territorial waters in
exclusive economic zone are gigantic
huge
and the Indian land mass is enormous.
If we seriously look in the right
places, we'll find
huge reserves
of oil and gas and whatever else. We we
will be eventually energy independent as
well. It's just a matter of time and the
sooner the better, I would say. Yeah.
So, we need to be a little more
proactive in these matters.
Okay. Chand Batya says, "Many Israeli
analysts say after Iran it's Turkey. Why
since 1948 Syria, Lebanon, Libya, Egypt,
Iraq, now Iran, next Turkeykey's target,
what's the main end objective? Look, for
every nation that is a proactive and
ambitious nation, they want to pacify
the entire region and be the sole large
sole major power in the region. That's
what the US has done in the Americas,
right? The US has done exactly this in
the Americas. They have vasalized and
pacified every single nation in northern
in North America in Central America and
South America.
Only Cuba is left and it's a matter of
time before they take out Cuba. When it
comes to Western Europe, they have
pacified and vasalized every nation in
Western Europe. And Israel is trying to
do do the same thing in its own region.
The end objective is to be the supreme
most powerful country in the region.
That's the end objective. Is that uh is
that is that something that's bad? I
don't think it's necessarily a bad
thing. I think India should do the same
thing in its region. Yeah.
Ravite says, "Hypothetically, if the use
US loses the war, Iran also takes heavy
damage and Israel has no adversaries in
the region. What would or might be
Israel's next step? Expansion and
control the region." So hypothetically
the US loses this war and Iran also
takes heavy damage which is which it is
taking. So let's say hypothetically in 6
months time the US limps out of this
region. It has lost the war or it has
not achieved its objectives. Iran's
regime still stands. It is still strong.
The people have rallied around the flag
and Israel, Iran is still fighting and
still hitting out and and and inflicting
uh damage on its uh adversaries.
If that happens and the US leaves the
war, what happens?
Will we have a situation where Israel
has no adversaries in the region? No.
Iran will still be an adversary. And if
Iran survives the next 6 months, I
assure you that if Iran's nuclear
facilities are not destroyed, it will
acquire nuclear weapons.
Then it's not the case that Israel has
no adversaries in the region.
You have a case where Israel has a peer
adversary nuclear armed rival in the
region. The next step, there's no next
step. You keep quiet and sit down.
That's all you do.
Right? So, Israel doesn't want the
situation to arise. That's why they are
they they somehow or the other they want
to defeat Iran comprehensively and end
the regime and ensure that Israel that
Iran has no it's it's its nuclear uh
program is permanently destroyed. That
is Israel's objective. Will they achieve
it or not? It's a huge question mark.
I think uh the chances are that they
will not achieve this. But let's see how
it goes. Okay. Nitin says, "Can we see
AI robotic soldiers used in a war in the
future? Maybe in 10 years you will see
that maybe even in 5 years." Even now
the Chinese have these robotic dog
soldiers that they can deploy in in in
battle, right?
They even have humanoid robots that can
do kung fu and whatnot. So I think it's
a matter of time 5 10 years maximum
before which you will see by by which
time you will see robotic soldiers used
in wars.
Okay.
Ishika
Vanigra
Ishika Vanigra says G Sri Lankan here
explain what happened Iris Dana. Okay.
Uh the Iranian uh warship Dana what
happened to it? So this Iranian warship
was it participated in a multinational
naval exercise in India.
Was it Kochi? Was it Was it Was it
Vishaka? It was on the east coast of
India. Okay.
And the sailors they participated in a
parade in front of the Indian president
and other nations also participated in
this. The United States was also invited
for this naval exercise. They had agreed
to participate but they pulled out at
the last moment essentially.
So the Iranian you know vessel came to
India. the sailors, the naval officers,
they participated in all the activities
and then eventually um the ship decided
to return home and by the time the war
had already started in uh by the time
Israel and the US had already attacked
Iran and the war was ongoing.
So from what I know, the ship went
south. Okay, let's let's pull out the
maps of our region. Let's pull out the
map of our region and let's try and
orient ourselves based on the map. So,
so the ship takes off from the east
coast of India whether it's Vishaka
Patnam or uh whether it's
can't be Kochi. Kochi is west coast. So
somewhere on the east coast of India it
takes off and it its objective is to go
back home to Iran. So it goes down
south. You can't obviously pass through
the Balk State straight because it's too
shallow. So, it has to go south of Sri
Lanka. And then from what I hear, the
Iranian ship requested the Sri Lankan
authorities to allow it to dock in Gal.
I don't know how to pronounce Gal. Is it
Gal? Is it Gal? I don't know. Gal,
whatever. So, they wanted to dock in
Gal.
But uh the Sri Lankan decision to to
accept or deny this request, it was
delayed and the Iranian ship was waiting
for like 8 10 hours or something
apparently for permission from Sri
Lanka. So they waited and waited and
waited and then an American submarine
came and torpedoed the Iranian warship
south of the south coast of Sri Lanka.
And uh
President Trump of the US said that uh
they they had the choice of either
having the Iranians surrender or just
destroying the Iranian ship. And they
decided to shoot down to torpedo and
destroy the ship because that's more
fun.
and
and after shooting the after destroying
the ship you the sailors were in water
and they started drowning and they
drowned and the Americans just watched
and I think the Sri Lankan Navy then
came into came into the picture and they
tried to rescue as many people as
possible. I'm not sure how many uh
Iranian sailors were rescued uh but they
tried. So that's what I know of the
situation. There was another warship of
Iran which also was in the region and
then they were given permission by India
to dock at Kochi over. So that ship is
still uh docked in India. I'm not sure
if the sailors have been repatriated or
not but they were housed in uh Indian
Navy quarters. So that is what I know of
the situation and it's very unfortunate
that this happened.
Rohan BD says, "Did India seek Russian
assistance in developing its nuclear
program? If yes, then why did Russia not
help? If no, why did we not reach out to
Russia?"
I'm not sure. I don't know whether India
took any Russian assistance in
developing the nuclear program. I think
there was some French or Canadian
involvement in the very beginning like
in the 1950s or something.
I don't remember exactly what the story
is like. U
what I do know is that India is the only
nation to develop a nuclear weapon
entirely independently apart from the
US. All other nations got some
assistance or the other from existing
nuclear powers. So apart from the US
which developed the nuclear weapon
entirely independently Manhattan project
1940s apart from the US India is the
only nation to independently develop a
nuclear weapons program. And obviously
India also has a civilian nuclear energy
program. So from what I vaguely remember
there was some French and or Canadian
assistance initially maybe a little bit
of US involvement to some extent perhaps
little bit. I'm not sure about Russia
but I do know that India operates the
INS Chakra which is an Akula class
nuclear submarine which is manufactured
by Russia and we typically lease out
these submarines on 10-year leases and
India is the only nation to whom Russia
leases its nuclear submarines. We also
know that the Indian um nuclear
submarine program has benefited from
Russian technical knowhow and assistance
especially the miniaturization of
nuclear reactors. Once again this sort
of assistance no nation offers you but
Russia has offered it to India. So
that's what I know. How to what extent
have they helped us and all I don't know
the specifics because this is all
classified. But yes so uh when it comes
to the initial phases of the Indian
nuclear program in the 1950s or wherever
or 60s um I'm not very clear about the
details of that.
Pratip Kumar Roy says did you watch
Dunda 2? Rasputin scene is one of my
favorites. Well I haven't seen it yet. I
look forward to seeing it sometime this
coming week. Hopefully by the time the
weekend comes hopefully I will have
watched it but I haven't seen it yet.
But I'm very eager to watch it. I met a
couple of people today who have both
multiple people today who have both who
have all watched it and they're all you
know u full of praise for the movie.
Apparently it's almost four hours long
which is like wow. But okay, we'll see.
Okay, fast snail. Love this fast snail.
Okay. Is Tulsi Kabad's statement on
Pakistan being most dangerous nuclear
nation a subtle way of conveying that
Iran was never a threat to the west?
That's a good question.
Um,
it's possible.
That's possible. Yeah.
I don't think Tuligabad is a big fan of
Trump's policies.
I'm not entirely sure why Trump has
appointed Tulsi Gabbad to to the
position of the director of the National
Intelligence Agency, but she's in charge
of that and she's a very competent
person. She's a um you know armed forces
veteran. She has served on multiple
tours tours of duty of combat and uh
she's a person of high integrity clearly
and clearly she her loyalty is to her
nation and not to a specific president
or regime which is how it should be
and I'm not sure based on all the
statements she has made she has been she
has testified in front of various uh
committees and so on in the past couple
of weeks two three weeks
and she has been very clear that Iran is
not really a threat right to the US.
It's not really posed a clear and
present danger or threat to the US.
Um so her statement about Pakistan being
the most dangerous nuclear nation could
have been a subtle way of conveying that
Iran was never a threat to the west.
Yeah, it it could be. Yes.
Okay. Aman Singh says many people in
India think you're a Russian spy. Well,
see there is no der of low IQ people in
India and thankfully that's not the kind
of people you you have who watch this
channel. On this channel we have people
of higher standards and higher caliber
and higher IQs. This channel is not for
everybody. There is no shortage of low
IQ people in in India. So that's fine. I
serve my nation. I will never ever serve
any other nation's interests or agendas.
Okay. And if I based on my
experience,
my learning, my analysis,
I feel that the that Russia is a better
strategic partner for India compared to
China or the US or whoever else. That
doesn't make me a Russian spy. Okay?
That that makes me an honest
communicator of what our actual national
interests are. And if somebody doesn't
have the intellectual bandwidth to
comprehend
what I am communicating,
well then they should well that's okay.
There's no shortage of such people.
Okay.
Vive Singh says
just heard the news that Russia has sent
4 S400 to Iran via an antonov 124 cargo
plane courtesy of recent attacks from
the US and Israel. new direction. Let's
quickly take a look at that. Very
interesting if uh this has actually
eventuated.
Okay, let's see.
Iran S400.
Let's see. Reports from late 25 indicate
Russia has delivered and deployed the
advanced S400 Triumph air defense system
to Iran to bolster its air defense
against potential US and Israeli
threats. These systems we which we know
have 400 km range were likely deployed
near Isfan to protect nuclear and
military sites.
Okay.
Um
so uh that's doesn't seem to be
new a new development.
Um
I don't know there there's multiple
perspectives that I'm seeing over here.
Some are saying that it's useless. Some
are saying it's very good. Some are
saying that the Americans have I don't
know. The missile just proved itself in
Iran. Let's see.
Go away. Um the missile which missile
the missile just proved itself in Iran.
The US This is a totally different story
clearly. Okay. Okay. So, I'll not go and
dig through all this news, but uh
okay, it looks like this happened in
2025, not recently.
But if Iran has that, well, it's a
valuable asset to have. The S400 did
prove its worth during Operation
Synindur.
And uh if used appropriately, I'm sure
it will do a great job for Iran as well.
Okay. Noob chess life says I am 35 in a
nontech government job I love physics I
have done a bachelor of engineering I
want to do IPHD what's an IPD at IISC
etc is it a good idea at this age what
job could I do after PhD at 40s first of
all let's me understand what is an IPD
what's an IPD
I PhD D.
Okay. Integrated PhD program. IPD.
Um, okay. IC, right? Okay.
What's an IPD?
Integrated PhD MTech research and PhD.
So, you get a master's degree and a PhD
as part of the of a package deal. Uh,
essentially that's an IPD. Okay. See,
okay. These are new new things.
Uh I understand PhD, I understand
master's degree, but now they are
packaging it together.
In the past, you could do a a PhD
straight after a bachelor's degree.
That's also okay. Anyway, so uh you're
35, you're in a non- tech government
job, you love physics, you've done a
bachelor of engineering, you want to do
an IPD, integrated PhD, which means a
masters and a PhD altogether in let's
say 5 years or so. Should take about 5
years hopefully. Uh if it takes six,
seven years, it's a little too long. So,
is it a good idea at this age? What job
could I do after PhD at the in my 40s?
Um, is it a good idea at this age?
I I don't know if it's a good idea at
this age.
What? First, the real relevant question
is if you have a PhD, what job could you
get from that? Well, it depends. If it's
a PhD in physics, what branch of physics
is it?
If it is mathematical physics, you will
get a certain kind of certain kind of
kinds of jobs. If it is in theoretical
physics, the job opportunities dwindle
very badly because theoretical physics
is all theoretical. You can get a
professor job, teacher job, whatever. If
you have a PhD in electrical engineering
or or
nuclear physics, if you have a PhD in
nuclear physics, for example, you could
get a job in BC.
um something like that. So typically if
you have a physics PhD, you don't have
too many job opportunities. You see
um
especially job opportunities that are in
the domain of physics. If you have PhD
in physics, you can get a job in other
other disciplines. You can get a job in
IT, I suppose. You can get a job in uh
quantitative finance modeling or
whatever. But in physics, there are very
few physics jobs in India unfortunately.
Right? So I'm not sure if it's a very
good idea doing your physics PhD. If you
want to have a job in India at any age,
if you want to have a job outside of
India, in the west or whatever, a
physics PhD can give you lots of
opportunities. Inside India, I'm not
sure. So I would say that if you love
physics and you want to do a PhD then
it's perfectly fine to pursue a PhD for
your own satisfaction for your own um
you know to to to
because you're doing it for the love of
physics but I'm not sure what job
opportunities it will give you because
there are few jobs for which there is a
tremendous amount of competition.
So um that is my honest uh answer to
you. If you have a good job that that
pays you well I would say stick to it.
If you have free time then do your job
plus do the PhD if it is at all
possible.
But if you spend 5 years getting a PhD
and then there is no clear job
opportunity. I think it will be a little
dangerous
from you know a salary and and and
income perspective. So I would say
approach this very carefully. Don't give
up the existing job you have before
doing your complete research and due
diligence about what opportunities
exists for you if you get yourself a
PhD.
Okay. I think the road could be a little
difficult and tricky if you leave your
job spend 5 years doing a PhD whatever
and then what do you do?
Let's say you want to become a college
teacher or university teacher or
professor or something. There's a
tremendous amount of competition for
these jobs.
And when it comes to research uh jobs,
I'm not sure what research jobs have in
India. So be careful, okay? Do your full
due diligence.
Godliness says US with its full might
has the capabilities to flatten Iran,
but the price will be to abandon all
Middle Eastern allies and get the tag of
Naranhar. The US may not pay this price,
but Israel can surely do. Does Israel
have the capability to flatten Iran?
Does even the US have the capability to
flatten Iran? It can cause immense
damage. It can do carpet bombing of
Iran. Sure, it can flatten cities.
But the majority of the population of
Iran is not in the big cities. It's in
the countryside. It's in the towns and
villages. And if they see that the
Americans are starting a campaign of
carpet bombing cities, they're going to
disperse and move to the mountain side.
And then what does the US do? You can't
carpet bomb mountains,
right? And if the Americans start a
carpet bombing campaign, the Iranians
will will essentially flatten the Middle
East
and those urban centers and cities in
the Middle East in the Gulf nations,
right? In retaliation.
So even if the US does this, it's not
going to achieve the objectives they
want to achieve. Israel doesn't even
have the capabilities that the US has.
So the US can act act as an extension of
Israel as a Israeli
asset and do what Israel wants it to do
and still they won't achieve the
objectives. The Americans can flatten
half the cities in Iran and still not
win the war.
Right? That's the problem they are
facing because the Iranians are willing
to fight to the last man. Maybe the last
woman. Who knows?
Kakashi says the 1991 fall of Soviet
Union leading to India's liberalization
out of necessity compromised sovereignty
unlike China which planned to transition
better and not penetrated. Absolutely.
Absolutely.
India had to liberalize out of
necessity. India liberalized and opened
up its markets as per the directions of
the IMF and World Bank.
We did not want our our leaders did not
want to do it. They had no choice but to
do it. So the World Bank, IMF, whoever
it was, they told India how to do they
said we will give you money but we will
decide how you use the money and you
have to open yourselves up and you to
allow us to penetrate you and compromise
you.
That's what happened in 199192.
India was penetrated. India got
compromised
more and more deep deeper over time.
China planned its transition entirely
independently in in a sovereign fashion.
China decided how it will transition
from a closed economy to a capitalist
planned capitalist economy. The Chinese
were fully in control of the destiny. In
India, we allowed the west to control
our destiny and the direction our
economy will take. Absolutely correct. I
agree with you.
Sachdev Satijit says, "Is it true that a
civilization must expand to survive?"
Not necessarily. A civilization must
ensure that it is not defeated by
anybody else in order to survive. As
long as it's able to even defensively
ensure its its its its uh safety and
security and prosperity, it will
survive.
Yeah. So, it's not necessary that you
have to expand to survive.
Anoj says Israel wants GCC countries to
also get into the war against Iran
which will devastate them and later they
expand border to make greater Israel.
What's your take
from a logical perspective? it, you
know, it's beneficial for Israel if the
Gulf nations, GCC nations
are forced into this war
because then you have multiple vectors
of attack against Iran, right? Uh so
yeah, it's it's beneficial for Israel if
the whole region gets involved in in in
the war against one enemy, one target
which is Iran.
Uh but this this will obviously
devastate the GCC nations. The GCC
nations are sparssely populated. They've
got these small, you know, just a few
cities
and just very simple economies that are
basically based on oil. In the UAE, you
have Dubai which is not oil- based
economy, but it's a different model
which is in under under tremendous
stress right now. Um, so if the Gulf
nations are devastated
and incapable of of defending themselves
in the future, who knows? Like you're
saying, maybe Israel may even be tempted
to expand its border. Who knows? That's
possible. So overall, strategically, it
makes sense from the perspective of the
logic of strategy.
Hyphen says, "What happens if Israel
escalates faster than the US wants?"
Has Trump trapped himself in this
considering how unpredictable Israel
could get?
Has Trump trapped himself in this? Yes.
And Israel is making it a point to
escalate beyond what the Americans
expect,
right?
Um who hit the Paris gas field? Was it
the Americans or the Israelis?
Big question, right? Um so the question
is what happens if Israel keeps
escalating or escalates faster than the
US wants? What will the US do then? Will
they say okay we will no longer
participate in the war? No.
They somehow seem to be duty bound
to protect Israel no matter what
happens. So if Israel keeps escalating,
the US has to keep keep up with Israel.
Trump is trapped in this. There is no
way out for Trump from this.
So the the Israelis will take this war
as far as they want and the US has no
choice it looks like but to
stay the course with Israel and ensure
that you know they keep on protecting
Israel.
That seems to be the case.
Godliness says can India afford two
nuclear moola regimes Pakistan and Ian
in its neighborhood knowing their
theology and life though thought is very
suicidal. Please understand one thing
about Iran. Iran is not a bunch of crazy
lunatics.
Iran's politicians are way more educated
than your average Indian politician.
And Iran is not a suicidal nation that
wants to die and kill everybody. Iran
wants to be left alone, left in peace.
They want to live their life their way.
According to Sharia allo, they allow
their women to get education. They allow
their women to get PhDs. But they have
to wear burkas. That is the way of life
they have chosen for themselves. That's
the way of life the moolas have chosen
for their people. But they are not a
bunch of crazy lunatics. And if they are
a nuclear armed nation, they will
actually counterbalance Pakistan.
Okay?
Then Iran has no enemy with India.
Understand that
actually it will be good for India if
Pakistan a nuclear Pakistan is
counterbalanced by a nuclear Iran. Iran
is no friend of Pakistan. Do you not
understand this? Indians only see things
in black and white from a religious
perspective.
Please grow up a little and and
acquire a little bit of maturity. Please
I know you are watching other YouTube
channels and I know I know what they're
telling you.
My perspective is different. India has
no initiative with Iran. Iran has no en
enmity with India.
India and Iran are potentially can
potentially be good friends if external
constraints are removed from the region.
So I don't see nuclear Iran being a
problem for India. It's more of a
problem for Pakistan. Then Pakistan
cannot be used as a counterbalance for
India because they to counterbalance
Iran. So it's actually a disaster for
the US and for Israel and for Pakistan.
If Iran becomes a nuclear power, it's
not a disaster for India.
Pratep Kumar Roy says, "I just found out
that many so-called Hindu organizations
like whatever
and a few others worship Jesus besides
other Hindu gods." Shocking.
Okay, I am not aware of any of these
things. So, I shall uh refrain from
commenting. I am not aware of this.
Um,
okay. If if it is true, it is indeed
shocking.
So, I personally don't
know about these organizations and what
they do. Uh,
okay. I am I'm personally feeling a
sense of shock right now if if this is
true.
Sorab says, "What can India do to keep
the Iranian regime in power?" Nothing.
Nothing.
It all depends on Iran. There's nothing
India can do about this.
India is like whatever happens we will
try and make the best of it.
India India is not a participant in this
and I think it's best for India to stay
out of this matter. Whoever wins we will
work with them. That's how it is and
we'll make sure we don't antagonize any
anybody. India is is say India's
objectives are to stay out of any
military confrontation for the next 10
20 years. right? So that we grow our
economy, we give our people a better
lifestyle and so on. That seems to be
the agenda of you know India and that
makes sense. You know I've said this for
a long time India makes needs to make
sure the next 10 20 years it stays out
of any major military confrontation or
if a military confrontation happens
minimize it to the shortest possible
time duration and don't get involved in
somebody else's war. So what can India
do? India should stay out of this matter
and there's not much India can do
anyway. So yeah,
she says, "Since Europe is a vasal of
the US, how come Trump is not able to h
arm twist NATO to join the war to open
the straits? How is Europe able to say
no?"
Um, that's a good question. How is
Europe able to say no? And why is Trump
not able to arm twist NATO to join the
war?
Well, how do you arm twist someone? You
threaten consequences.
That's how you arm twist someone. You
threaten very real consequences.
So for example
um with India, Trump has been imposing
tariffs.
India wants its economy to keep growing
and India thinks that for our economy to
keep growing we have we need to have
access to the US market. And then Trump
says I'm going to impose these many
tariffs on you 50% tariffs. That hurts
our economy. So that's real consequences
and real pain he imposed on India.
That's why India had to agree to so so
and so trade deal which may not be the
best trade deal for us. So that is how
how you arm twist somebody
right
now when it comes to Europe
he Trump has already armwisted Europe
into giving so many concessions. Europe
has committed that by 2030 they will
double the amount of money they are
spending on NATO.
He they have agreed to all his demands.
They have agreed to keep funding Ukraine
in the Ukraine in the war against
Russia. They have agreed to keep
supplying Ukraine with all their arms,
ammunition, tanks, whatever else. What
more can Europe do for the US?
And if they say no, what more pain can
Trump impose on them? He has deprived
them, the US has deprived Europe, Europe
of the cheap Russian gas they were
buying by destroying Nordstream too. I
mean, what more pain can they impose in
Europe? Will they spend send even more
illegal immigrants into Europe? Is it
even possible to have so many people
coming into Europe every year? So, I
don't think there's any more pain Trump
can impose on Europe. He's already used
all the pain, all the arm twisting he
can do. And I think even he has reached
his limit of of how much pain he can uh
impose on Europe and how much you can
twist their arms. Once your arms are
twisted out of out of the out of your
socket, how much more can you twist it?
I suppose. So that's why Europe is
telling Trump to go
go take a hike.
We are done with you. Yeah. And
obviously NATO is relevant in in Western
Europe. Europe will say to Trump, you
are you people are claiming that Russia
is the biggest boogeyman in the region.
So we need to focus on Russia and we
will not have the time or the energy or
the resources to spend on West Asia. You
deal with it. You started the war. You
you you finish it. And there's not much
more Trump can do about this. So that's
why
H Shubber Shukla says your thoughts on
Annie Bessent how overnight success I
have no idea of Annie Bessent I know
that she exists some Irish lady or
whatever who was apparently a freedom
fighter I don't know anything about her
background her history anything
whatsoever so I have no idea about her
so that's why I have no thoughts on her
I know there's a place in Chennai called
Basagar I once stayed there a few days
long long time ago but beside that I
have no idea about her life her history
or contributions or not to India
whatever so can't say
Pratip Kumar Roy says your views on IC
versus CBS state versus state boards I
have no idea whatsoever I have an IC
background I think it's better than the
rest international boards excluded I am
not
somebody who studies the different uh
nuances between the various boards in
India I have no idea whatsoever I can
tell you from a um you know 3000 30,000
ft perspective that everything is
garbage. Now what is the quality of this
gar garbage versus that garbage? I have
no idea. These are different kinds of
garbage.
I know the overall the entire Indian
education system is trash. It is painful
and a waste of time for students no
matter which board you go into.
Okay. So if you ask me to differentiate
between
sample A, sample B and sample C of
garbage, I'm sure there are nuances and
differences, but I don't know what they
are. I'm not interested in finding out.
So I don't know what the differences are
and uh that's why it doesn't matter to
me what the differences are.
Uh D, thank you very much.
Pratepit Pumar Roy says, "Recently the
the foolish Japanese prime minister
visited nuclear bomber graveside along
with Trump paying respects. Are they
idiots?" So that's what I discussed in
the beginning of a today's live stream.
Where is it? Give me a second.
Um
here,
let me put this on the screen.
Uh so this is uh a tweet by somebody on
Twitter.
It says that the foolish prime minister
of Japan has gone and play and paid
tribute to the pilot who dropped the
atomic bomb on Japan and this is from
from yesterday the tweet.
So this is what I wrote in response. I
said it's it's good
to periodically humiliate themselves
before the overlord.
It's it's terrible.
It's it's unfortunate. Uh I don't think
it's because the prime minister of
Japan, Madame Sai Takayichi, is a
foolish person. It's because she has no
choice. It's because the United States
is the overlord of Japan. Okay? And they
require their vasals to periodically
humiliate themselves. This is what you
get when you are a vasal state.
You have to periodically abase yourself
and humiliate yourself to please the
please the overlord. That's the
unfortunate situation.
That's the perk of being a wasal.
So they're not idiots. They have no
choice. They have no choice. Hush Patel
says Trump's pledges to end the wars are
exactly like that friend who swears I'm
just 5 minutes away and then rolls up 3
hours later. The only difference, at
least the friend actually shows up.
That's it's a good way of putting it.
Yeah. At least the friend eventually
actually shows up 3 hours later. Trump
is like, I'm 5 minutes away. He's been
saying that for the past 3 weeks, right?
Yeah, you are absolutely right.
Right. Angle says, how do you measure
the greatness of a leader? Parameters.
Good question. How do you measure the
greatness of a leader?
You don't measure the greatness of a
leader from their words and from what
people say about them.
You measure the greatness of a leader
based on what they have what they tried
to achieve and to what extent they were
able to achieve that.
Okay.
Overall, what is the purpose of being a
leader?
What's the job of a leader?
What's the nature of leadership? The
true nature of leadership is service.
Leadership is actually service.
Service of whatever constituency you
serve. It can be 10 people. It can be 50
people. It can be a village. It can be a
municipal district. It can be a state.
It can be a nation. But it's always a
finite number of people that you serve.
So leadership is service. Leadership is
not having a loud voice or being 6 feet
tall or being aggressive.
Leadership is service. So how well were
you able to serve your people is the
only measure of the greatness or not of
a leader.
So the question is then what type of
service was the leader trying to provide
to the people?
So what are the different things that
they were trying to achieve? All leaders
are trying to achieve at least two three
different things. So then you measure
how much were they able to achieve or
not. Did they deliver on the promises or
on on their agendas? If yes, did they to
what extent did they succeed? 50%, 30%,
80%, 100% did they overachieve 200%. All
of that is how you measure the greatness
of a leader. A great leader
overachieves.
A good leader achieves or close to
achieves. A poor leader either
underachieves 20 30% instead of 100%. Or
lies to you.
Okay.
Current houses. When will the war be
over? Sovereignty index in a month
surely. I hope so. In a month shortly.
If the war is over in a month. When will
the war be over? I am not optimistic.
It's ending soon. I'll be very very
happy if it's over one month from today,
but I am a little skeptical about that.
So, if the war doesn't end in a month or
two, I'll have to put my sovereignty
index on out by that time.
Um, right angle says, "Will you consider
France as a shadow sovereign nation?" I
consider France to be a 66% sovereign
nation or maybe 50% sovereign nation.
I'll have to calculate exactly how
sovereign it is. It's not a shadow
sovereign nation. It's a quasi or
partially sovereign nation.
Abu Singh says Abai Singh says crowds
aligning perfectly for China. The hater
in me is in shambles. Is Trump a Chinese
asset? Is China successful in Taiwan? If
China is successful in Taiwan, are they
coming from for Andy Pradesh for
Arunachal Pradesh next? So the cards are
indeed aligning for China. The US
military capabilities are declining.
What do I mean by that? Their stockpiles
of essential critical arms, ammunition,
missiles, and so on, interceptors, etc.
are drastically low now because they've
used up so much of that in the last
three or so weeks against Iran and
achieved nothing.
Nothing politically. Tactical success,
yes, but political success, strategic
success, no.
The EU and NATO are critically short of
munitions
and the US even if it restarts and
kickstarts its its military industrial
complex it won't be able to start
producing things at scale for the next
two couple of years. They right now
produce maybe a 100 interceptor missiles
per year per year. That's a joke.
So all China has to do is to wait a few
more months for the war to go on and
then make its move on Taiwan when the US
is critically low even more than today
of critical supplies, missiles, arms,
ammunition, munitions, so on.
>> Yeah. And just apply the lessons of the
Iran war. China will succeed in that
case. Yeah. Um is Trump a Chinese asset?
No. Trump is just an idiot. Trump is is
a foolish egoistical person and maybe
he's somehow beholden to the nation of
Israel perhaps. Um yeah so if China is
successful in Taiwan will they come for
for Arunachal Pradesh next
Arunachal may be a totally different
kettle of fish compared to Taiwan and
Taiwan if they actually succeed in
Taiwan even if Taiwan is destroyed but
they take Taiwan it'll be a huge
achievement for them. Will they come for
Arunachal next? I think Arunachal will
not be that easy for them because India
has been preparing for a very long time
for such an eventuality. So maybe not.
Adit Chandra says Israeli billionaire
Miriam Aden has donated 250 million to
Trump's third term campaign. No wonder
he has to bow down to Israeli interests.
That may be one factor, but I'm sure
there are other factors as well
potentially. Not just somebody donated
this much money. Maybe there are other
factors. There are two kinds of
leverage. There is the carrot and
there's the stick. So what you're
showing talking about here is the
carrot. What could be the stick is the
question, right?
Okay. Dave says, "Wow, Israel army
shoulder batch has gr Israel map.
Greater Israel map." Really?
Really? Let's see. That's interesting.
That would be more interesting than um
that would be actually a little
you know um
let's see
Israel Army shoulder patch.
Israeli army grow shoulder patch. That
looks like a greater Israel region.
Definitely.
Definitely. It's way more than the what
what present day Israel is.
That's really interesting. Now, yeah,
greater Israel. Well, well, well. If
this is actually
the actual
shoulder patch of IDF soldiers,
it includes parts of Egypt, Sai, Egypt,
Saudi Arabia, Iraq, Syria, Lebanon.
Well, well, well. that kind of
substantiates
claims of Israel aiming for greater
Israel if that is indeed true. Very
interesting. Very interesting. Wow.
Indeed. Chage Lada has become a new
member. Thank you very much Chitage and
welcome to the channel's membership.
Thank you.
Right angle says why they target
nationalist business houses in India
like Vidanta, ADA, I Guptas who have
given a lot to India versus who
extracted and exported Indian wealth to
other nations like BA JJ and etc etc
etc.
Um
uh look first of all I am not agreeing
or disagreeing with who has extracted
and who has done whatever but generally
why do certain elements maybe it's media
maybe politics maybe whoever else why do
certain elements target nationalist
business houses
who are actually serving the nation and
doing something good for the nation why
would uh certain elements of media or
whoever do that typically because they
are aligned with with the agendas and
interests of other nations.
or they are aligned with the agendas and
interests of anti-India forces in that
case they would obviously target
nationalist business houses
okay I am not necessarily saying that I
agree with the lists or list of names
you've given out I'm not saying that but
as a matter of uh
a larger you know theoretical
perspective
yeah you would align
You would target nationalist business
houses if you are aligned with the
objectives and interests of anti-India
groups who whatever they are
2B by Iran to US Diego Garcia balls of
steel
coord uh two ballistic missiles Iran
says it wasn't us Iran says it wasn't us
so
uh Suman Vikant says one Iran connection
natural two Iran Houthi conction natural
three Iran Hamas connection more
connection more like geopolitical
alignment and Houthi don't work like
terrorism Hamas does what's your opinion
you see my enemies enemy is my friend
that's how it goes in geopolitics so the
US seeks to contain India what have they
done to contain India they have aligned
with Pakistan and used Pakistan and what
does Pakistan do to contain India and to
hurt India terrorism
so you
If if Iran is working with Hamas to
achieve its geopolitical objectives,
it's like the US working with Pakistan
to achieve its geopolitical
objectives. Right? When the US funds
finances Pakistani terrorism for
decades, we don't call the Americans as
a supporters of terrorism. Right? But if
Iran alliance with Hamas because Hamas
is anti-Israel, then the whole world
says Iran is terrorist.
Pakistan is a terrorist nation,
right? Hamas is a bunch of terrorists
and Hamas is anti-Israel.
I'm not saying that I that Hamas is not
a terrorist organization. They are a
bunch of terrorists. What they did in
October 2023 is the most inhuman,
brutal, ghastly thing one can imagine.
Very similar to what Pakistan has been
doing against India for decades.
Pakistan obviously has inflicted way
more pain on India than Hamas has on
Israel. But similar um proclivities,
right? So the US knows what Pakistan has
been doing. The US have been funding and
financing that.
But nobody accuses the US of uh being a
state sponsor of terrorism. So in the in
exactly the same way, you can't accuse
Iran of being a state sponsor of
terrorism. You can't.
So yes, Hamas is a terrorist
organization. No question. Um so it's
all about achieving your geopolitical
objectives by whatever means necessary
and I would assure you that Vishnuktank
would approve of this
right
Pa says please unlock a way through
which membership chats should also be
displayed here otherwise what is the use
of membership on your channel please sir
you can't do membership chat chats I am
not aware I've just turned on super
chats
I have to look into it. I was not aware
that members can't put out chats here.
And look, it's not necessary for you to
be a member to to purchase a member on
my channel.
Okay? I as such, I don't really give any
specific perks to members.
So, if if you feel that purchasing a
membership on this channel is not
worthwhile, then please don't purchase a
membership. I will not look at you any
differently because you you're not a
member. Right? So I don't know if
YouTube allows members
to display chats during a super chat
session. I'm not aware of how it works.
I've just turned on the super chat mode.
I don't think there's any special
membership chat mode or any such thing.
So in that case maybe you will feel that
membership is not a good idea. In which
case it's perfectly fine to not renew a
membership. It's perfectly fine. See, I
never ever promote my channel's
membership to anybody. People buy
memberships. I'm very grateful for that.
But I you will never see me advertising
and asking you to become members. Right?
If you become members, I am very
grateful. But if you don't become a
member, I'm not any less grateful for
your viewership. Please understand that.
All right? So, I don't know if it's
possible what you are asking me to do. I
understand why you asking. I'm not sure
if YouTube gives that option. Whatever
options are there, I've already turned
them on. So, I'll see if it's possible.
But if it's not possible, then I
apologize. Right.
Okay. Ankumar says, "Is Kiri Muk Rahu
the one who devours in everything the
personification of a black hole?" I I
don't know. I have no idea. Um yeah, I I
don't know. I don't I don't have the
answer to this question. Sorry.
Rohit says recently found out that India
provided $25 million of assistance to
Pakistan in 2010
but we are truly we were truly a
punching bank. This was just 2 years
after the Mumbai terror attacks. What?
Let me let me see.
Did India provide $25 million of
assistance to Pakistan in 2010?
What?
Oh god. Really?
Once again, let me just put this so that
I
Yes. In August 2010, the government of
India announced a total of $25 million
in aid to Pakistan to assist with
devastating floods. This consisted of an
initial $5 million offer later increased
by 20 million routed through the United
Nations to support flood flood relief
efforts.
Okay. So Pakistan was initially
reluctant hesitant to accept the aid for
India from India but later agreed to
receive it requesting that the funds be
routed via the United Nations.
What can I say? This is the behavior of
a nation that's run by a bunch of losers
clearly.
Okay. Muhit Raj Singh says there's many
claims that Kame is still alive because
like CIA Mossad KGB is also working and
it's in their benefit if Iran survives
and this war will continue. What are my
your thoughts? My thoughts Iran has
officially stated that that uh Mr. Kame
has been assassinated
now. So I'm going to go with the
official statements.
I don't have any ties with the with with
Mossad and RAW and CIA and God knows
what like many YouTubers allegedly have.
I have no ties with anybody.
Okay? My analysis, whatever I say is
based purely on information that's
available in the public domain. I don't
know any spies. I don't have connections
with Mossad or whatever. So my
perspective is I will go with Iran's
official statements. If they have said
he has been assassinated, that's what
I'll believe. And all these claims are
all empty speculation without any
factual basis of evidence. So that's it.
That's that's my views.
Goautam WHMA Goautam WHMA Dantaluri says
what's your opinion on Dr. APJ Kalam APJ
Abdul Kalam the missile man of India in
our missile development.
I think he was a brilliant engineer
right I am not sure that he personally
developed the missiles and built them
all but he clearly was in charge of the
program as the senior project manager
scientist engineer whatever it was. So
this this entire
uh development of certain specific
missiles initially of our missile
program it happened under his
supervision and guidance and for that we
have to be immensely grateful to the
great man right and not only that he was
a great inspiration for the young people
of India so I have the highest regard
for Dr. APdul Galab that's that's my
opinion on him
says how Jews became such a competent
force in the world isn't it a matter of
all thus their capabilities led to the
rise of anti-semitism how Jews why Jews
um yes Jews have are a very small
population there's a very small number
of Jews in the world and yet they are so
powerful so influential
they have the world's most powerful
nation at essentially their beck and All
it is it is clearly a matter of awe awe
inspiring incredible achievement isn't
it small group of people
and they have the US as their
unconditional ally the US is willing to
fight wars for them incredible
achievement you have to respect that no
question about that you have to respect
that
pratipar says can we use nuclearpowered
sentinel robots Google in the future
What's a sentinel? Okay, let's see.
Nuclearpowered
sentinel robots.
What is that? Nuclearpowered sentinel
robots are specialized autonomous
machines developed for designed for high
radiation hazardous environments
primarily for surveillance, inspection,
maintenance, and nuclear facilities.
While the sentinel aspect aspect refers
to monitoring, these robots are
increasingly using advanced AI and
radiation hardened materials to act as
autonomous guards and inspectors. What
how are they nuclearpowered?
Nuclearpowered.
Let's go deeper into this AI mode. How
are they nuclearpowered?
Real world D. Okay, most industrial
robots are battery powered but nuclear
powered typically refers to two things.
Okay, radioisotope thermmoelectric
generators
uh and nuclear facility maintenance.
How do you use a radioisotope
thermmoelectric generator to power a
robot
providing decades of power from decaying
plutonium?
Um that can provide heat. It can be a
heat source but can you turn that into
power? I suppose there must be some way
of turning that heat from radioactive
decay of plutonium into power. I suppose
it can be used in the future but uh I
haven't really looked into this and
looks like it's it's it's pos possible
to use radioisotope thermmoelectric
generators
possibly to power robots. I'll have to
think of how it you could do that
but maybe maybe it's possible. Yeah,
YT user 786s says, "Do you think a
country's army needs a huge number of
soldiers like India? Shouldn't we focus
on modern weapons? I've seen how
helpless soldiers are to tiny drone
bombs. In Russia Ukraine war, they use
fiber op fiber optic drones. Okay,
drones
in today's day and age in the context of
21st century warfare, you don't need
huge numbers of soldiers. It's always
good to have backup in reserves, you
know, but I don't think you need a
million soldier armies anymore,
but it always helps to have a backup.
So, let's say you going to press maybe a
100,000 soldiers into war, but there's
no harm in having a 1 million soldiers
as a backup.
But at the same time, we should very
much focus on modern weapons.
Absolutely. We should focus on the most
modern cuttingedge weapons in quantity
and with decent quality because quantity
always overwhelms quality. Quantity
always overlins quality. We've seen that
over and over again.
Um
yes. So we should certainly focus on
modern weapons. Absolutely. And since we
have such a huge population, there is no
harm in having more soldiers. As long as
it doesn't be it doesn't become a huge
drain on our u defense expenditure,
right? There has to be a balance. If you
have too many soldiers and they are
eating up all the salary and you not
able to invest that money into modern
weapons, then that's a problem. So there
has to be a balance and a trade-off
somewhere.
Ojas says does how does the US get to
dictate the terms in a deal? Through
through leverage because they can they
have the ability to inflict all kinds of
pain. That's why they get to dictate
their deals. That's how it goes.
Leverage.
Okay.
Oh
wig. Sorry. Ishika van says my name was
taken
my name was taken word from Sanskrit is
it hard it's an unusual name for for
those of us who are not used to sinali's
names so it's I ishika vanra clearly
Sanskrit origin name yes but it it's
it's not you know it's a little unusual
to those of us who are not accustomed to
the shinhali language right so for for
Me personally, I don't have too many
Selles friends. I hardly interact with
Selles people. So, Selles names are it
it takes a moment to to get it. You
know, it's Ishika Vanigara. Clearly,
it's a Sanskrit origin name and
initially it's hard, but once you get
it, you get it right. So, okay.
JRXna says, "If and when US hedgemony
ends, regardless of the results of the
Iran war, the empire is deteriorating.
What roles will Turkey, Japan, India,
EU, Taiwan, and Russia play in the new
world order?" Well, it all depends on in
what fashion and in what way does the US
hedgemony end. See, right now, we have a
certain global world order and it's all
underpinned by the US military might. If
the US hedgemony ends and their empire
declines, deteriorates or disintegrates,
then there's going to be a certain
period of time, maybe a decade, maybe
multiple decades of chaos where you're
going to have fragmentation. You're
going to have fragmented world orders,
fragmented local orders where local
hedgeimments will will rule the root in
localized regions. Right? So, it
depends. If it ends abruptly and there's
chaos in the world, then every little
nation will be a local hedgeim. So
Turkey will be the local hedgemon and
they'll terrorize neighboring nations.
They'll do that. Japan, it depends on
how it ends, how the US occupation ends.
Right now it's under US occupation. If
it ends and the Japanese population is
just tired and old, then I wonder what
happens to Japan. Will will the Chinese
take over or or will the Russians take
over or will Korea make a bow on them?
Right. India, it depends. EU will
fragment.
Why is the EU one block? It's because of
the US holding it together. The moment
US ends, the U EU will fragment
and they will all go back to their good
old ways of uh the European tribal wars.
Russia could be a major hummer if it if
it uh remains uh united. India depends
on the kind of leadership we have and so
on. So it it depends on so many
different factors. It's it's very hard
to foretell how it goes, right? It's
very hard to forail how it goes.
MK for MKkeshar says Jahin Jenji Iran
start
Iran a start of a new world order world
divided versus hormones. NATO versus
bricks, production versus consumption,
Muslims versus radical Muslims.
So the question is is is is this Iran
war the start of a new world order? Is
the world going to be divi divided? Suez
versus Hormuz.
It's not S versus Hormuz. You could even
see the blockade of the straight of
Babel Mandeb in the coming months, weeks
or months. If things escalate, Iran
could have the Houthis close the
straight of Babal Mande which will be a
major problem for the world including
for India. So Suez Hormos Yeah. NATO
versus bricks. BRICS is not a military
alliance. NATO is a military alliance.
Bricks is a coalition economic coalition
of nations and it's not a very strongly
bound coalition of nations. So you can't
really compare NATO with bricks.
Production consumption. Yeah, that we'll
see Muslims. I will not comment about
Muslims and all that. But yeah, we the
Iran war is the beginning of a new phase
of world history. We are not going to go
back to the old days of the pre-Iran war
era. Okay? It's going to be the world
has changed permanently now.
Now, supply chains are going to be
weaponized. GE geographic choke points
are going to be weaponized. Uh you're
going to have at least two parallel
systems in the world that will emerge
and so on. So, yeah, that's right.
Bureau TV, good to see you says
US said India is funding Ukraine war
through Russian oil purchases. Yet the
US itself is waging wars worldwide. Why
should India heed US concerns? Now what
can they even do?
The US is the world's most powerful
nation and as such they have the right
to be as hypocritical as they want.
Hypocrisy
is a privilege.
You can be hypocritical only if you're
powerful. You see India is not a
hypocritical nation because India is not
powerful or rel relatively way way less
powerful. So the US says India is
funding the Ukraine war because it
purchases Russian Russian oil but US
purchases purchases Russian uranium at
the same time. The EU purchases way more
Russian oil and gas than India but India
is allegedly funding the Russian oil
purchases. That's hypocrisy.
But it's the US that's initiating wars
worldwide and waging wars worldwide. The
question is why should India heed US
concerns now? These are not US concerns.
The US is trying to dictate terms to
India. Stop buying Russian oil. Stop
buying Venezuelan oil. Now you can start
buying Venezuelan oil. Venezuelan oil
again. Stop buying Iranian oil. Iranian
oil. Uh open up your economy to us.
Agree to a trade deal on our terms and
so on and so forth. The the dictats the
the the conditions are endless. The
demands are endless.
Why should India heed US concerns for
its own survival?
India is not
Iran.
India is not willing to take immense
damage to protect its sovereignty.
India may not even have the kind of
firepower that Iran has actually. And
India doesn't want to be in a war. India
wants to be on good good terms with the
US. India wants access to the US market
for its exports.
because of these things that we desire
and need and want. We have to heed
Indian American concerns.
That's what they can do. They can deny
India access to the US market. They can
deny India access to the swift system
which will cut off India from the global
economy. They have so many things they
can do to impose pain on India. They can
do endless things to India.
Yeah. That's why India has to heed US
concerns.
Okay. Pratip Kumar Roy says, "Your views
about the four Shankara Charara
positions." I
Yeah, no views. I haven't studied this
in detail so I can't say.
Adita Takar says, "Opinion on
competitive exams like NE TJ G." Look,
competitive exams are a good idea. Okay,
so I have no issue with competitive
exams. I have an issue with the garbage
rotten education system. I don't know
about NE but J is used to be a great
competitive exam. It it's a exam that
you need to be really good at physics
and whatever in order to pass J. So I
think that's that's not a bad idea. The
Chinese have competitive exams. Their
education system is way better than
ours, but they also have competitive
exams. The Americans have SATs and
whatnot. So competitive exams are
actually good.
They allow you what they do is that you
know you get a standardized
understanding of where you stand visav
everybody else your peers. So I think
competitive exams are not a bad idea but
the education system is is terrible.
Kakashi says good you speak
good you speak with all but JD gives
mental colonized vibes. Uh no comments.
No comments.
Mama bucket VFXs, I believe all races on
Earth have ET origin. Makes sense.
Who knows? Maybe it's true. Maybe we all
are descendants of aliens. No, who
knows? Who knows?
Kakashi says, "People think you are
Russian spy to spoil relations with the
West." Okay, let people think whatever
they want to think. That's fine.
Ishika says, "G explain next 10 years
India see and China see war how
countries act. India Southeast Asia and
China Southeast Asia or India sees China
Sea war
how country act
the next 10 years are extremely
unpredictable. Uh you know a lot will
depend on how the what kind of outcome
we're going to have of the Iran war.
Most likely the US and Israel will not
be able to achieve their objectives.
They will not be able to subjugate Iran.
They will not be even able to balconize
Iran at least for a few years. Iran will
be willing to fight with sticks and
stones if it comes to that. They will
not be able to take Iran. So they will
not most likely and see time is a big
factor in this war.
The longer there's a stalemate, the more
unpopular Trump gets at home and that
pressure is going to be devastating for
him. So it a lot will depend on what
happens in the Iran war. And if the Iran
war significantly depletes US stockpiles
of munitions, weapons, missiles, etc.
interceptors, then the Chinese will
perceive possibly it's the right time to
make a move on Taiwan and they will have
absorbed all the lessons of the Iran war
and the Chinese may have massive
stockpiles of drones and missiles. So
then they will be able to take Taiwan.
Maybe Taiwan will be burned to a crisp
but they will take the island and that
will also possibly have major effects on
Japan and South Korea because the
Americans will press Japan and South
Korea into action if China makes a move
on Taiwan. So just like the Iran the the
American and Israeli war against Iran
this devastating the whole Gulf region.
Similarly a Chinese war on Taiwan could
devastate the whole of this the eastern
Asian region.
Similarly,
and if that happens, the whole world is
in turmoil. It's in chaos. The global
economy economies will go down,
recession everywhere. So, it looks like
the next 10 years could be a period of
great chaos. I hope none of these things
happen. It looks like the future, the
next decade or so is going to be a time
of chaos possibly. I hope I'm entirely
wrong about this. I hope so.
M for MKkesh Kumar's MK for MKkesh Kumar
says Jahind sir Jahind US ultimatum is
park joining there's no ultimatum right
now but in the future maybe in the next
weeks or so the US may press China into
action in the war who knows we'll see
about that right now there is no
ultimatum that I know of Rohanir says
Maharasha government passed
anti-conversion law your views I don't
discuss internal politics I don't
discuss this I have no views about this
I don't even follow internal politics so
I I I have no views about this
Okay. Java bro says, "I am from Uttar
Pradesh. I want to marry a girl from the
northeast of India. On Reddit, I
discovered they have a lot of dislike
for North Indian people. Shall I be
hopeful?" 9 39 y
39 years old. Okay, listen. I don't
think there's a lot of dislike for North
Indian people or whatever in the
northeast. What you see online is not
necessarily a true representation of
what happens, what exactly exists in the
real world. what you see on on the
internet and on social media is very
polarized opinions.
I'm sure if you go to the northeast, you
will find that most people will welcome
you and be happy with you. And obviously
there's going to be some skepticism
because people don't understand other
parts of India very well. But as long as
you are a good husband and good
son-in-law, you'll I don't think
there'll be any issue. So I would say if
you are in love with this lady and you
want to marry her and she she feels the
same about you go ahead and do it. All
right. All the best. All the best.
Gupit says a thought experiment
but wanted to your take. If AI becomes a
Kali like force controlling humanity,
could Khalki be a hybrid intelligence
created to reset it? Are we unknowingly
accelerating the cycle?
Right? So we have the concept of Kali.
We have the concept of Khalki and so on.
So a thought experiment, interesting
thought experiment. If AI becomes a Kali
like force controlling humanity. See
Kali, the goddess Kali is is a goddess
of destruction but is she's not an evil
goddess. She destroys evil. Kali is the
destroyer of evil forces. And in order
to destroy evil, she becomes this
fearsome scary version of the mother
goddess. So she becomes black in color
with with scary eyes, red eyes and red
loling tongue and garland of skulls and
all. But she's not evil. She destroys
evil and she becomes so fearsome that
even evil is scared of her. But she is
still the mother goddess and she still
loves us. Right? So that is Kali. Now
when you're saying that AI becomes a Kal
like force controlling humanity, Kali
doesn't seek to control humanity. Kali
seeks to liberate humanity from evil. So
AI doesn't become a Kal like force
controlling humanity. AI becomes a
raaslas like force which seeks to
enslave and control humanity.
Right? So that's how how I would see it.
I would not portray Kali as evil. I
would portray AI as a raous like force
if it becomes something that controls
and subjugates humanity. So could kalaki
be a hybrid intelligence created to
reset it? Possibly. Possibly if somebody
creates a hybrid intelligence that
resets this uh disaster that
hypothetically exists then you could say
that is a khalky like figure. Sure.
And are we unwittingly accelerating the
cycle? I think we are tumbling forward
into the unknown future where AI becomes
more and more relevant. Uh we
unknowingly may be accelerating a cycle
of this sort. Indeed. Yeah.
Kakashi says Modi named Hamas in Israel.
Why government of India not label them
as terrorists? I have no idea.
I don't know.
It's not our problem.
Hamas obviously are terrorists but it's
not our business to go and decide who is
terrorist and who should be put on a
list of terrorists and all. No, the US
does it. We don't need to do that. Okay.
It is not the business of the government
of India to create a global list of who
is terrorists, who should be on the list
and who's not. Why should we do that?
What do we gain from that?
No need to do that. So that's why
probably government of India is not not
why why hasn't the government of India
designated Boo Haram as terrorists?
Why not somebody else here and there
wherever? It's not it's none of our
concern. Doesn't matter to us. That's
why
Gear TV says in my opinion now all
important nations just fall under the
bracket of 30 to 50 hard power scores.
No one is significantly more powerful
than the others. Um I will calculate
this
properly and I I'll see about that. I
think the US will still exceed 50. I
think if if it was 94 earlier it may be
maybe 75 80 now. I'll have to see about
that but I don't think it's fallen that
badly.
I don't think India's hard power score
is anywhere near 30. It was 4.94
earlier. I wonder what it is right now.
So I will have to do a calculation. I
will do it in a month's time or so.
Yeah, let this war hopefully settle
down. Yeah, hopefully end. If not, I'll
do it in a month's time.
RV math says want to raise standards
peri
no matter what.
Oh well um
you're not able to study. Well I'm not
sure why you're not able to study but uh
see everybody has problems in life. All
of us we face some problem or the other
and we have to find a way of solving
those problems. So if you are not able
to solve your problem, maybe you can
take help from your parents, from your
well-wishers, from family,
from friends, from elders, from
teachers. If you're a young person, it's
obviously you want have all the wisdom
to solve your own problems. So that's
why we have elders in life. So find a
way, find a way. If I knew you
personally and I knew the circumstances
that you have, then maybe I may be able
to give you come some sort of
constructive advice. But since I don't
know you at all personally, so I will
recommend please talk to your elders,
parents, uncles, aunts, whoever and
discuss it with them openly and find a
solution. You'll be able to find a
solution. There is a solution to every
problem in the world. Okay. All the
best. Do well.
Mahabak VFX says, "If we keep going up,
if we keep going up, who's there
dictating all of the world?" I have no
idea. I'm not sure what you're asking.
But if we keep going up, I'm I'm right
here. I'm not going up. I'm right here.
So I'm not going up. So I'm not sure
who's dictating all over the world.
Ar Patel says, "How practical was the
ancient gurugal curriculum? Did it
include teachings on health, fitness,
ay, finance, and handling emergencies
such as war?" These are specialized
things you're talking about. The gurugal
system was about basic education for
most people. For certain people gurugul
system was from all the way from the
childhood all the way to adulthood. That
was for uh maybe aristocrats for princes
and so on. But for most people gurugul
system the gurugul curriculum. Gurugul
was your local temple. You spent a few
years learning things there. We don't
know exactly what curriculum was there
but it was basic education. Basic as in
arithmetic
grammar a bit of history and stuff like
that. Understand your culture that sort
of thing. And then if you wanted and
once you were done with that you would
get specialized education in your family
itself because each family would be
would have its own business and that you
and you would be part of a jati where
you would have specialized knowledge
that would be imparted to you and you
become an apprentice and eventually you
take over the business that's how it was
done when it comes to health fitness
with finance you had to it was only for
those people who went to higher
education in the wish for vidylayas
okay
D says the greater Israel map on army
shoulder patch matches the prophet
Abraham's promised land from Nile river
to river if it is any thoughts so I am
not familiar with prophecies and
Abrahamic stuff and all I don't know
what prophet Abraham has promised to his
people um from Nile River to Euphrates
that's fascinating really
okay I I'm not aware of this I have not
studied you know yeah the Judaism and
the history of the prophets and stuff
like that so I don't No, but if it does
match this promised land of prophet Abra
Abraham, that's fascinating.
This greater Israel map on the
on the army shoulder patch. That's
fascinating. Now, this is this no longer
sounds like a conspiracy theory to me.
It's it no longer sounds like
speculation to me. This sounds like it's
kind of real. They look this they seem
to really want to expand their
territory.
Okay, I will have to now offline do some
research into this. Very interesting.
Very interesting.
Pratit Kumar Roy says, "Google Sentinel
robots possible real life." Let's see.
Sentinel robots.
Sentinel. Sentinel.
Sentinel robots. Uh, iconic, highly
advanced mutant hunting robots from
Marvel comics. Marvel comics. Okay. to
protect humanity. Uh, mutant DNA chose a
person X-Men, all that stuff. Okay. Uh,
so how do they work? They have massive
size, adaptability, energy blasts.
Uh, they target mutant DNA
and so on. Pose a persistent threat.
Possible in real life. Look, there's
nothing in the laws of physics that says
this is not possible. So maybe it's
possible. But so maybe it's it's
possible you know if you are an engineer
and you want to incorporate
bioengineering and and genetic
engineering into your repertoire and you
want to create a being like this. I
suppose it theoretically is possible.
YT user says do you think Americans
British sent Jews to their current land
to keep check on the Middle East and
control their resources or it's the
other way around? Do you think the
British supported them in the Yam Kipur
war?
I I am still not sure about which way is
it. Is it this way around or that way
around?
See, Israel was created by the West,
right? Uh the British the the mandate,
British mandate of Palestine and you had
that and in the 1920s 30s etc. the Jews
were settled in batches in this region.
Right? Obviously it was their ancestral
land. No question about that. Right. Um
and eventually that's how uh Israel was
created.
So clearly the British sent Jews to
their current land. Now is it because
they wanted to keep a check on the
Middle East or whatever? I'm not sure if
that is why they sent them. I don't
remember exactly what the story is
because it's been a while since I've
studied this. But we know that u it was
the British mandate of Palestine where
the Jews were settled over a couple of
decades. And this progressively led to
strife between the Jews and the people
who were already occupying the land who
are now called the Palestinians and so
on. U but obviously Israel as we know
it's a very important nation for the
west because it it it creates certain
balance of power in the region and it's
great to to keep the Arabic nations in
check. Right? So the west needs this
balance of power in the region. If
Israel doesn't exist then the Arabic
nations become way more powerful
relatively speaking. Do I think the
British supported the Israelis in the
Yamipur war?
They definitely had US support. I don't
remember about British support. I have
to refresh my memory of those of those
events. Right now I can't remember. I
don't definitely the US supported them.
I'm not sure about British. FYCS says
why is being a good civilized person so
tough in India?
Being a good civilized person is tough
in any society where you have poverty
and low standards.
A society where you have alleged
corruption
and low standards and poverty
and you have a system of rent seeking
in that society. No matter where it is
in the world, it's very tough to be a
good civilized person. It's tough. It's
tough
but it's still there. You still have
good civilized people despite all these
issues.
Raman Gil says government making nuclear
reactors in close to border especially
hana example Hana isn't it better to be
more inland with real water bodies
beside it or it just doesn't matter. I
think it makes see India has such a
massive territory and land mass and we
also have border regions that are close
to terrorist nations like Pakistan, Hana
for example. So I think it's actually
better since we have such enormous land
mass it really makes sense to have
nuclear reactors in the interior parts
of India as opposed to near the borders
with the temporary artificial nation of
Pakistan.
I think it makes sense to have these
critical installations far from Pakistan
and far from the borders whether it is
petroleum refineries whether it is
nuclear reactors or anything that's
sensitive and critical.
So I think if do we have any reactors
we're putting out in Hana
Hana nuclear reactor
do we have any Gorakpur Hana Anu Vidyat
Pioja
it's a 2800 megawatt nuclear power plant
in under construction in the Fahabad
district of Rihanna and
okay so okay we are we are constructing
one nuclear reactor in Hana and it's uh
going to start producing power in 203031
in the first phase.
Um okay so we have one there uh it's not
a great idea to have a whole bunch of
nuclear reactors there but I suppose
even the people of Hana have the
aspirations
nuclear reactor so I think it's okay to
have one there as long as it's not too
close to the border is it it's in what
fathabad right let me let me go back
there where is fathabad district
you know hana where is that
uh how far is it from the border let us
see the map fatyhabad district.
How far is it from the border?
Um,
it's about 150 140ish kilometers from
the border. So, it's not too close to
the border and not very far away either.
I suppose look, you can't deny the
people of Hana their own nuclear reactor
if they have the aspiration. So, I think
it's fine.
I think it's okay. It's not very close
to the border. But overall I agree with
your your concern ma'am that uh nuclear
reactors need to be most most of these
critical
uh projects need to be in the interiors
of India far from borders. Okay.
Ja Gada says deep state is aliens. Iran
war breaks world order. Small
decentralized power emerge and aliens
will divide and rule and take over
earth. Hey well I I hope that doesn't
happen but we shall see. We shall see.
Pratep Kumar Roy says, "Your views about
Achara Prashant and Khanser Fishy. I
have no idea. No comments. Sorry."
Okay.
Uh Obnak says, "You just acknowledged my
previous question, not answer. What was
your previous question?"
I don't remember. I must have taken a
100 questions by now. It's been 4 hours,
15 minutes, 16 minutes. Uh if I have uh
not answered your previous question, I
apologize. I acknowledge it. Uh I am
sorry I don't remember now and I don't
have the list anymore. I am taking the
list list away. So in that case I am
sorry. I apologize. I don't remember
what the question was. As far as I
remember I've tried to answer all the
questions but yeah in that in case you
feel that way I'm sorry.
Just DB says is religion really useful
for wars?
Is religion really the reason for wars
or just an excuse?
Are all wars caused because of religious
religion?
Uh did the Faullands war happen because
of religious issues? No. No. No. No. No.
No. No. Did China go to war against
India in 1962 because of religious
reasons? No. No. No. No. I can give you
a thousand examples. So, it's not like
that.
Uh Java bro says, "Thank you, sir. Real
Vladimir Putin in my bro V intro." All
right.
Shah the Punjani says, "If America is
busy with Iran for a long time, will
that be the time when China thinks
Taiwan?
The longer this war lasts, the higher in
my opinion the probability will be that
China makes a move on Taiwan. Okay,
America gets bogged down in this war
like it is right now and its supplies of
arms, ammunition, missiles, munitions,
etc. start running critically low which
they already are and Europe supplies are
already depleted because of the Ukraine
war that's a great time for China to
make a war they make a move on Taiwan
so yeah yeah
says Israel grabs some territory each
time it goes to war fighting its
existential threat isn't this the sign
of an expansionist nation looks like it
aspires to make greater Israel your your
opinion well from shoulder patch. We saw
the shoulder patch on the shoulders of
Israeli soldiers which seems to show a
greater Israel from the Nile to the
Euphrates. It looks like Israel seeks to
expand its territory. If if idea of
soldiers are wearing that, it means it's
an official thing.
And um each time Israel goes to war, it
grabs some territory. Well,
historically, it's been that way. Has
it? Most likely it's been that way. Some
territory. It took Sai then it gave gave
back the Sinai Peninsula to to Iran and
in whichever war it was 67 or whenever
it was it took Jerusalem.
So it does grab some territory.
Uh is this the sign of an expansionist
nation? No. When you have a war,
territory does change hands and if you
are a better if you're better at
fighting than other nations, you're
going to grab territory. You're going
you're going to gain territory each
time.
So that is not necessarily the hallmark
of an expansionist nation. It's the
hallmark of a nation that is good at
fighting. And whenever it has had to
fight a war, it's prevailed and gained
territory. Of course, there's been at
least one war that Israel did not do
very well in the Yamapour war,
obviously. Um,
so I think Israel gaining territory each
time it goes to war, is not necessarily
the sign of an expansionist nation. is
the sign of a nation that's great at
fighting. But that shoulder patch does
seem to give uh indications of major
territorial aspirations,
greater Israel. That shoulder patch
seems to indicate that it aspires to
create a much much larger greater
Israel. Yeah, that is what seems to be
the clincher for me. Not the fact that
Israel has gained territory every time
it fought. Not that. this shoulder
patch. That is very interesting.
Okay. Guprit says kali means meant
kalyug sir not di kali mis. Okay. Okay.
No issues. No issues. But anyway. Yeah.
Kaliuga.
Okay. No issues. I got it. I got it.
Thank you. Kiran says, "Is Russia
sending its S400 and SU35 to Iran?" I
think Russia seems to have dispatched at
least at least one if not more S400
systems to Iran in 2025 last year. So
that seems to be old news. Uh Sukoy 35
I'm not sure about that. I've not seen
any news about the Sukoy 35 being
dispatched to Iran. Or have I? I think
it has happened. Yeah. No, not I was
imagining the Sukoy 57, not the Suka 57.
Suka 35 most likely they may have sold a
few of those to Iran.
Most likely they did. Yeah. But I've not
seen any
I've not seen this aircraft making any
appearances thus far in the war. So I'm
not sure what the status is. Let's see.
Iran Su35.
It's in the process of acquiring the
Sukoy 35.
When does it happen? 2027 or 28? So it's
not acquired it yet. So okay. Okay. So
that's a deal.
Brown leprechaun says Russia energy, USA
economy, China manufacturing. What can
India's silver bullet be? I wonder the
government of India needs to find an
answer to this. It should have been
manufacturing. It should have been
manufacturing. We have been uh harping
on about the slogan of make India since
what for the past decade.
A slogan doesn't change the world,
right? You have to make it happen. So we
have done a poor job thus far of of
doing make in India. Yeah. We have not
become a major manufacturing power.
India's silver bullet should be
manufacturing.
Russia energy. Yes. USA economy. Yeah.
China manufacturing. India should have
been the replacement to China or the
answer to China. And we haven't done a
great job of that. India silver the
answer is India's silver bullet has to
be manufacturing.
Dave says, "Look at Nile to Euphrates
and greater map together, please." I saw
it. I saw it. I I I saw it. I know.
I know. I wasn't aware of this. I wasn't
aware of this. So, that has been an eye
openener for me just a few minutes ago.
Greater Israel looks like it's a real
thing. Looks like it looks like it's not
speculation or conspiracy theory. Looks
like it's a real thing. Very
interesting. Kakashi says India may be
sovereign but it is not anti-imperialist
like Iran, Russia, China. For that you
must resist in US demands not comply
with their sanctions and bullying.
Should I disagree with you? I can't
because you are correct. You are
correct. India is not an
anti-imperialist nation. India is a
nation that still
thinks about its colonial past with with
great fondness and longing.
India is a India's people and a lot of
India's leaders are a bunch of mentally
colonized people.
Lots of Indians are still angopiles who
thought who think that the British did
us great favors by colonizing and
occupying us. So yeah, India it's in
it's in the blood of so many Indians.
to not be anti-imperialist
and a lot of that has to do with India's
education system that that mentally
colonizes Indians. So I agree with you
100%. India is not that hard rigid anti-
anti-imperialist
nation with a with a straight spine like
the Iranians, like the Russians, like
the Chinese. India is a more pliable
nation right now sadly.
Vive Kopadia says your views about PMK's
fund and cast reservations. I don't know
what the PM carees fund does. So I can't
say about this cast reservation. I have
always opposed that.
I am okay with reservation as long as it
is done on the basis of economic status.
Not on the basis of cast. I don't
believe in cast. Cast should be
annihilated.
Remove all references of cast and all
relevance of cast.
If you want to continue reservations, do
that for 20 years maximum and do that on
the basis of economic on the economic
condition of family not on the basis of
cast of any such nonsense.
Okay. Pushina says today Abijit Sar will
beat Amani in wealth through super chat.
I wish. Thank you sir. Please tell us
about your life and education. It's not
relevant. It's not important. I am not
an important person. We are discussing
important matters in the world. I am not
important. I am not Amani. I'm not Elon
Musk. I'm not Putin. I'm not Trump.
Who am I? I'm just somebody who
interprets the world the best he can for
you. My background is not important. How
is it important? One day maybe I can do
a podcast in which I explain I speak
about myself but today is not the day
but I appreciate you asking this
question. Okay, I'm not trying to rebuff
you. Maybe one of these days I should
speak about that in detail but that will
be a separate session. Okay, not today.
And yeah, I'm hoping to end this session
soon because it's been like four and a
half hours now, which is super super
long. Okay, let's see. Uh, Chira Raj
says, "Narcissism with acton can slow
confidence and procrastination."
Narcissism
with action can
slow low confidence. And why does
everybody try type in this compressed
way? Why? I don't know. So narcissism
with action can slow low confidence and
procrastination. Okay, if you say so sir
I am not aware of this.
Pratep Kumar Roy says Sentinel robots in
X-Men were massive could survive massive
explosions. Could fly had invisible
missile shield powered by nuclear
reactor as it at its core similar to
Iron Man suit but massive. See nuclear
reactor at its core. You can't have that
small of a nuclear reactor. Okay. If
they are massive, you see the iron man
man technology of a nuclear fusion
reactor or arct reactor or whatever
reactor powering the suit that may be
speculative science fiction. I can't
think of actually making it happen in in
reality. Uh Sentinel robots and X-Men
were massive, could survive massive
explosion, could fly a nuclear reactor
its core. I think some of it is fantasy,
some of it is f science fiction. I can't
think of any way of miniaturaturizing a
nuclear reactor and making it this big
or whatever. Yeah.
Because if you want
you need a certain amount of fuel to
in order to produce the heat that drives
the nuclear reaction that generates the
heat that that drives the steam turbine
that produces electricity. That's
essentially what it is, right? A nuclear
reactor to make it to oversimplify what
a nuclear reactor does. It's a heat
source.
It's a heat source that drives a steam
engine that generates electricity.
That's what a nuclear reactor is. Now,
how do you put a steam engine inside a
robot is a big question, right? So, I'm
not sure how how feasible that is
actually.
Dier says if war goes for long could
benefit India back P. Let's forget about
P right now. Let us forget about this
obsession with P
H
we have bigger things to do than P.
So if this war goes for long it's not
going to b I don't see it benefiting
India. It's going to hurt India more.
It's it'll benefit Pakistan. Sorry it'll
benefit China.
Jitha Gara says, "Should Indian IT
employees start exploring options beyond
it? At my mid-senior level, my team has
harved in 14 months yet AI boosted
productivity but CXO across Indian IT
companies deny your opinion." Okay.
So you are at the mid senior level.
Your team has in 14 months. AI has
boosted productivity. Obviously it will
boost productivity. So you can retain
your most productive employees and make
them even more productive by giving them
AI tools, whatever AI tools you're
using.
Um,
and the problem is that you will no
longer want freshers. You have
reasonably mid to senior level talent
and you will give them the AI powers,
right? Um because AI can do the job of
entry- level programmers for sure. So
the question is should Indian IT
employees start exploring options beyond
IT? I think it makes sense to do that.
Indian IT employees should start
exploring options options beyond it. The
question is what are those options? I'm
not really sure but yeah it makes sense
to do that do that because like you're
saying your team is haved and I suppose
a lot of u you know teams are seeing
this sort of phenomenon. So I think it's
a bad time to be a fresher or a junior
programmer in India or anywhere in the
world. AI will boost productivity but it
will cut down team sizes.
Uh I don't know if if various people
across Indian IT companies deny it. I
think it it AI is going to have a big
impact in the coming months and years on
IT on India's IT industry. It's going to
have a big impact and not a very good
impact. It's going to be pretty bad
actually. So I think it is high time for
those of you who are in IT, if you're IT
employees to start upskilling, acquiring
other skills and start exploring options
beyond it. I think it is high time you
start doing taking this very seriously.
Right?
Moit Raj Singh says how does why do you
write like this? Why can't you put
spaces so that I can read?
Okay, let me try and understand what
this is. How does in early 1950s US
become so powerful politically that it
was able to put pressure on Canada to
cancel its AO arrow program and acquired
also for its Apollo program? Why do you
have to write like this? Why does it
give you pleasure?
How does in
early 1950s US become so powerful? How
did the US become powerful in 1950s? It
won the second world war. It was the big
winner of second world war and it
established the US dollar as the world's
reserve currency.
It had the biggest biggest armed forces.
It was the biggest beneficiary of the
second world war. Okay. And it had
started the process of taking over the
imperial infrastructure, trade routes,
everything of the British Empire by the
1950s. By 1956, by 58 it was over. The
British Empire was over. It was done. So
the Americans had started this. They had
already started on boarding the best
German rocket and rocket engineers and
other scientists
and they were militarily incredibly
powerful. They made thousand tens of
thousands of of fighter planes in the
Second World War. They made more than I
don't know 200 or 300 aircraft carriers.
They were incredibly powerful.
And that's why they were able to get
everything done. Okay.
Pratim Kumar Royce says Panipo please.
Good night sir. Good night to you sir.
Thank you very much for the reminder.
Thank you very much. I need to end this
very soon. It's been too long.
Um Yashvy says how are movies like
Durand important in promoting India's
soft power like US and Israel did
through their movies. Have you seen both
those yet? I have seen Durand one. I
haven't seen Durand 2 yet. I don't
believe in soft power. I believe in hard
power. Without hard power, there is no
soft power. And because India has little
hard power, India soft power is next to
zero. Okay? So let's India I know that
Indians are obsessed with soft power.
But soft power is worthless without hard
power. So please if you remember
anything from what I say remember this
soft power is meaningless unless you
have hard power. If you have hard power
then soft power becomes relevant.
Otherwise it's nothing.
So yeah. Okay.
Uh, Ishika Waninga says, "Gee, what do
you think about the Epstein files in
Israel?" I think Epstein files are 6
million documents of horror. It shows
what the Western elite really are.
Absolute monsters.
I mean,
what kind of person abuses children?
How can you even think of doing that?
Inflicting pain on a helpless innocent
human being? I just don't understand.
And that's what they seem to have been
routinely doing. This god knows what
else cannibalism and all kinds of
horrific things. I it makes me sick to
my stomach. And this tells you what the
true nature of western society is. It's
very different from our culture and our
society sir. Yeah. I don't know what
Israeli angle is there in that.
Obviously Epstein was a Jewish person. I
don't know if he was affiliated with
Israel. Some people say he was. I
haven't explored that angle. Some people
say that that people like Trump are
being uh controlled by Israel because of
the Epstein files. Who knows? It may be
a possibility. Who knows?
Rit Praar says, "Is US military might
overhyped?" Not quite. But the way they
have fought the war has made them look
stupid
because of their overconfidence, because
of the hubris, because of the lack of
planning, because of completely wrong
assumptions and so on.
And of course the problem is that the
the rate of production of munitions,
missiles and so on. It's it's it's
abysmally low. So that would actually
say that their military might maybe a
little bit at least overhyped. Yes,
says I don't know how to read this.
What does this mean? Indeed need to live
for go. Please don't do this. I I I
can't read this sort of thing. Please if
you put a message put it properly. I
can't read this.
India need to in the war. Okay.
India need to in
war in sorry sorry sorry sorry I can't
D says compare greater Israel to Nile to
Euphrates map live please.
Uh,
compare greater Israel to Nile to
Euphrates. It's the same thing. It's the
same thing. It is the same thing. I saw
it. It's exactly Nile to Euphrates.
Let's quickly take a look. Okay, let's
quickly take a look at that. So, Nile to
Israel, right?
So, the Nile is in Egypt. Here it is.
This blue strip. And where's the
Euphrates? It's in Iraq, right?
The river that passes through Baghdad is
the Tigris. If I'm not mistaken, it's a
Tigris. And the other river is the
Euphrates. Here it is. So that's that's
exactly that map of greater Israel.
Looks like that. Yeah. So there we have
it. Looks like they actually are serious
about that. Interesting.
Okay. He's right about Sentinel robots.
The smallest operating nuclear reactor
was a Snap 10A launched in 1965.
Measuring 40 cm long and 23 cm wide
producing 500 W. Let me see the Snap
10A. What is that? And how did they make
it happen? That's interesting. That
actually interests me.
Snap 10A nuclear reactor.
What was that? Uh
uranium 235 fuel, sodium potassium
Nakant.
Um, turbo electric converters to turn
heat into electricity with no moving
parts in the power conversion system.
400 W 500 W. What do you do with that
actually? But interesting interesting.
Uh, Snap 10A. Let me see. Do we have a
schematic of this thing?
Whoa, that is a massive massive thing.
Its launch mass was 440 kilogram.
That is ginormous.
I mean compared to actual nuclear
reactors that we are operation today
it's small but it's huge right it's huge
what were the dimensions of this thing
the reactor measures this much and that
much 37 fuel rods
okay but the reactor itself is that
small but the casing the housing and all
that is massive
and
um you shielding right without shielding
you can't make a reactor work. So
unshielded weighs 290 kg but with
shielding it weighs about what uh 440 kg
and see as you can see this is the
actual power plant. The the reactor
itself may be small but okay interesting
interesting though thank you for
bringing this to my attention.
Interesting. I'll have to look into this
in a little more detail. Anika Chri says
if India was so advanced in science in
Indian ancient era and had known about
permanu and astras why didn't they
create atomic weapons and stop all
invasions um
how do I answer a question of this
nature
we knew things we we had conceived of
things theoretically
Okay, we spoke about see Mahareshi Kad
gave us the the atomic theory
but we had not actually understood the
nature of the atom the quantum nature of
the atom
through experiment. We did not know the
energy levels. We did not know of the
concept of photons. We did not know of
the concept of electrons. We did not
know of the concept of neutrons and
protons.
Right? We do not know about molecules,
about radioactivity.
We had the concept of the anu and the
permanu.
We had the idea of astras. But do you
understand to formally rigorously
understand this and then
use it in a practical way? It's a whole
different story, right?
So that's why
Mohit Raj Singh say says you are getting
frustrated sir it's because of word
limit.
Okay it's because of a word limit. So
okay so I have never used super chat so
I don't know how it works and if I look
frustrated with that I'm sorry but it's
very hard to read you know right. Anyway
thank you for letting me know sir. Thank
you. Aid Singh says Pyat please sleep.
Well I will sleep once these super chats
are over. There are still six more to
go. So thank you for the reminder. Thank
you. Thank you sir. Abidai G. Rajan says
thermal electric effect to create iron
man suit. Thermal electric effect to
look it's nice. Uh
okay thermal what's a thermal electric
effect.
Now how are you generating electricity
is my simple question.
thermal electric effect. It's a nice
terminology, but how are you actually
making it happen? See,
okay. Uh ML with AWS says machine
learning with AWS says, does India have
the structure to be anti-imperialist?
No. The only other country is China
which has to manage a billion population
not a democracy. India does not have the
structure to be imperial
anti-imperialist. India has the
governance structure in the overall
structure of governance to be a
collaborator with imperialists.
Right? India is not structurally
designed to be an uh to be an
anti-imperialist nation and to last as a
sovereign nation for too long. Yeah.
India's structurally penetrated and
compromised.
Sumant Suman Vikran says, "How did
Mossad miss Iran's mosaic system?" I
don't know. The Americans have messed up
Mossad. I don't know what their agenda
is.
And once Iran starts the mosaic warfare,
it operationalizes that. Even what can
Mossad do? And I'm sure Iran is very
very very aware of the potential
penetration of Iran set up by Mossad and
they must have taken adequate measures
to to deal with that. Right.
Kakashi says I don't want India to be
anti-imperialist or we will be Iran
right now but you
will be uniquely remembered for waking
India to truths about west when no one
else did. Yeah look we don't want to
just for the sake of principle start
fighting with everybody and be
anti-imperialist. We need to have our
own agenda. We need to have our own
clear vision for our future and work on
that. So it doesn't necessarily mean
that we have to be anti-imperialist. it.
All I am saying is we should not be
vasalized by anybody. We should not be
made to serve someone's agenda. I'm not
saying we should go to war with
everybody. No, absolutely not. Mind our
own business, do our own thing,
cooperate with everybody, be friendly as
as far as as possible with everybody and
you know serve our people and ensure
there a prosperous future. That's what
India needs to do. But my problem is
that there are so many Indians who are
super obsquest to the west and super
colonized mentally and that's an issue.
Uh anyhow thank you so much for the nice
thing you said over here for me. Thank
you.
Mohitra Singh says think you're tired
now. It's been a long session today.
Well it's been 4 hours and 42 minutes. I
think anybody will be tired after that
long of a session. And so yeah,
Amomar Vir Singh Orthodontist says, "Is
it safe to move to Dubai as a dentist
now? Sir, I think you should take a
pause. Don't decide don't think of
moving to Dubai right now. I hope this
war ends soon. If it does end soon and
there is peace, then it will be fine to
move to Dubai. But right now, I think
you should not make any plans.
If the war doesn't end in in the in the
next few months, I think the entire
Dubai economic model becomes unviable.
So right now don't make a decision. Wait
and watch. If the war ends soon and
there is lasting peace, move to Dubai.
Sure. Otherwise think of alternative
alternatives to Dubai.
Jagalas says cuts aren't just
developers. Designers test. Yeah. Yeah.
Designers quality assurance testers BAS
to many weren't underperforming. AI
tools automated 80% of the work.
Absolutely. Absolutely. Yeah. I mean you
have things like cloud code. um you now
have open claw which is kind of
problematic of course but you have all
these tools agentic uh tools that can
automate yeah 70 80% of many people's
work and then you're going to have to
let people go even those who are not
underperforming but they just become
redundant because AI tools automate so
much I mean then how do you justify
having so many employees on board and
you can't bench half of people or so
whatever so I get it yes I get it it's
it's a terrible time if you are in if
you're in IT absolutely I agree so
designers also AI will do design work
for you excellent designer you all all
you have to do is to feed it the last 10
designs or whatever what's your design
methodology what are your previous
design documents in similar projects and
so on and and what are your new
requirements
AI is going to give you the best designs
AI will do QA testing for you or I
suppose it will at least create testing
plans test documents or whatever. I'm
sure it can you can use in QA testing to
and so on. Yeah, absolutely. Yashyasa
says, "I have a very new YouTube channel
with two videos and 18 subs. I if I
wanted to invite you to a podcast from
there, how do I contact you with the
details and get something set up? It is
not a good idea to contact me if you
have two videos and 18 subs. Uh I'll be
very honest with you. I get a lot of
invitations and I can't accept all the
invitations. I would like see I would
like to help everybody out but I have
limited time. So then I have to make a
decision as to let's say I have a policy
in a month I will say yes to five
invitations hypothetically then I will
decide
based on what which channel which
invitations to accept. The invitations I
will accept will be the ones that will
give me the most impact in terms of
visibility
naturally because I think I have
something important to say and when I
say something I want it to be as visible
as possible.
So that's why if you have two videos and
18 subs it is not a good idea for you to
invite me. You can do it but I will not
be able to say yes.
If you want me to accept your invitation
you have to first prove yourself.
Okay? work hard for a few months, build
up a channel,
you know, show that you're capable of
good work consistently and then invite
me. So, it's not like I will only accept
invitations for somebody who has
millions of followers. I have accepted
invitations from channels who have like
less than a lakh followers. So, it also
depends on the quality of the work
you're doing. But with two videos, I'm
not going to accept you. you put out 20
30 40 videos over a period of time
consistently then I will respect your
work ethic and even if you don't have a
lack followers even if you have 50,000
40,000 30,000 I may definitely consider
your invitation very seriously but first
put in the hard work
okay you will not get get an approval
from me at this point in time at least
make 30 40 I would say make 30 40 videos
at least okay show that you are capable
of hard work that you have of discipline
then then I'll consider it seriously all
right sir all the best all the best
pusha says thanks sir for not getting
angry on my previous
I'm not angry absolutely not sometimes I
sometimes it's hard for me to read this
this stuff but I understand now I
understand that there is a word count
limit and all so I'm not angry with
anybody sometimes I sometimes get
frustrated after four and a half hours
almost five hours now
not angry.
Anoj
art says your thoughts on chemtrails and
recent hail storms. I am not aware of
recent hail storms. Chemtrails.
Look, I have seen chemtrails since I was
a little kid. Most likely they just
vapor contrails from exhaust from
airplanes.
But there's a theory that maybe they're
spraying something in that. So I don't
know about that. Yeah, I don't know.
Hyphen says, "Let us all save some
questions for next week and let us let
us take some rest. It's been 5 hours. I
want this live stream to go on and on
and on. By the way, lol.
I think it's a good idea for all of you
to now give me give me permission to log
off. I think this is the live last super
chat for today. So, thank you so much.
Yeah, it's been 4 hours 48 minutes. I've
done longer live streams, but it it kind
of stretches
stretches your stamina and your mental
and and the amount of concentration you
can do. So I think uh so first of all
hyphen thank you so much. This is the
last last super chat for today. So I'm
going to now finally end this live
stream. Thank you so much everybody. I
really really appreciate you all for
asking so many questions to me. It's a
privilege to be able to ask answer
questions. I'm absolutely not upset that
I have done this live stream almost 5
years. I actually enjoy it. Thank you so
much. Keep asking questions. Keep
learning. Keep raising your standards
and I will see you very soon in the next
live stream which will be most likely in
in the next couple of days or so. Take
care everybody. Thank you so much. I'll
see you soon. Bye-bye.